<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The continuation of the laws of Jamaica passed by the Assembly, and confirmed by His Majesty in Council, December 26th, 1695 :being the second volume of the said laws.</title>
            <title>Laws, etc.</title>
            <author>Jamaica.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1698</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 212 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 55 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A46389</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing J123A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R42084</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">23748238</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 23748238</idno>
            <idno type="VID">109567</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A46389)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 109567)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1703:4)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The continuation of the laws of Jamaica passed by the Assembly, and confirmed by His Majesty in Council, December 26th, 1695 :being the second volume of the said laws.</title>
                  <title>Laws, etc.</title>
                  <author>Jamaica.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[4], 101, [3] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Charles Harper ... and Samuel Crouch ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>MDCXCVIII.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Advertisement: 3 p. at end.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Harvard University Law School Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Jamaica --  History --  To 1962.</term>
               <term>Jamaica --  Politics and government.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>Zev Berger</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>Zev Berger</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:109567:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:109567:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>The Continuation of the LAWS OF JAMAICA, Paſſed by the Aſſembly, And Confirmed by His MAIESTY IN COUNCIL, <hi>December</hi> 26<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1695. Being the Second Volume of the ſaid LAWS.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Charles Harper,</hi> at the <hi>Flower-de-Luce</hi> over-againſt St. <hi>Dunſtan</hi>'s-Church in <hi>Fleet-ſtreet,</hi> and <hi>Samuel Crouch</hi> at the Corner of <hi>Pope's-Head-Alley</hi> over-againſt the <hi>Royal-Exchange</hi> in <hi>Cornhil.</hi> MDCXCVIII.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="index">
            <pb facs="tcp:109567:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:109567:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>INDEX.</head>
            <list>
               <item>AN Act for Eſtabliſhing a perpetual Anniverſary Faſt on the Seventh of <hi>June, Pag. 3</hi>
               </item>
               <item>An Act for Raiſing Money, for, and towards the Defence of this Iſland, <hi>Pag. 5</hi>
               </item>
               <item>An Act to Encourage Sea-faring Men, and other Their Majeſties Subjects, <hi>Pag. 20</hi>
               </item>
               <item>An Act for making <hi>Kingſton</hi> a Pariſh, <hi>Pag. 26</hi>
               </item>
               <item>An Act for the better Securing of <hi>Port-Royal, Pag. 29</hi>
               </item>
               <item>An Act for Making and Clearing a Publick Road from St. <hi>Mary</hi>'s and St. <hi>George</hi>'s into the Pariſh of St. <hi>Andrew</hi>'s, <hi>Pag. 35</hi>
               </item>
               <item>An Act appointing the Prices of Meats, and Regulating Markets, <hi>Pag. 36</hi>
               </item>
               <item>An Act for Reimburſing Their Majeſties Treaſury, <hi>Pag. 40</hi>
               </item>
               <item>An Act to Reimburſe Their Majeſties Treaſury, and Incourage Their Subjects to come and Settle in this Iſland, <hi>Pag. 42</hi>
               </item>
               <item>An Act for Raiſing Money to Solicit in <hi>England,</hi> the Affairs of this Their Majeſties Iſland, <hi>Pag. 52</hi>
               </item>
               <item>An Act for Guarding the Sea Coaſts, <hi>Pag. 59</hi>
               </item>
               <item>An Act for Raiſing Money as a farther Aid to Their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties, for, and towards the Defence of this Their Iſland of <hi>Jamaica, Pag. 63</hi>
               </item>
               <item>An Act appropriating ſeveral Sums of Money heretofore Raiſed, to the immediate Service of this Iſland, <hi>Pag. 79</hi>
               </item>
               <item>An Act for Appropriating ſeveral Sums of Money for the ſpeedy Relief of the Wounded, and Diſtreſſed Inhabitants of this Iſland, who have ſuffered by the late Invaſion of the <hi>French, Pag. 84</hi>
               </item>
               <item>An Act for the Encouragement, and Freedom of Servants, and Slaves which have done, or ſhall do any remarkable Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice againſt the <hi>French</hi> during this preſent War, <hi>Pag. 88</hi>
               </item>
               <item>An Act for Prevention of Indebted Perſons from Departing this Iſland in the Time of Martial-Law, <hi>Pag. 93</hi>
               </item>
               <item>An Act to Enable <hi>George Ivey</hi> Eſquire, to Sell his Eſtate for the Payment of the Debts of his Father <hi>William Ivey</hi> Eſquire, Deceaſed, <hi>Pag. 98</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="notice">
            <pb facs="tcp:109567:3"/>
            <head>ADVERTISEMENT.</head>
            <p>THE Laws of <hi>JAMAICA,</hi> paſſed by the Aſſembly, and confirmed by His Majeſty in Council, <hi>April 17. 1684.</hi> To which is added, the State of <hi>JAMAICA,</hi> as it was under the Government of Sir <hi>Thomas Lynch.</hi> With a Large Map of the Iſland.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Printed for <hi>Charles Harper,</hi> at the <hi>Flower-de-luce</hi> over-againſt St. <hi>Dunſtan</hi>'s Church in <hi>Fleet-ſtreet;</hi> and are to be had of Capt. <hi>Thomas Hudſon</hi> and Mr. <hi>Robert Cotes,</hi> Merchants, at <hi>Port-Royal.</hi>
               </hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="part">
            <div type="preamble">
               <pb n="1" facs="tcp:109567:3"/>
               <head>AT THE COURT AT KENSINGTON, The 26<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Day of <hi>December,</hi> 1695.</head>
               <head type="sub">PRESENT <hi>The King's Moſt Excellent</hi> MAJESTY, In COUNCIL.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>Lord Keeper.</item>
                  <item>Lord Privy-Seal.</item>
                  <item>Duke of <hi>Norfolk.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Duke of <hi>Schonberge.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Duke of <hi>Shrewsbury.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Marq. of <hi>Wincheſter.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Lord Great Chamberlain.</item>
                  <item>Earl of <hi>Bridgwater.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Earl of <hi>Stamford.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Earl of <hi>Scarborough.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Earl of <hi>Romney.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Lord <hi>Godolphin.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Mr. Vice-Chamberlain.</item>
                  <item>Mr. Secret. <hi>Trumbull.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Mr. Chancellor of the <hi>Exchequer.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>L. Chief Juſtice <hi>Holt.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Mr. <hi>Ruſſell.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Mr. <hi>Boſcawen.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Mr. <hi>Smith.</hi>
                  </item>
               </list>
               <p>WHEREAS by Commiſſion under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> to Sir <hi>William Beeſton,</hi> Knight, His MAJESTY<hi>'s</hi> Lieutenant Governour,
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:109567:4"/>and Commander in Chief of the Iſland of <hi>JA<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>MAICA,</hi> bearing Dated the Twentieth Day of <hi>September,</hi> One Thouſand Six Hundrerd Ninety Two, in the Fourth Year of His MAJESTY<hi>'s</hi> Reign; His MAJESTY has been Graciouſly pleaſed to Authorize and Impower the Governour, Council and Aſſembly of the ſaid Iſland, to Conſtitute and Ordain Laws, Statutes and Ordinances, which are to Continue and be in Force till His MAJESTY<hi>'s</hi> Pleaſure he ſignified to the contrary. And for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>aſmuch as certain Laws have in purſuance of the ſaid Commiſſion been tranſmitted to His MAJESTY, with the Humble Deſire of the Governour, Council and Aſſembly, that His MAJESTY would be Pleaſed to paſs the ſame in the Words following.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <pb n="3" facs="tcp:109567:4"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>An ACT</hi> For Eſtabliſhing a perpetual Anni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſary Faſt on the Seventh of <hi>June.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>FORASMUCH as it hath pleaſed Almighty GOD,<note place="margin">Preamble.</note> the Great Creator and Judge of Heaven and Earth, on the Seventh Day of <hi>June,</hi> One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Two, juſtly to puniſh the Inhabitants of this Iſland, for their manifold Sins and Wickedneſſes committed againſt his Divine Majeſty, by a moſt terrible and dreadful Earthquake,<note place="margin">The Occaſion of the Act; the Earth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quake.</note> which not only laid waſte our Eſtates and Places of Habitations in general, but alſo deſtroyed many Hundreds of People; which tremendous Judgment was ſucceeded by a raging Sick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs and Mortality, that few or no Families Eſcaped. Now, that ſo ſignal a Viſitation may be had in perpetual Remembrance, and we and our Poſterity may by hum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bling ourſelves, endeavour to appeaſe God's imminent Wrath, and prevent heavier Judgments: We Your Majeſties moſt Dutiful and Loyal Subjects, Your Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties Lieutenant-Governour, Council, and Aſſembly of this Your Iſland of <hi>Jamaica,</hi> do moſt humbly beſeech Your Moſt Sacred Majeſties, That it may be Enacted by Their Majeſties Lieutenant-Governour, Council and Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſembly; and it is hereby Enacted and Ordained by the Authority of the ſame, that every Seventh Day of <hi>June,</hi> (unleſs it falls out to be on the Lord's Day, and then the Day following) ſhall be for ever hereafter ſet apart, to be kept and obſerved by all the Inhabitants of this Iſland, as an Anniverſary Day of Faſting and Humiliation;<note place="margin">A Yearly Faſt.</note> and that all and every the Inhabitants aforeſaid, ſhall upon
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:109567:5"/>the ſaid Day, Annually reſort to ſome uſual Place where Prayers and Preaching are uſed to be Miniſtred, and there orderly and devoutly abide during the Celebration of Divine Service, by Prayers, Preaching, Singing of Pſalms, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And to the end that all Perſons may be put in Mind of their Duty therein, and be the better prepared to diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge the ſame with that Piety and Devotion as becomes them: Be it further Enacted, That every Miniſter ſhall give Notice to his Pariſhioners,<note place="margin">Notice to be given hereof by the Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter.</note> in the Church, or other Publick Place of Divine Worſhip, at Morning Prayer, the <hi>Sunday</hi> next before every ſuch Seventh Day of <hi>June,</hi> for the Obſervation of the ſaid Day, and that he provide a Sermon ſuitable to that Occaſion; and that in ſuch Pariſhes where there is no Miniſter, this Act ſhall be publiſhed Annually in the Seſſions next before the Seventh of <hi>June,</hi> as aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority aforeſaid, That no Perſon or Perſons whatſoever, neither by themſelves, Servants or Slaves, ſhall do, or cauſe to be done, any manner of Work in his or their Trade, Calling or Plantation: And that no Shop, Tavern, Coffee or Punch-Houſe be kept open on the ſaid Day, on Penalty of forfeiting Forty Shillings for every Perſon,<note place="margin">Penalty for Offenders.</note> by himſelf, Servant or Slave ſo Offending, as aforeſaid, to be Recovered before any of Their Majeſties Juſtices of the Peace, who are hereby Required and Empowered to award the ſame; one Half of which Forfeiture ſhall be to the Church-Wardens for the uſe of the Pariſh, and the other Half to the Informer, or him that ſhall Sue for the ſame.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>W. Bridgeman.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <pb n="5" facs="tcp:109567:5"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>An ACT</hi> For Raiſing Money, for, and towards the Defence of this Iſland.</head>
               <p>WHEREAS it has been found by Sad and Lamentable Experience,<note place="margin">Preamble.</note> that Their Majeſties Ships of War hitherto ordered to attend this Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, have not been ſo Serviceable to this Their Majeſties Iſland, in Cruiſing about the Coaſts thereof, as the Exi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gences of Their Subjects have from time to time required: The Enemies ſmall Crafts, Barque-Luengoes and nimble Veſſels, having from time to time Infeſted the remote Parts thereof, and Landed their Men, and made great Incur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions into the Country, and taken off, and carried away a very conſiderable Number of Slaves, and other Goods and Chattels of great Value, at ſeveral times, from many of Their Majeſties good Subjects Inhabiting thereabout; and may, if not timely prevented, deſtroy and unſettle all the Plantations ſettled on, or near the Sea-Coaſts, round this Iſland, to the great Diſhonour of Their Majeſties, and utter Ruin of Their Subjects here:</p>
               <p>WE therefore, Their Majeſties Dutiful and Loyal Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects, the Aſſembly of this Their Majeſties Iſland of <hi>Jamaica,</hi> having taken into our Serious Conſiderations, how Injurious the Ruin and Deſtruction of Their Majeſties Plantations may in time prove to Their Imperial Crown, and being ready and willing to the utmoſt of our Abi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lities, under the preſent Calamities of War, and the great Deſtruction and Ruin of Their Majeſties Fortifications, and of our own Habitations and Works by the late more dreadful Earthquake, to provide for Their Majeſties Iſland aforeſaid, and the Reſiſtance of Their Enemies, Have
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:109567:6"/>unanimouſly given and granted, and do hereby give and grant unto Their Majeſties, for, and towards the Buying or Hiring,<note place="margin">The Deſign.</note> Providing, Victualling, and Manning Two good Sloops of War, each with Fifty Effective Officers, Seamen and Soldiers, incluſively, to be Employed for Six Months, towards the Guarding of the Sea-Coaſts of this Their Majeſties Iſland, and in Cruiſing with Their Majeſties Friggats about the ſame, for the neceſſary De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence of it, and Common Safety of Their Subjects. And when on Emergent Occaſions the Governour or Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mander in Chief, ſhall by his Orders and Inſtructions ſend over the Friggats to the Coaſts of <hi>Hiſpaniola,</hi> or South of <hi>Cuba,</hi> to commit Acts of Hoſtility, that then the ſaid Sloop or Sloops ſhall attend the Friggat or Friggats, ſo ordered, the Term of Twenty Days and no longer, and upon no other Occaſion or Pretence whatſoever, the full and entire Sum of Three Thouſand Nine Hundred Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venty Seven Pounds Seventeen Shillings and Six Pence, currant Mony of this Iſland; and alſo for and towards the Raiſing of Two Parties, each of Ten Soldiers and Two Officers, for the Reducing Rebellious <hi>Negroes,</hi> for the like time of Six Months, the full and entire Sum of Three Hundred Twenty Five Pounds Six Shillings and Three Pence, like currant Mony of this Iſland; in all Four Thouſand Three Hundred Three Pounds Three Shillings and Nine Pence;<note place="margin">The total Sum.</note> which we do moſt Humbly beſeech Their Majeſties to Accept: And that it may be Enacted;</p>
               <p>AND be it Enacted by Their Majeſties Lieutenant-Governour, Council and Aſſembly of this Iſland, and it is hereby Enacted and Ordained by the Authority of the ſame, that the ſaid Sum of Four Thouſand Three Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Three Pounds Three Shillings and Nine Pence, cur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant Mony of this Iſland,<note place="margin">Who to be Aſſeſſors.</note> be Aſſeſſed, Taxed and Laid on by the ſeveral and reſpective Juſtices and Veſtries, within their ſeveral and reſpective Pariſhes and Precincts, or within the Commiſſion of the Peace for the ſame with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in this Iſland, where there is any lawful Veſtries; and
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:109567:6"/>where they have no lawful Veſtries, by the Juſtices of that Pariſh or Precinct, or within the Commiſſion of the Peace for the ſame, or Major part of the Veſtry, in all and every the Pariſhes of this Iſland, on all and every Perſon within their ſeveral and Reſpective Pariſh or Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cinct, by an Equal and Juſt Tax to be paid (within Three Months after the Tenth day of <hi>June,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Time of Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</note> which ſhall be in the Year of our Lord One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Three) by the reſpective Pariſhes of this Their Majeſties Iſland of <hi>JAMAICA,</hi> into the Hands of the Receiver or Receivers hereafter Named, according to the ſeveral Rates and Proportions hereafter mentioned, in ſuch Sort and Manner as by this preſent Act ſhall be Limited and Appointed, and in no other Way or Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner whatſoever: that is to ſay, for every <hi>Negro,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Slaves ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted.</note> 
                  <hi>Indian</hi> or <hi>Muletta</hi> Slave within this Iſland, of what Age, Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition or Quality ſoever, or to whomſoever belonging, ſhall be Paid for by the Maſters, Proprietors, Owners, Poſſeſſors, Guardians or Perſons Intruſted in the ſeveral Plantations, Pens, Crawls or Settlements within this Iſland, the Sum of Eighteen Pence for each <hi>Negro, Indian</hi> or <hi>Muletta</hi> Slave aforeſaid, and alſo for all Horſes, Mares,<note place="margin">and Cattel.</note> Colts, Mules, Aſſes and Neat Cattel, the Sum of Seven Pence Halfpeny for each Beaſt, and for all Sheep, Lambs, Goats and Kids, the Sum of Two Shillings and Six Pence <hi>per</hi> Score.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, that it ſhall and may be Lawful for the Juſtices and Veſtry, in the ſeveral Pariſhes or Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cincts, or within the Commiſſion of the Peace for the ſame, to Aſſeſs, Tax and Levy on all Overſeers and Hired Servants the Sum of Six Pence in the Pound upon the Wages they receive <hi>per Annum.</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Hired Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants Tax<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed.</note> And that all Handi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crafts and Tradeſmen, be Rated and Taxed according to the Direction of the Juſtices and Veſtry in the ſeveral Pariſhes where they reſide, any Law, Cuſtom or Uſage to the Contrary in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
               <pb n="8" facs="tcp:109567:7"/>
               <p>AND for the Pariſh of <hi>Port Royal,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Port-Royal.</note> it is hereby En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, that the Juſtices and Veſtry ſhall Lay, Aſſeſs, Levy and cauſe to be Levy'd Twelve Pence in the Pound, on all Rents, to be Paid by all Tenants and Allowed by their Landlords and Proprietors, and on all Leaſes, to be Paid, by the Leſſee, and be Allowed by the Leſſor. And alſo on the ſeveral In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>habitants for their ſeveral Trades, Occupations and Cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, according as they were Rated, Aſſeſſed and Taxed by the Juſtices and Veſtry in the Pariſh-Roll on <hi>Port Royal</hi> aforeſaid, for this preſent Year, One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Three. And alſo on all Perſons ſo Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiding at the Town of St. <hi>Jago de la Vega,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">S. Jago de la Vega.</note> Twelve Pence in the Pound on all Rents, to be Paid by all Tenants, and allowed by the Landlords and Proprietors. And all Leaſes to be Paid by the Leſſee, and Allowed by the Leſſor, and alſo according to the Rate, Tax and Sum Aſſeſſed by the Juſtices and Veſtry of St. <hi>Katharines,</hi> for this preſent Year One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Three.<note place="margin">Kingſton.</note> And for the Perſons Reſiding on <hi>Kingſton,</hi> Twelve Pence in the Pound on all Rents, to be Paid by all Tenants and Allowed by the Landlords and Proprie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors, and on all Leaſes to be paid by the Leſſee, and al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed by the Leſſor; and for their ſeveral Trades, Occu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pations and Callings, to be Rated and Taxed by the Juſtices of the Pariſh of Sr. <hi>Andrews,</hi> any thing in this Act to the Contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, that the Nation and People of the <hi>Jews</hi> Reſiding within this Iſland,<note place="margin">The Jews.</note> Pay or cauſe to be Paid, towards the Raiſing of the ſaid Sum of Mony before mentioned, and expreſſed to be Raiſed on the Inhabitants of this Iſland, over and above and beſides the Tax as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid Aſſeſſed, the full Sum of Seven Hundred and Fifty Pounds, Currant Mony of this Iſland, to be rated, Aſſeſſed, Taxed, Collected and Paid in by <hi>Solomon A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rarij, Jacob de Leon, Moſes Toiro, Jacob Mendez Guteres, Jacob Henriques, Jacob Rodrigues de Leon, Moſes Jeſurum
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:109567:7"/>Cardoſo, Samuel Gabay, Jacob Lopes Torres, Iſaac Coutin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ho, Iſaac Nunes Gonſales</hi> and <hi>Abraham Nunes,</hi> or any Five of them, into the Hands of the Receiver or Receivers hereafter mentioned, Impowred and Appointed to Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive the ſame, at, or within One Month after the Tenth day of <hi>June,</hi> which will be in the Year of our Lord One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Three, any thing herein to the Contrary notwithſtanding.<note place="margin">Caſe of Fai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lure.</note> And in Caſe of fai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lure in the Compliance of the ſaid Payment,</p>
               <p>BE it furt<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>r Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, that the Sum of Two Hundred and Fifty Pounds more, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides the ſaid Seven Hundred and Fifty Pounds above appointed to be Aſſeſſed on the Nation and People of the <hi>Jews</hi> aboveſaid: That then it ſhall and may be Lawful for the Treaſurer or Treaſurers hereafter to be appointed, by Warrant of Diſtreſs, under his or their Hands and Seals, Directed to the Conſtable or Conſtables for the reſpective Pariſhes where ſuch <hi>Jew</hi> or <hi>Jews</hi> reſide, to Levy or ſingly cauſe to be Levyed at Diſcretion upon the ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral <hi>Jews,</hi> Inhabitants of this Iſland, ſuch proportional Sum or Sums as ſhall make up the Sum of One Thouſand Pound as aforeſaid. And alſo if any of the <hi>Jews</hi> Rated or Aſſeſſed by the Perſons above-named, ſhall refuſe to Pay the ſaid Sum by them ſo Aſſeſſed; That then it ſhall and may be Lawful for the reſpective Juſtices in their re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpective Pariſhes, or within the Commiſſion of the Peace for the ſame, where the ſaid <hi>Jews</hi> reſide, for ſo much as any of the ſaid <hi>Jews</hi> are Aſſeſſed and Rated by the Perſons aboveſaid, who are hereby Impowred to Iſſue out their Warrant or Warrants to the reſpective Conſtables, to Diſtrain any of the Goods and Chattels of any of the ſaid <hi>Jews</hi> that ſhall refuſe or delay to pay the ſame: any Law, Cuſtom or Uſage to the Contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted, that if the ſeveral Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, or any of them of the <hi>Jewiſh</hi> Nation beforementio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned, Impowred and Appointed to aſſeſs, levy, collect and pay in the aforeſaid Sum, aſſeſſed upon the Nation of
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:109567:8"/>the <hi>Jews,</hi> ſhall neglect his or their Duty therein; that then it ſhall and may be Lawful for the Governor or Commander in Chief by Warrant under his Hand and Seal, Directed to the Provoſt-Marſhal or his Lawful Deputy, to Levy or cauſe to be Levied on all and every Perſon or Perſons ſo Offending,<note place="margin">100 <hi>l. forfeit.</hi>
                  </note> One Hundred Pound cur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant Mony of this Iſland, or the value thereof upon his or their Monies, Slaves, Goods or Chattels, and ſell the ſame by Publick Outcry, returning the Overplus, if any be, to the Owner; and in Caſe no Mony, Slaves or Goods are to be found, as aforeſaid, that then he take into Cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy the Body of the Perſon or Perſons ſo offending, and him or them in ſafe Cuſtody keep, until he or they Pay the ſaid Sum of One Hundred Pound for the ſaid Offence; any Law, Cuſtom or Uſage, or any thing in this Act ſeeming to the Contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, that the reſpective Juſtices of the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpective Pariſhes and Precincts, or within the Commiſſion of the Peace for the ſame, or any two of them, deliver into the Hands of their reſpective Conſtables within their re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpective Pariſhes and Precinct, a Roll of ſuch Tax or Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſment as aforeſaid,<note place="margin">Time for Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lection.</note> ſo that the Collection be made within Two Months after the Tenth day of <hi>June,</hi> which ſhall be in the Year of our Lord One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Three, with a Warrant under the ſame, Signed and Sealed by the ſaid Juſtices, or any two of them, Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>powring and Requiring the ſaid Conſtables to Levy the ſaid Tax or Aſſeſſment, and Pay the ſame into the hands of the Church-Wardens for the time being, in the Pariſh where the ſame is Taxed or Aſſeſſed as aforeſaid. And where it ſhall happen there are no Church-Wardens, That then the Conſtables are hereby required to Pay the ſame into the Hands of the Juſtices of the ſaid Pariſh, De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ducting Four Pence in the Pound for Collecting the ſame in all the Pariſhes of this Iſland, (<hi>Port Royal</hi> and <hi>Kingſton</hi> only Excepted) where it ſhall be done <hi>gratis:</hi> who are hereby Required to Receive and Pay the ſame into the
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:109567:8"/>Hands of the Receiver or Receivers hereafter named, within one Month after the Collecting thereof. And leſt any Perſon or Perſons ſo as aforeſaid Taxed or Aſſeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed, ſhall refuſe or delay to pay his or their Tat or Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſment, the ſaid Juſtices or any two of them, are hereby required in the Warrant aforeſaid to Impower and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand the Conſtables aforeſaid, by Vertue thereof, to Diſtrain the Slaves, Horſes, Mares, Colts, Mules, Aſſes,<note place="margin">Diſtreſs to be made.</note> Neat Cattle, Sheep, Lambs, Goats, Kids, or any other Perſonal Eſtate whatſoever of Him, Her or Them ſo refuſing or delaying, and ſell the ſame forthwith at Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Outcry, retaining to themſelves Twelve Pence in the Pound for every ſuch Diſtreſs on Slaves, Horſes, Mares, Colts, Mules, Aſſes, Neat Cattle, Sheep, Lambs, Goats, Kids, or any other Perſonal Eſtate whatſoever Diſtrained on, or Sold as aforeſaid; retur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning the Overplus, if any be, to the Owner.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, that for the better Aſſeſſing, Collect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, Levying and Paying in the Sums of Mony, ſo as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid Limited and Appointed to be Raiſed and Paid as aforeſaid; and for the more Effectual putting this Act in Execution,<note place="margin">Juſtices and Veſtries Duty.</note> the Juſtices and Veſtries within their ſeveral Pariſhes and Precincts, or within the Commiſſion of the Peace for the ſame, are hereby Required and Impowred immediately on the paſſing this Act, with all poſſible Speed to proceed to the Diſcharge of their ſaid Duties, in Manner and Form as is before Directed and Appointed.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, that if the Juſtices, Veſtry-men, Conſtables or Church-Wardens, or any of them, ſhall neglect or wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully fail in his or their Duty in Aſſeſſing,<note place="margin">Penalty of Neglect.</note> Collecting or Paying the ſame as aforeſaid; That then and in ſuch Caſe every Juſtice ſo Neglecting or wilfully failing in his or their Duty in this Act Preſcribed, contrary to the true Intent and Meaning thereof, ſhall Forfeit Fifty Pound; and all and every Veſtry-man, Church-Warden or Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable,
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:109567:9"/>the ſum of Twenty Pound, for every ſuch Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence as aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>AND be it Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, that all Owners of Slaves, Horſes, Mares, Colts, Mules, Aſſes, Neat Cattle, Sheep, Goats, Lambs, Kids, Tradeſmen and Hired-men whatſoever as aforeſaid, ſhall and are hereby by Themſelves, Guardi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans, Overſeers, Truſtees or Pen-keepers within the ſeveral Pariſhes aforeſaid, required and obliged to give a juſt and true Account on Oath to the beſt of their Knowledge,<note place="margin">Account on Oath.</note> at ſuch Time or Times as the Juſtices of each Pariſh or Precinct, or within the Commiſſion of the Peace for the ſame, ſhall Direct, of all Slaves, Horſes, Mares, Colts, Mules, Aſſes, Neat Cattle, Sheep, Lambs, Goats, Kids, Rents, Trades and Callings whatſoever as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid belonging to ſuch Owner, Guardian, Overſeer, Truſtees or Pen-keepers within their reſpective Pariſh or Precinct, or within the Commiſſion of the Peace for the ſame (the Nation of the <hi>Jews</hi> only Excepted) to the Juſtices of the Peace, or any of them in the ſaid Pariſhes or Precincts, or within the Commiſſion of the Peace for the ſame, who are hereby Required and Impowred to Admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter the ſame, and to ask all ſuch further Queſtions as to them or any of them ſhall ſeem Meet and Neceſſary, relating to this preſent Act. The Tenour of which Oath ſhall be as followeth.<note place="margin">Oath.</note> I <hi>A. B.</hi> do Swear, that I have within the Pariſh of <hi>C</hi>— Slaves, Young and Old, and alſo — Horſes, Mares, Colts, Mules, Aſſes, Neat Cattle, Sheep, Lambs, Goats, Kids, and no more: So help me God. And if it be to an Overſeer, I <hi>D. E.</hi> Overſeer of the Plantation of <hi>F. G.</hi> do Swear that the ſaid <hi>F. G.</hi> hath within the Pariſh of <hi>H</hi>— Slaves, Young and Old, and alſo—Horſes, Mares, Colts, Mules, Aſſes, Neat Cattle, Sheep, Lambs, Goats, Kids, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and no more, to the beſt of my knowledg. And ſo to Pen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keepers or any other Perſon for Cattle, Horſes, Mares, Colts, Mules, Aſſes, Neat Cattle, Sheep, Lambs, Goats, Kids, Rents, Trades, Taverns and Callings
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:109567:9"/>whatſoever, <hi>Mutatis Mutandis;</hi> and if any Perſon or Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons ſhall refuſe either by Themſelves,<note place="margin">Caſe of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſal.</note> Overſeers or Pen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keepers, to give an Account upon Oath as aforeſaid, of their Slaves, Horſes, Mares, Colts, Mules, Aſſes, Neat Cattle, Sheep, Lambs, Goats, Kids, Rents, Trades and Callings in manner aforeſaid; That then it ſhall be Lawful for the Juſtices and Veſtry, or the Juſtices where there is no Veſtry, to Tax the Perſon or Perſons ſo refu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing according to their Diſcretion.</p>
               <p>AND foraſmuch as the preſent Neceſſity will require the Advancing of Mony for and towards the Buying or Hiring and Equipping the ſaid Two Sloops and Men to Sea, with all poſſible Expedition:</p>
               <p>BE it enacted by Authority aforeſaid, that it ſhall and may be lawful to and for any Perſon or Perſons to ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vance and lend to Their Majeſties, for and towards the furtherance of this preſent occaſion, ſuch Sum or Sums of Mony as may be needful; and that whoſoever ſhall advance and lend any ſuch Sum or Sums of Mony upon the ſecurity of this Act,<note place="margin">Interect on Mony ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vanc'd.</note> ſhall receive for the Loan of the Sum they ſhall ſo lend after the rate of Twelve Pound Ten Shillings, <hi>per Cent. per Ann.</hi> for the time he or they ſhall be in disburſe of the ſaid Sum, on the Credit of this ſaid Act as aforeſaid, any thing beforementioned to the contrary thereof in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND to the end that all Moneys that ſhall be lent unto Their Majeſties upon the Credit hereof may be well and ſufficiently ſecured:</p>
               <p>BE it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, that all and every Perſon and Perſons who ſhall Advance and Lend any Sum or Sums of Mony to Their Majeſties, on the Credit of this Act, and actually Pay the ſame into the Hands of the Receiver or Receivers hereafter Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med and Appointed, ſhall by the Receiver or Receivers on the firſt Payment of Mony that ſhall be Paid into the
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:109567:10"/>Receivers Hands, by virtue of this Act, be forthwith Paid into the Perſon or Perſons, their Executors or Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſtrators, ſo lending the ſaid Sum Advanced, with the Intereſt of the ſame, for the diſcharge of the Mony ſo Lent and Advanced. And that all and every other Sum or Sums of Mony that ſhall be laid out, or be Paid by the Receiver or Receivers, for and towards the Buying, Equipping, Victualling and fitting to Sea; as alſo for Paying the Officers and Seamen on Board the ſaid Sloops: and alſo for Paying the Officers and Soldiers of the Two Parties beforementioned, for Reducing the Rebellious Negroes, ſhall as they become due, be Paid by the Receiver or Receivers that are hereafter menti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oned and Appointed, without Fee or Charge.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">Receivers Names.</note>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, that the Honourable Colonel <hi>Charles Knights,</hi> one of Their Majeſties Council of this Iſland, and alſo Colonel <hi>Thomas Clarke,</hi> Captain <hi>Lancelot Talbott,</hi> Captain <hi>Robert Wardlow, William Hutchinſon</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> Captain <hi>Joſiah Heathcote</hi> and Captain <hi>Thomas Clarke,</hi> be and are hereby Required and Impowred and Warranted to be Receiver or Receivers, of all and ſingular the ſeveral Sums afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, mentioned and intended to be raiſed on the ſeveral Pariſhes or People aforeſaid, and ſhall and may Law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully by Advice and Conſent of the Lieutenant Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour or Commander in Chief, forthwith Buy or Hire Two good and ſubſtantial Sloops fit for War, and Provide, Equip, Fit ready for the Sea, and Victual the ſame for Fifty Effective Officers, Seamen and Soldiers Incluſively, for each Sloop for the ſaid Six Months, or for ſuch ſhorter time as to to them ſhall appear moſt convenient; and that the ſaid Two Sloops being thus Fitted and Victualled, it is hereby Required that the Right Honourable Sir <hi>William Beeſton</hi> Knight,<note place="margin">Captains ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed by whome.</note> Their Majeſties Lieutenant Governour aforeſaid, by Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion under his Hand and Seal, do Conſtitute and Appoint on Board each of the ſaid Sloops, ſuch Diſcreet and Able Captains for this preſent Service, as his Honour
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:109567:10"/>ſhall in his Prudence think fit, and can Confide in; and that each of the ſaid Captains receive for their Pay after the rate of Six Pounds <hi>per</hi> Month:<note place="margin">And other Officers.</note> And likewiſe ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>point by his Warrant for each Sloop one Maſter at Four Pounds <hi>per</hi> Month; one Boatſwain, one Gunner at Three Pounds <hi>per</hi> Month each; one Chirurgeon, and one Carpenter at Four Pounds <hi>per</hi> Month each, on Board each Sloop. And Command and Require them in Their Majeſties name to Raiſe and Enliſt on Board the ſaid Two Sloops, by Impreſſing or otherwiſe, to make and fill up the full number of Fifty Effective Officers, Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men and Soldiers in each Sloop, who ſhall alſo receive after the rate of Forty Shillings each Man <hi>per</hi> Month. And that their monthly Pay, ariſing from this preſent Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice, ſhall be paid out of the Mony raiſed by this pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Act, Commanding and Requiring the reſpective Captains of each Sloop aforeſaid, by his Commiſſion and Inſtructions therewith to be given, that they take care from time to time, to their utmoſt Abilities, to Guard and Defend the Coaſts of this Iſland by conſtant Cruiſing, and looking out both Windward and Leward, North and South ſides of this Iſland, as his Honour in his great Wiſdom ſhall from time to time Direct and Command.</p>
               <p>BE it alſo Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the ſaid Colonel <hi>Charles Knights,</hi> and <hi>Joſiah Heathcote,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> be and are hereby appointed, impowered, and warranted to be Treaſurers to Receive and Pay all Sum and Sums of Mony as ſhall from time to time come to their Hands,<note place="margin">Treaſurers.</note> for the more eaſie and ready diſpatch of ſuch Perſons as they may have occaſion to Deal with; or pay all ſuch Wages unto the Officers, Seamen and Soldiers, as the Occaſion and Intent of this Act may require. And as ſoon as the Receiver or Receivers, before appointed and impowered, have Bought or Hired, and Equipped the ſaid Sloops, and Victualled them with ſufficient Victu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>als for their reſpective Complements of Men aforeſaid, for the time they ſhall find convenient; That the ſaid
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:109567:11"/>Sloops be forthwith diſpatcht out to Sea by Command and Direction of the Lieutenant Governour, or Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mander in Chief, to Cruiſe about the Coaſts of this Iſland, as aforeſaid. And that the Receiver, or Receivers, keep a diſtinct Accompt of the Mony raiſed by this preſent Act. And for all Payments made for the Uſes and Purpoſes by this Act required, and render a juſt and true Accompt thereof,<note place="margin">Accompt to be given.</note> when demanded, unto Their Majeſties Lieutenant Governour, or Commander in Chief, and Council, of all Sum and Sums of Mony by them, and every of them received by Vertue of this preſent Act, and how laid out, and for what, and to whom, and for what Uſes. And ſhall in like manner give an Accompt to the Aſſembly of this Iſland when Sitting and Aſſembled, when thereunto required, of ſo much of the ſaid Mony as ſhall be by them, and every of them reſpectively re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived, and to whom the ſame are iſſued and paid by them reſpectively, and to what Uſes, and if the ſaid Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiver, or Receivers, or any of them, after the Receipt of any of the ſaid Monies, ſhall divert or miſapply the ſame, or any part thereof by any pretence whatſoever, otherwiſe than before intended and directed, contrary to the true intent and meaning of this Act; he or they ſo Offending ſhall forfeit to Their Majeſties,<note place="margin">Forfeit.</note> for, and to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards the ſupport of the Government of this Iſland, and contingent Charges thereof, double the Sum ſo di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verted or miſapplyed.</p>
               <p>AND for the better Order and Government of the ſaid Sloops of War, wherein the Honor of Their Majeſties, and the Intereſt of this Iſland are ſo much concerned: Be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid,<note place="margin">Articles and Orders.</note> That all and every the Articles and Orders mentioned in certain Acts of Parliament, made in the Thirteenth year of the Reign of His Majeſty <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, of bleſſed Memory, for the Eſtabliſhing Articles and Orders for the Regu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lating and better Governing of his Majeſty's Navies, and Ships of War, and Forces by Sea, ſhall be duly and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpectively put in Execution, Obſerved, and Obeyed on
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:109567:11"/>Board the ſaid Sloops of War: And are hereby de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clared to be the Law of this Iſland againſt all ſuch Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or Perſons aboard the ſaid Sloops, as ſhall Offend therein. And for further Encouragement of the Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers, Seamen, and Soldiers aboard the ſaid Sloops,<note place="margin">Encourage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </note> All Ships, Sloops, or Veſſels by them taken from the Enemy, and not belonging to this Iſland, are hereby likewiſe given them for their ſaid Encouragement. Provided always, that all Slaves, Veſſels, or Goods belonging to Their Majeſties Subjects of this Iſland, which the ſaid Sloops of War ſhall happen to retake before they ſhall have ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rived at the Enemies Port, during the time that they, or either of them are employed in this preſent Service, on the Countries Charge as aforeſaid, ſhall be returned to the reſpective Owners or Proprietors, their Agents or At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torneys, any Law, Cuſtom, or Uſage to the contrary in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That the ſaid Parties hereby raiſed, or to be raiſed for the ſubduing the Rebellious <hi>Negroes</hi> aforeſaid, in caſe of Miſdemeanour or Neglect of their Duty in that be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>half, ſhall be liable to the Pains and Puniſhments pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribed in the Articles of War, as when Martial Law is in force in this Iſland, and that the Captain of each Party receive for his Service in this Act intended and appointed, the Sum of Four Pounds <hi>per</hi> Month,<note place="margin">Pay for the Land-Forces.</note> and that each Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeant alſo receive Fifty Shillings <hi>per</hi> Month, and each Soldier Forty Shillings <hi>per</hi> Month, to be paid by the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiver or Receivers, without any Fee or Charge to either Officer or Soldier.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, That for the better Encouraging of the Perſons Employed on Board the ſaid Sloops for the Service of Their Majeſties, and this Iſland, that they ſhall receive as Salvage for all Veſſels, Slaves,<note place="margin">Prizes re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taken.</note> and other Goods taken of this Iſland, and by-them retaken before they are landed in any of the Enemies Commiſſion-Ports,
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:109567:12"/>One ſixth part of the Veſſels, Slaves or Goods ſo retaken, or the value thereof, the ſaid Veſſels, Slaves or Goods having been firſt Appraiſed by two Perſons indifferently Choſen, one by the Commander or Commanders of the ſaid Sloop or Sloops, and the other by the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpective Owner or Owners; which ſhall be divided a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong the Officers, Seamen and Soldiers of the ſaid Veſſels, proportionably to the Pay each Perſon receives of the Country for that Service.</p>
               <p>AND that all ſuch Perſons as ſhall go out in the Parties to reduce the Negroes in Rebellion, may be in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duced to proceed with the more Reſolution and Vigour; it is hereby Enacted that they ſhall Receive from the Treaſurers,<note place="margin">Negro kill'd, or retaken.</note> for each Negro Killed that was Actually in Rebellion, which ſhall be Evidenced by bringing in his Head to any Juſtice, the Sum of Forty Shillings: And for each Negro in Rebellion taken and brought in alive, not Maimed or Mortally Wounded, the Sum of Ten Pounds, to be paid by the Owner or Proprietor of ſuch Slave or Slaves, who is hereby obliged under the Penalty of Fifty Pounds to Tranſport the Slave or Slaves ſo Reduced from Actual Rebellion: And in caſe that no Owner can be found; That then the Treaſurer or Treaſurers, by this Act appointed, or either of them, ſhall be by this Act Obliged and Impowred to pay the ſaid Ten Pounds our of the Treaſury, and Receive the ſaid Slave or Slaves, and him or them Sell and Tranſport as aforeſaid: And the Produce retain in his or their Hands to be em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed in the ſaid Service, and for defraying the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tingent Charges thereof. And to the end that it may be the better known who is a Negro in Rebellion, It is hereby declared that all Negroes that have been abſent from their Owner or Plantation, the Term of Six Months, be and are accounted as in actual Rebellion, any thing to the Contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND be it Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, that in Caſe any of the Officers, Seamen or Soldiers on Board
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:109567:12"/>the ſaid Sloops, or in the ſaid Parties, ſhall, in actual Service, loſe either Leg or Arm, or be otherwiſe Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>abled: That then and in all ſuch Caſes,<note place="margin">Caſe of Maim.</note> all and every of the ſaid Diſabled Men ſhall receive Ten Pound <hi>per Annum</hi> without Charge, during his or their Natural Lives: And alſo their Cures to be Paid for out of the Publick Revenue of this Iſland, by order of the Lieu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenant-Governour and Council, or of the Government of this Iſland, out of the firſt Payment.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, that all Monies which ſhall Remain over and above,<note place="margin">Surplus not expended.</note> or be not Expended of the ſaid Sum of Four Thouſand Three Hundred Three Pounds Three Shillings and Nine Pence, ariſing by vertue of this Act, and not hereby applyed towards the defraying the Charges of the Sloops and Parties aforeſaid, ſhall be and remain in the hands of the ſaid Treaſurers or either of them, by this Act appointed to be applyed and diſpoſed of, for and towards ſuch other uſe or uſes as the Aſſembly of this Iſland ſhall appoint by a Law: And that the ſaid Receiver or Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceivers, Treaſurer or Treaſurers be allowed all his or their, or either of their reaſonable Charges, in and about the diſcharging the Truſt hereby repoſed in them, Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion or pretences to Commiſſion hereby excepted.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, that the Fines and Forfeitures mentioned in this Act and not declared where they ſhall be Recovered,<note place="margin">Fines, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> how diſpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed.</note> or how Diſpoſed of, be one half to Their Majeſties, for and to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards the Support of the Government of this Iſland, and the contingent Charges thereof; the other half to the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>former, who ſhall Sue for the ſame in any Court of Record within this Iſland, and where no <hi>Eſſoyne, Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tection, Injunction, Wager of Law or nonvult ulterius pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſequi</hi> ſhall be allowed.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <pb n="20" facs="tcp:109567:13"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>An ACT</hi> To Encourage Sea-faring Men, and other Their MAJESTIES Subjects.</head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">Preamble.</note>WHEREAS great Numbers of Perſons, as well Sea-faring Men as others, by the ill Uſage and Diſcouragement they have formerly met with, have been driven from this Iſland, and for Common Subſiſtence, many of them have fallen under the Neceſſity of taking unlawful Courſes, and been forced ever ſince the preſent War with <hi>France,</hi> to ſeek for Shelter in the Ports and Settlements belong<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the <hi>French</hi> King in the <hi>Weſt-Indies,</hi> and elſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>where, and afterwards Compelled to enter into his Service.</p>
               <p>AND whereas divers other Perſons being Diſabled by their Loſſes in the late Dreadful Earthquake, and other Misfortunes, to Pay their Debts to avoid the Suits and, Proſecutions of their Creditors, have been likewiſe obliged to go off this Iſland; And by reaſon of the Offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces and Debts aforeſaid, cannot ſafely return again. And foraſmuch as nothing can more conduce to the Strength, Security, and Flouriſhing Condition of this Country, than Multitudes of People; and that it is become ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolutely neceſſary in Order thereunto, for putting the Iſland in this time of War, into a Poſture of Defence againſt the Enemy, to Invite and Encourage as much as poſſible, Their Majeſties Subjects to come to this Iſland, by Delivering them from the Penalties and For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feitures they have already incurr'd, and by preventing
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:109567:13"/>all Vexation and Trouble they may be put to hereafter, by any Proſecution in Their Majeſties Name for the ſaid Offences, or by means of the Suit or Suits of any other Perſons to whom they ſtand indebted:</p>
               <p>THE Lieutenant-Governour, Council, and Aſſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly, moſt humbly beſeech Their Majeſties to be Gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciouſly pleaſed to extend to all Perſons ſo Offending, as aforeſaid, Their Majeſties Free and General Pardon,<note place="margin">Free and Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral Pardon.</note> and for the Eaſe and Quiet of them and the reſt, to give convenient Time to Pay their Debts.</p>
               <p>AND that therefore it may be Enacted by the Lieutenant-Governour, Council and Aſſembly, and be it Enacted by the Authority of the ſame in Manner and Form following, that is to ſay, That all and every Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon and Perſons whoſoever, ſhall be, and are hereby Acquitted, Pardoned, Releaſed, and Diſcharged againſt Their Majeſties, Their Heirs and Succeſſors, and all others whomſoever, of, and from all manner of Penal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties incurr'd by Serving under the <hi>French</hi> King or his Subjects as aforeſaid; and all Crimes and Offences, Acts of Hoſtility, or Violence whatſoever (Treaſon and Murder excepted) and of, and from all manner of De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>predations by Sea or by Land, and all other Crimes, Offences and Miſdemeanors whatſoever, already done and committed before the Firſt Day of this Seſſion, in the Year of our Lord One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Three, and not otherwiſe or afterwards; And of and from all manner of Forfeitures, Penalties, Pains Corporal, and Pains Pecuniary, and all Suits, Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments and Executions, for, or by reaſon of the ſame, or any of them.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That all and every Perſon or Perſons that have committed Piracy or Robbery by Sea, and not Murder or Treaſon, that ſhall come hither,<note place="margin">Time of Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>render.</note> and Surrender and Submit themſelves within Ten Days after their Arrival
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:109567:14"/>in this Iſland, unto the Commander in Chief for the time being, and give in moderate Security for their future Good Behaviour, that then, and in ſuch Caſe, the ſaid Commander in Chief ſhall be by Vertue of this Act obliged to extend to ſuch Perſon or Perſons ſo Submitting and Surrendring as aforeſaid, Their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties Gracious Pardon under the Great Seal of this Iſland, for the Crime or Crimes afore-mentioned, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Let, Hindrance, or Moleſtation from Their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties Attorney-General, or any other Perſon or Perſons whatſoever; for which Pardon, the Parties to whom Their Majeſties Mercy is ſo extended,<note place="margin">Fee for Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don.</note> ſhall pay the Summ of Forty Shillings, and no more, to be paid as a full Fee unto ſuch Officer or Officers as the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mander in Chief ſhall Direct and Appoint to receive the ſame.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted, That the Attorney-General, or any other Officer or Officers whatſoever, that ſhall preſume by any way or means, directly or indi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rectly, to Exact any Summ or Summs of Money of any Perſon or Perſons whatſoever, to whom ſuch Act of Mercy is extended,<note place="margin">Caſe of Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>action.</note> or intended to be extended, ſhall forfeit the Summ of One Hundred Pound, currant Money, one Half to Their Majeſties, for, and towards the Support of the Government of this Iſland, and the Contingent Charges thereof; and the other Half to the Patty injured, to be recovered by Action of Debt, Bill, Plaint, or Information in any Court of Record within this Iſland, where no Eſſoyne, Protection, Injunction, Wager of Law, or <hi>Nonvult ulterius proſequi,</hi> ſhall be allowed; any Law, Cuſtom or Uſage, or any Thing in this Act ſeeming to the contrary in any wiſe notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That this Their Majeſties Free-Pardon as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, ſhall be as good and effectual in the Law to every of the ſaid Perſons before-mentioned, as the ſame Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:109567:14"/>ſhould have been, if all and every the Perſons, and all and ſingular the Offences aforeſaid, had been parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cularly, ſingularly, eſpecially, and plainly Named, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hearſed, and Specified, and alſo Pardoned by proper and expreſs Words and Names, and be as fully, largely,<note place="margin">This Pardon to be taken in the largeſt Senſe.</note> amply and beneficially Underſtood, Interpreted and Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pounded to all Intents and Purpoſes, againſt Their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties, Their Heirs and Succeſſors, and all others, to, and for the Benefit, Advantage, and Favour of the Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons before intended to be Pardoned, as the ſame can, or may be Underſtood, Interpreted and Expounded; any Statutes, Acts, Laws, Cuſtoms, or Uſages hereto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore had, made or uſed to the contrary in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Lieutenant-Governour, Council and Aſſembly, and by the Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity of the ſame, That all and every Perſon or Perſons whomſoever, that ſhall come and Reſide here, and Claim the Benefit of this Act, and be employed in the Service of the Country in Privateering Trade, or otherwiſe, ſhall by Vertue hereof be Protected, Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cepted, and Excuſed from the Payment of their ſaid Debts, contracted before their coming hither, or their going off from hence, for the ſpace of Five Years, to be computed from the Firſt Day of this preſent Seſſion, and during the ſaid Time, that all real, perſonal,<note place="margin">Time for Debtors.</note> or mixt Actions, and all Arreſts, Proceſs, Suits, Informa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, Judgments, Executions, and all other Proſecu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions whatſoever, to be had, commenced, ſued or pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecuted for, or by reaſon of their ſaid Debts, or any Summ or Summs of Money by them as aforeſaid, Due or Owing to any Perſon or Perſons whomſoever, be, and are hereby Suſpended, Reſpited and Diſcharged, and made Void, for and during the ſaid Term of Five Years and no longer.</p>
               <p>PROVIDED always, and it is the true Intent and Meaning of this preſent Act, That no Perſon or
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:109567:15"/>Perſons claiming the Benefit of the ſame, ſhall plead the Statute of Limitation in their Favour or behalf, as if the ſaid Intermiſſion had not been after the Expiration of the ſaid Five Years, but that the ſame ſhall be accounted as if this Law had not been made, any Thing in this Act seeming to the contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND if any Action or Suit hereby Suſpended, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpited and Diſcharged, ſhall be Commenced or Proſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuted, every Perſon ſo Sued may plead the General Iſſue, and give this Act and the Special Matter in E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vidence; and if the Plaintiff ſhall become Nonſuit,<note place="margin">Suit commen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ced contrary to this Act.</note> or forbear further Proſecution, or ſuffer Diſcontinuance, or if a Verdict ſhall paſs againſt him, the ſaid Plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiff ſhall for ever abſolutely Forfeit and Loſe his Ori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginal Debt ſo Sued for, and beſides, Pay to the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant his Double Coſts and Charges out of Purſe; to be Aſſeſſed by the Jury, or the Judges of the Court, where ſuch Action or Suit ſhall be Commenced, and Levied by Rule of Court, of the ſaid Plaintiff's Goods and Chattels, or the ſaid Plaintiff to ſtand commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted till Payment thereof, at the Diſcretion of the ſaid Court.</p>
               <p>PROVIDED always, nevertheleſs, That no Perſon ſhall take, or have any Benefit or Advantage by this Act, or any thing therein contained, who ſhall not within Twenty Days after his Arrival,<note place="margin">Names to be enrolled.</note> cauſe his Name to be Entred into the Office of Inrolments for this Iſland, in a Book to be kept there for that particular Purpoſe, and Claim, and Demand the Benefit of the ſame; which ſaid Claim, and Demand, and Entry of his Name as aforeſaid, ſhall be to all Intents and Purpoſes; as effectual and available in the Law, as if the ſaid Perſon had been herein particularly named and expreſſed, and an atteſted Copy of the ſaid Entry and Claim as aforeſaid, ſhall be pleaded in any Court, and of as much Authority, Force and Validity in the Law, as this pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Act, or Special Pardon under the Broad Seal as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid;
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:109567:15"/>any Statutes, Acts, Laws, Uſages or Cuſtoms to the contrary in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That the Secretary, or Clerk of the Enrolments for the time being,<note place="margin">Fee for En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rolment.</note> ſhall not refuſe to make Entry of ſuch Claim and Demand as aforeſaid, and give an atteſted Copy thereof; or take more than Fifteen Pence for ſuch Entry, and the Copy thereof, under the Penalty of Ten Pounds for every ſuch Offence, to be paid to him, who by Bill, Plaint, Information, or Action of Debt, ſhall Sue for the ſame.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That whereas by an Act of this Country, Enti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tled, <hi>An Act for Reſtraining and Puniſhing Privateers and Pyrates;</hi> in which Act, among other Things,<note place="margin">Relation to a former Act.</note> there is contained one Clauſe, Branch and Article, whereby it was thus Enacted: Be it further Enacted by the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority aforeſaid, That all and every Perſon and Perſons that ſhall any way knowingly, Entertain, Harbour, Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceal, Trade, or Hold any Correſpondence by Letter, or otherwiſe, with any Perſon or Perſons that ſhall be deemed, or adjudged to be Privateers, Pyrates, or other Offenders within the Conſtruction of this Act; and that ſhall not readily endeavour to the beſt of his or their Power, to apprehend, or cauſe to be apprehended, ſuch Offender or Offenders, ſhall be liable to be Proſecuted as Acceſſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries and Confederates, and to ſuffer ſuch Pains and Penal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties as in ſuch Caſe by Law is provided.</p>
               <p>WHICH ſaid Clauſe, Branch, or Article contained in the ſaid Act, and every Word, Matter, and Thing contained in that Clauſe, Branch or Article, ſhall from henceforth be repealed, annulled, revoked, annihilated,<note place="margin">Cauſe re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pealed.</note> and utterly made void for ever, any Thing in the ſaid Act to the contrary in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <pb n="26" facs="tcp:109567:16"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>An ACT</hi> For making <hi>Kingſton</hi> a Pariſh.</head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">Preamble.</note>WHEREAS it hath pleaſed Almighty God by his late Dreadful Judgment, to lay Waſte, and Deſtroy the Habitations and Dwelling-Places of many of the People, late of <hi>Port-Royal,</hi> whereby they were neceſſitated to reſort to ſome more convenient Place, wherein to Unite and Settle for the Advantage of Trade, and better Conveniency of Living, and did by the Encouragement of the then Government, Repair to, and Settle upon a certain Place now called and known by the Name of <hi>Kingſton,</hi> in the Pariſh of St. <hi>Andrews,</hi> on the Harbour of <hi>Port-Royal</hi> aforeſaid; and have with great Trouble and Charge made a Conſiderable Progreſs in Building and Settling there, and being willing and deſirous there to Continue by reaſon of the Convenient Situation of the Place, and Commodiouſneſs of the Channel and Har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour:</p>
               <p>BE it therefore Enacted and Ordained by Their Majeſties Lieutenant-Governour, Council and Aſſembly, and it is hereby Enacted and Ordained by the Authority of the ſame,<note place="margin">Bounds there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of.</note> That the aforeſaid Place commonly called and known by the Name of <hi>Kingſton,</hi> lying in the Pariſh of St. <hi>Andrews,</hi> on the Harbour of <hi>Port-Royal,</hi> bounded Southerly by the Harbour, Weſterly and Nor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therly by the Line of the Land of Sir <hi>William Beeſton</hi> Knight, and to continue from a <hi>Callabaſh</hi> his North-Eaſterly Corner Tree, by a ſtrait Line to the Foot of the Long Mountain, Eighty Chain diſtant from the Sea, and from thence towards Three Rivers at the ſame Diſtance from the Sea, until it meets with the
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:109567:16"/>Bounds of the Pariſh of <hi>Port-Royal;</hi> And alſo all that Part of the Harbour which lies to the North-Eaſterly and Eaſterly Part of the Middle Ground, ſhall be and for ever hereafter be taken and eſteemed to all Intents and Purpoſes, an intire and diſtinct Pariſh, ſeparate from the ſaid Pariſh of Sr. <hi>Andrews,</hi> and be called and known by the Name of the Town and Pariſh of <hi>Kingſton,</hi> and Have, Uſe, Exerciſe, and Enjoy all and every the Powers, Authorities, Benefits, Priviledges, Rights, Immunities and Cuſtoms, that all or any of the Pariſhes or Precincts within this Iſland, have, or ought to Have, Uſe, Exerciſe, or Enjoy of Common Right, or by Vertue of any General Act or Act of this Country, as fully, amply and effectually, as if the ſame had then been a diſtinct and ſeparate Pariſh or Precinct, and therein by Name expreſly mentioned and ſpecified: And particularly, that there ſhall be choſen Three Repreſentatives to Serve in every Aſſembly here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after, or after the firſt Prorogation of this preſent Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſembly for the ſaid Town and Pariſh of <hi>Kingſton,</hi> any Law, Cuſtom or Uſage to the contrary in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, That for the Eaſe of the Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chants and Trading People of the ſaid Town of <hi>Kingſton,</hi> that there be Erected, Eſtabliſhed and Held in the ſaid Town, a Quarter-Seſſions for the Conſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation of the Peace, and a Court of <hi>Common-Pleas,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Courts of Juſtice.</note> with the ſame Power and Authority, that is, or hath been lately Held or Exerciſed at <hi>Port-Royal,</hi> which ſaid Court ſhall be held the firſt time on the Second <hi>Thurſday</hi> in <hi>October,</hi> in this preſent Year One Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Six Hundred Ninety Three, and afterwards Once every Two Months, and the Seſſions every Three Months, any Thing in this Act to the contrary not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding.</p>
               <pb n="28" facs="tcp:109567:17"/>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, that the Receiver-General, Secre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tary of this Iſland, and Naval Officer for the time be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, do by Themſelves or Deputies within One Month after the paſſing this Act, keep, or cauſe to be kept in the Town of <hi>Kingſton</hi> aforeſaid, their ſeveral and reſpective Offices,<note place="margin">Publick Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fices.</note> as they now do, or heretofore have or ought to have done on <hi>Port-Royal,</hi> on Penalty of Fifty Pounds each for every Month, they or any of them ſhall Neglect or Refuſe to do the ſame, to be Recovered againſt them, or any of them, by Bill, Plaint, Information, or otherwiſe, in the Supreme Court of this Iſland; the One Half to Their Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties, for, and towards the Support of the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of this Iſland, and the contingent Charges there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, and the other Half to the Informer, or him that ſhall Sue for the ſame, wherein no Eſſoyn, Injun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction, Protection, Wager of Law, or <hi>Nonvult ulterius proſequi</hi> ſhall be Allowed.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <pb n="29" facs="tcp:109567:17"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>An ACT</hi> For the better Securing of <hi>Port Royal.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">Preamble.</note>WHEREAS the Town of <hi>Port-Royal</hi> is a Town of a very Conſiderable Trade, and of great Strength to reſiſt the Enemy in time of War, by reaſon of Their Majeſties Fortifications, and a great number of Houſes through the Mercy of God left ſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing thereon.</p>
               <p>AND whereas by the late Dreadful Earthquake the Land on the Back-Sea-ſide is ſettled lower than it was, by reaſon whereof the Sea hath more power to gain up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on it, and if not timely prevented by Wharfing to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſt the Violence thereof, may endanger the Houſes that are ſtanding on that Sea-ſide, for prevention whereof</p>
               <p>BE it Enacted and Ordained by Their Majeſties Lieutenant-Governour, Council and Aſſembly, and it is hereby Enacted and Ordained by the Authority of the ſame, That it ſhall and may be lawful, from, and after the Twenty Fifth day of <hi>July,</hi> in the Year of our Lord 1693. for the Juſtices and Veſtry of the Pariſh of <hi>Port-Royal,</hi> or the Major part of them, to Aſſeſs, Tax,<note place="margin">Mony for the Work.</note> and Levy ſuch Sum, or Sums of Mony, upon all and every the Freeholders of the ſaid Pariſh of <hi>Port-Royal,</hi> as to them ſhall ſeem Meet and Convenient, for, and towards the Wharfing, or otherwiſe Securing the Town of <hi>Port-Royal</hi> towards the Great-Sea-ſide abovementioned.</p>
               <pb n="30" facs="tcp:109567:18"/>
               <p>AND whereas after the Wharfs are made they may from time to time want Repairing, Be it therefore further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, and it is hereby En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted and Ordained by the Authority of the ſame; that it ſhall and may be lawful for the Juſtices and Veſtry of <hi>Port-Royal</hi> aforeſaid, or the Major part of them, to Aſſeſs, Tax,<note place="margin">For the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pairs.</note> and Levy yearly, and every Year, ſuch Sum or Sums of Mony upon the Freeholders of the ſaid Pariſh of <hi>Port-Royal,</hi> at ſuch times as to them ſhall ſeem requiſite or neceſſary, for Repairing and Maintaining the ſaid Wharfs; and that the Conſtable or Conſtables of the ſaid Pariſh of <hi>Port-Royal</hi> ſhall gather in the aboveſaid Monies ſo to be Levyed, Aſſeſſed and Taxed, as before mentioned and appointed by this preſent Act; and pay the ſame into the Hands of the Church-Wardens of the ſaid Pariſh of <hi>Port-Royal</hi> for the time being, Deducting to him or themſelves Four Pence in the Pound for Collecting the ſame. And in Caſe any Conſtable or Conſtables ſhall neglect his or their Duty in Collecting, Gathering, or Paying in the Mony ſo Collected by Vertue of this Act, he or they ſo neglecting his or their Duty therein, ſhall Forfeit for every ſuch Offence the Sum of Twenty Pounds.</p>
               <p>AND in Caſe any Perſon or Perſons ſhall refuſe or delay to pay his or their Tax ſo to be Aſſeſſed, Taxed, and Levyed,<note place="margin">Caſe of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſal.</note> as in this preſent Act is preſcribed, Be it fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, that it ſhall and may be lawful to, and for any two of Their Majeſties Juſtices of the Peace of the Pariſh of <hi>Port-Royal</hi> aforeſaid, to Iſſue out their Warrant of Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſs, directed to any Conſtable of the ſaid Pariſh, to Levy the ſame upon the Goods or Chattels of him, her, or them ſo refuſing or delaying to pay the ſame, and Sell the ſame at Publick Outcry, returning the Overplus, if any be, to the Owner.</p>
               <pb n="31" facs="tcp:109567:18"/>
               <p>AND to the Intent that the Mony which ſhall be Collected and Raiſed by virtue of this Act, may be ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plyed to the uſe and purpoſe by this Act mentioned and directed, Be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority aforeſaid, that the Church-Warden or Church-Wardens of the ſaid Pariſh of <hi>Port-Royal</hi> for the time being, ſhall, and are hereby required from time to time to pay the Mony ariſing by virtue of this Act to ſuch Perſon or Perſons, and to ſuch Uſes as the Juſtices and Veſtry,<note place="margin">Payment to whom.</note> or major part of them ſhall direct and appoint, and that the Church-Wardens of the ſaid Pariſh for the time be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ſhall keep a diſtinct Accompt of the Mony by them, and each of them received by virtue of this Act, and likewiſe render a true and juſt Accompt thereof to the Juſtices, and Veſtry of the ſaid Pariſh of <hi>Port-Royal,</hi> when thereunto required, and alſo pay the full Balance of the ſame unto the ſucceeding Church-Wardens, or to whomſoever the ſaid Juſtices and Veſtry, or major part of them ſhall direct and appoint, under the Penalty of Fifty Pounds for every Offence committed contrary to their Duty in this Act enjoyned.</p>
               <p>AND whereas ſeveral of the Freeholders of <hi>Port-Royal</hi> may be, or are not Reſident or Inhabitants on the ſaid Place, for the better Recovery of the ſaid Tax to be Aſſeſſed as aforeſaid, Be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, that in ſuch Caſes, from,<note place="margin">Abſent Free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holders.</note> and after the Twenty Fifth Day of <hi>July,</hi> One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Three, an Action of Debt ſhall Lye in any Court of Record, or before any Juſtice of the Peace, as in other Debts, for the Church-Wardens of the reſpective Pariſh of <hi>Port-Royal,</hi> and their Succeſſors to Recover againſt any of the ſaid Perſons Rated, or Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſed by virtue of this Act, or any of them, or their Heirs, Executors, Adminiſtrators, Aſſigns, Agents or Attorneys here, all ſuch Sum and Sums of Mony as are, or ſhall be Rated or Aſſeſſed upon them as aforeſaid. And
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:109567:19"/>that the ſame Rate or Aſſeſſment produced in ſuch Court of Record, or before ſuch Juſtice of the Peace as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, ſhall be ſufficient Evidence and Proof for the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covery of all ſuch Sum or Sums Mony ſo Rated or Aſſeſſed as aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That if any Perſon or Perſons being Seized, Poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſed, or Intereſted of, or in any Ground which was formerly builded upon, and the Houſes thereupon being now Deſtroyed,<note place="margin">Neglect of Rebuilding.</note> or pulled Down at the times, or by the means of the late Dreadful Earthquake, ſhall not with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in Three Years next Enſuing Build on the ſame, that then the Judges of the Court of <hi>Common-Pleas</hi> of the ſaid Pariſh for the time being, or any one of them, ſhall forthwith cauſe publick Proclamation to be made, as well at, or upon the ſaid Ground, as alſo in the Court-Houſe of the ſaid Pariſh, thereby to give notice to all Perſons that ſhall, or may be therein Concerned, to cauſe the ſame to be rebuilded within the ſpace of Nine Months then next following, and in Caſe the Owners thereof, or other Perſon or Perſons having Intereſt therein, ſhall refuſe or neglect to Rebuild the ſame within ſuch time as aforeſaid, that then, and in ſuch Caſe the ſaid Judges of the ſaid Court, or any one of them, are here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by Authorized to Iſſue out their Warrants to the Provoſt Marſhal for the time being, requiring him to Impannel, and return before them, or any one of them, a Jury of good and lawful Men of the ſaid Pariſh, which the ſaid Provoſt Marſhal is hereby Authorized and Required to do accordingly, which Jury ſo Returned ſhall upon their Oaths to be Adminiſtred to them by the ſaid Judges, or one of them, who are likewiſe hereby Authorized to Adminiſter the ſame, Enquire, Eſtimate, and Aſſeſs the true and juſt Value of ſuch void Ground, according to their Judgments; and that from, and after ſuch Enquiry and Valuation thereof made as aforeſaid, by Inqueſt of the ſaid Jury, it ſhall, and may be Lawful to, and for
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:109567:19"/>the ſaid Judge or Judges to make Sale of the Fee and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>heritance thereof, by Conveyance under his or their Hands and Seals, to any Perſon or Perſons that will Purchaſe the ſame at ſuch Price, at which the ſame ſhall have been ſo as aforeſaid Eſtimated and Valued by the ſaid Jury, and the Monies thereupon to be received of the Purchaſers thereof, ſhall forthwith be paid into the Hands of the Church-wardens of the ſaid Pariſh for the time being, and from thence to be iſſued out, and Paid by the ſaid Church-wardens for the time being, unto ſuch Perſon or Perſons, who ſhall have any Eſtate or Intereſt in, to, or out of the ſame, according to his or their reſpective Eſtate or Eſtates, Title or Intereſt, which Sale ſo made and Enrolled in the Office of En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rolments of this Iſland,<note place="margin">Sale to be Enrolled.</note> ſhall be Final and Concluſive to all other Perſons whatſoever, and ſhall Bar them, their Heirs and Aſſigns, to Claim any Eſtate, Right, Title, or Intereſt of, in, or out of the Grounds ſo Sold, Precedent to the ſaid Sale; and the Purchaſer or Pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſers thereof, his, and their Heirs and Aſſigns, ſhall, and may by virtue of this Act, have, hold, and enjoy the ſame againſt all Perſons Claiming any Eſtate, Right, Title, or Intereſt in, to, or out of the ſame, his, her, and their Heirs, Executors, Adminiſtrators, and Aſſigns, freed and diſcharged of, and from Incum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brances in Eſtate, Title, Charge, or otherwiſe, Prece<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent to the ſaid Sale: Their Majeſties Quit-Rents only excepted.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority aforeſaid, and it is hereby Enacted and Ordain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by the Authority of the ſame, That the Receiver General, and Naval Officer of this Iſland, ſhall by themſelves, or lawful Deputy,<note place="margin">Offices to be kept on <hi>Port-Royal.</hi>
                  </note> keep their Offices on <hi>Port-Royal,</hi> as at any time heretofore they have, or ought to have done: and that the Secretary of this Iſland, ſhall from time to time by his lawful. Deputy keep his Office at <hi>Port-Royal,</hi> as at any time heretofore has, now
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:109567:20"/>doth, or ought to have done, under the Penalty of Fifty Pounds for every Month the Receiver General, Naval Officer, or Secretary of this Iſland, or any of them, ſhall neglect or refuſe to do the ſame.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, That all, and every the Fines and Forfeitures in this Act mentioned and contained,<note place="margin">Fines, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> how diſpoſed.</note> ſhall be one half to Their Majeſties, Their Heirs and Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors, for and towards the Support of the Government of this Iſland, and the contingent Charges thereof, and the other half to the Pariſh of <hi>Port-Royal,</hi> for, and to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards the Wharfing, Repairing, and Maintaining the Wharfs ſo to be Made, Repaired, and Maintained, as in this Act mentioned, and to, and for no other Uſe, In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent, or Purpoſe whatſoever; to be recovered in any Court of Record within this Iſland, by Action of Debt, Bill, Plaint, or Information, wherein no Eſſoin, In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>junction, Protection, Wager of Law, or <hi>Nonvult ulteri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>us proſequi,</hi> ſhall be allowed, any Law, Cuſtom, or Uſage to the contrary in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <pb n="35" facs="tcp:109567:20"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>An ACT</hi> For Making and Clearing a Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Road from St. <hi>Mary</hi>'s and St. <hi>George</hi>'s into the Pariſh of St. <hi>Andrew</hi>'s.</head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">Preamble.</note>WHEREAS by reaſon of the uncertainty of the Bounds of the Pariſhes of St. <hi>Mary</hi>'s, St. <hi>George</hi>'s, and St. <hi>Andrew</hi>'s, the Paths leading from St. <hi>Mary</hi>'s and St. <hi>George</hi>'s, have not yet been Laid out and Cleared, to the great Hindrance and Damage of the Inhabitants thereof; and it being requiſite, as well for Their Majeſties Service in Tranſporting ſpeedy Succours to each Place, as for the neceſſary uſe of Their Majeſties Liege People; that a Publick Road be laid out from the ſaid Pariſhes of St. <hi>Mary</hi>'s and St. <hi>George</hi>'s, into the Pariſh of St. <hi>Andrew</hi>'s:</p>
               <p>BE it therefore Enacted and Ordained by the Lieu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenant-Governour, Council and Aſſembly, And it is hereby Enacted and Ordained by the Authority of the ſame: That the Path or Road, as it is now uſed,<note place="margin">The Cauſe of the Road.</note> from the <hi>Orange</hi> River Plantation, in the Pariſh or St. <hi>Mary</hi>'s, over <hi>Little Tom</hi>'s River, and from thence over <hi>Viney</hi> Ridge, leaving the Plantation belonging to Colonel <hi>Thomas Clarke</hi> to the Eaſtward, unto the Plantation late of <hi>Andrew Holloway,</hi> deceaſed, at <hi>Wagwater,</hi> and ſo into the Pariſh of St. <hi>Andrew</hi>'s, be a Publick Road, or King's High-way, between the ſaid two Pariſhes of St. <hi>Mary</hi>'s and St. <hi>Andrew</hi>'s; and that the Path or Road from <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>notta</hi> River Bay in the Pariſh of St. <hi>George</hi>'s, leading to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards St. <hi>Andrew</hi>'s aforeſaid, ſhall by its neareſt and moſt
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:109567:21"/>convenient Courſe fall into the Path coming from the ſaid <hi>Orange</hi> River in St. <hi>Mary</hi>'s, upon a Ridge or Moun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain, commonly called or known by the Name of <hi>Mam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mee</hi> Ridge, and from thence forward along the ſaid Path to <hi>Little Tom</hi>'s River, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And that the ſame be a Publick Road, or King's High-way, between the ſaid two Pariſhes of St. <hi>George</hi>'s and St. <hi>Andrew</hi>'s as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, That the Surveyors of the High-ways for the Pariſh of St. <hi>Mary</hi>'s, do yearly, and as often as need ſhall require, clear and amend the ſaid Road,<note place="margin">Surveyors limited.</note> or High-way, from the <hi>Orange</hi> River aforeſaid, over the ſaid <hi>Mammee</hi> Ridge, unto the Ford at the Foot of the ſaid Hill at <hi>Little Tom</hi>'s River aforeſaid: and that the Pariſh of St. <hi>George</hi>'s alſo clear their Road or High-way from <hi>Annotta</hi> Bay as aforeſaid, unto the ſaid Place, as it ſhall fall into the Path on <hi>Mammee</hi> Ridge as aforeſaid, coming from the ſaid <hi>Orange</hi> River Plantation; and that the Pariſh of St. <hi>Andrew</hi>'s clear the ſaid Ford and Road, or King's High-way, leading from thence over <hi>Viney</hi> Ridge aforeſaid, leaving the Plantation of the ſaid Colonel <hi>Thomas Clarke</hi> to the Eaſtward as aforeſaid, unto the Plantation of the ſaid <hi>Andrew Holloway</hi> and <hi>Wagwater,</hi> and ſo forward into the Pariſh of St. <hi>Andrew</hi>'s.</p>
               <p>AND it is hereby further Enacted, That the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpective Surveyors of the High-ways, and Inhabitants of the Pariſhes of St. <hi>Mary</hi>'s, St. <hi>George</hi>'s, and St. <hi>Andrew</hi>'s, ſhall be ſeverally ſubject to the like Pains and Penalties,<note place="margin">Penalty on neglect of Duty.</note> for their, or any of their neglect of their Duty therein, and be in the ſame way and manner Recovered, and in the like manner applied, as is provided for and ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed in the Act for the High-ways, for the neglect of their ſeveral Duties in the like kind.</p>
               <pb n="37" facs="tcp:109567:21"/>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">Proviſo.</note>PROVIDED always, That if at any time here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after it ſhall be found neceſſary that the ſaid Path or Paths, or any part of them ſhould be turned or altered: That it ſhall, and may be done in ſuch manner as in the ſaid Act for the High-ways is provided and appointed in the ſaid Act for turning, or altering Old-ways to more Conveniencies, any Law, Cuſtom, or Uſage to the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <head>
                  <hi>An ACT</hi> Appointing the Prices of Meats, and Regulating Markets.</head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">Preamble.</note>FOR Prevention of the many Hardſhips and Abuſes that may be put upon the Inhabitants of this Iſland, by thoſe that Sell in Publick Markets the ſeveral ſorts of Meats hereafter mentioned, and demand Extravagant Prices for the ſame;</p>
               <p>BE it Enacted by Their Majeſties Lieutenant-Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernour, Council, and Aſſembly of this Iſland, and it is hereby Enacted and Ordained by the Authority of the ſame, that no Perſon or Perſons upon any pretence whatſoever, Selling in any Publick Market within this Iſland, any of the ſeveral Kinds of Meat hereafter named, preſume to Ask, Demand, or Receive for Freſh Beef,<note place="margin">Beef, Goat, Mutton, Veal, Hog.</note> or Goat, any more, higher, or greater Price, than Four Pence <hi>per</hi> Pound; Mutton Six Pence; Veal, the Breaſt and Loin Nine Pence, and any other part thereof Seven Pence Half-peny the Pound; Hog, that weigheth Twelve Pounds the Quarter, or under, Seven Pence Half-peny; and all weighing above, Six Pence the Pound;
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:109567:22"/>Lamb or Kid, Seven Pence Half Peny the Pound: all which ſaid Meat ſhall be weighed without the Head, Entrails, or Feet, and no Suet to be ſold at higher Rates than the Meats aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, That any Meat brought into the Market, and offered after Cut up to be Sold for Veal,<note place="margin">Beef for Veal.</note> weigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing above Twenty Five Pounds the Quarter, ſhall be adjudged Beef, and for Lamb weighing above Eight Pounds the Quarter, ſhall be deemed Mutton, and each Sold by the Quarter or Joint, at the reſpective Prices in this Act beforementioned.</p>
               <p>AND to prevent Selling and putting off Old and ſmall Mutton for Lamb,<note place="margin">Mutton for Lamb.</note> be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, that all Lamb ſhall be brought into the open Market with the Heads on, and ſhewn before Cut up to the Clerk thereof with the uſual Signs and Marks of Diſtinction, that he upon Scruple may Determine the Matter between Buyer and Seller.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That no Common Seller, Butcher, Cutter up of Tortle,<note place="margin">Tortle.</note> or any other Perſon whatſoever, Sell Tortle, or any of the Meats beforementioned by Retail, but in open Market, where they ſhall not refuſe to Sell the ſame to any Perſon, bringing Ready Mony, by the Quarter, Joint, or Piece by weight, not leſs than the Value of Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven Pence Half-peny at the Prices aforeſaid, without Conditionally impoſing upon the Buyer the Head, Feet, Inwards, or any part thereof, or Meat of any other Kind whatſoever; which Meat ſo Bought, and Paid for, ſhall immediately be, or cauſed to be removed out of the ſaid Market by the Perſon Buying the ſame.</p>
               <p>AND to the end that it may be underſtood what within this Act ſhall be accounted the Publick and Open Market, Be it Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, that
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:109567:22"/>the Place appointed by the Juſtices in Seſſions for the Sel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling there the ſeveral Sorts of Meat in this Act men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned, ſhall be deemed the Publick Market-Place,<note place="margin">Publick Market, Place and Time.</note> and the Markets opening by the Ringing of the Bell by the Clerk thereof, or his order; which on <hi>Saturdays</hi> ſhall be at three of the Clock after noon, and on that, and all other days, <hi>Sundays</hi> excepted, at Five of the Clock in the Morning, and not ſooner; in which place, and after which time, the Market ſhall be adjudged Open and Publick, within this Act as aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>BE it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That from, and after the Tenth Day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> of this preſent Year One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Three, that this Act, and every Clauſe thereof, is, and ſhall be of Force to all Intents and Purpoſes whatſoever.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That all, and every Perſon whatſoever, Seller, Buyer, or Officer, that ſhall Offend againſt any Particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar in this Act mentioned, or contained,<note place="margin">Forfeiture on Offending.</note> or any Branch thereof, he, ſhe, or they ſo Offending, ſhall Forfeit Forty Shillings for every ſuch Offence, one half to the Church-wardens of the Pariſh where ſuch Offence ſhall be Committed, for the Uſe of the ſaid Pariſh, the other half to the Clerk of the Market, Informer, or who ſhall Sue for the ſame, to be Recovered before any Juſtice of the Peace, any Law, Cuſtom, or Uſage to the Contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <pb n="40" facs="tcp:109567:23"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>An ACT</hi> For Reimburſing Their Majeſties Treaſury.</head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">Preamble.</note>WHEREAS Their Majeſties Revenue is conſiderably Anticipated, the Principal Branch of which is the Cuſtoms of Wines, and that great Quantities were loſt at <hi>Port-Royal,</hi> in the late dreadful Earthquake.</p>
               <p>WE, therefore, your Majeſties moſt Dutiful and Loyal Subjects, the Aſſembly of this your Iſland, do moſt hum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly beſeech your Majeſty that it may be Enacted, and be it Enacted by your Majeſties Lieutenant-Governour, Council, and Aſſembly, and it is hereby Enacted and Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dained by the Authority of the ſame, that from, and after the Seventeenth Day of this Inſtant <hi>Auguſt,</hi> One Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Six Hundred Ninety Three, there ſhall be Raiſed, Levyed, and Paid unto your Majeſties for the Term, and time of Three Months, from, and after the ſaid Seven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth Day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Impoſt on Wines.</note> and no longer, as an Additional Duty and Impoſt upon <hi>Madera</hi> Wines Imported, over and above what is already payable for the ſame, <hi>viz.</hi> the Sum of Forty Shillings for every Tun.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That for every Slave Exported by way of Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chandize, from, and after the ſaid Seventeenth Day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> for the Term aforeſaid, and no longer, the Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>porter or Owner ſhall pay the Sum of Twenty Shillings <hi>per</hi> Head,<note place="margin">Negroes.</note> as an Impoſt to Their Majeſties, all which <hi>Negroes</hi> ſo Exported ſhall be Entred in the Receiver-Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nerals Office, and immediately Bond given by the
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:109567:23"/>Owner or Exporter to Their Majeſties, for the Payment of the Money into the Hand of the Receiver-General, or his Lawful Deputy, within One Month after the Entry ſo made as aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>AND whoſoever ſhall perſume after the ſaid Seven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth Day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> to Export any Slave or Slaves, and not make ſuch Entry, and give Bond, and Pay as before in this Act is Directed,<note place="margin">Forfeiture up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Non-Entry of Slaves.</note> ſhall Forfeit for every ſuch Slave ſo Exported, the Summ of Fifty Pounds, to be Recovered by Action of Debt, Bill, Plaint, or Information in any Court of <hi>Record</hi> with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in this Iſland, One Half to Their Majeſties, for and towards the Support of the Government of this I<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſland, and the Contingent Charges thereof; and the other Half to the Informer, or he or they that ſhall Sue for the ſame, wherein no Eſſoyn, Injunction, Prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction, Wager of Law, or <hi>Nonvult ulterius proſequi</hi> ſhall be allowed.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That every Merchant, or other Perſon Importing any <hi>Madera</hi> Wines into this Iſland,<note place="margin">Of Wines.</note> from and after the ſaid Seventeenth Day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> for and during the ſaid Term of Three Months, and no longer; do, and ſhall make Entry, make up Accounts, and give Bonds to Pay the ſaid Summs ariſing by Vertue of this Act, according to the Way and Method, and under the ſame Penalty for not doing the ſame, and to be Recovered in the ſame Manner as is Directed by an Act of this Iſland, Entitled, <hi>An Act for Raiſing a Publick Revenue for the Support of the Government of this His MAJESTY's Iſland.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the Money ariſing by Vertue of this Act, ſhall be to the Uſe of Their Majeſties for the Support of the Government of this Iſland, and the Contingent Charges thereof, and towards the Repair<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:109567:24"/>the Loſſes the Revenue has ſuſtained by the Wines and other Merchandiſes loſt in the Earth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quake.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <head>
                  <hi>An ACT</hi> To Reimburſe Their MAJESTIES Treaſury, and Incourage Their Subjects to come and Settle in this Iſland.</head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">Preamble.</note>WHEREAS Their Majeſties Revenue is conſiderably Anticipated, the Principal Branch of which, is the Cuſtoms of Wines, great Quantities whereof were loſt at <hi>Port-Royal,</hi> in the late Dreadful Earthquake.</p>
               <p>WE therefore Your Majeſties moſt Dutiful and Loyal Subjects, the Aſſembly of this Your Iſland of <hi>Jamaica,</hi> do moſt humbly beſeech Your Majeſties, That it may be Enacted, and be it Enacted by Your Majeſties Lieutenant-Governour, Council and Aſſembly; and it is hereby Enacted by the Authority of the ſame, that from, and after the Seventeenth Day of <hi>November,</hi> in this preſent Year One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Three, ſhall be Raiſed, Levied, and Paid unto Your Majeſties, Your Heirs and Succeſſors, for the Term and Time of Five Years, from the ſaid Seventeenth Day of <hi>November,</hi> and no longer, as an Additional Duty and Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſt, on the ſeveral Liquors hereafter mentioned, over and above what is already payable for the ſame,<note place="margin">Additional Duty on Wines.</note> 
                  <hi>viz.</hi> for every Tun of <hi>Spaniſh</hi> and <hi>Madera</hi> Wine imported into this Iſland, the Summ of Forty Shillings; all Wines
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:109567:24"/>of the Growth of the Weſtern Iſlands, or Mixture of <hi>Madera</hi> Wines, with thoſe of the Weſtern Iſlands, the Summ of Five Pound <hi>per</hi> Tun; for every Tun of <hi>French</hi> or <hi>Rheniſh</hi> Wines, Thirty Shillings; for every Tun of Beer or Syder, Four Shillings; for every Tun of Mumm or Metheglin, Twenty Shillings; for every Gallon of Brandy, Six Pence; for every Gallon of <hi>Engliſh</hi> Spirits, Three Pence, and ſo proportionably for a Greater or Leſſer Quantity. All which ſaid Liquors ſhall be duly Entred, and under the ſame Penalties and Regulations as in a former Act of this Country, Entitled, <hi>An Act for Raiſing a Publick Revenue for the Support of the Government of this His Majeſty's Iſland.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, That for every Slave exported from this Iſland by way of Merchandize, the Exporter or Owner ſhall Pay the Summ of Twenty Shillings,<note place="margin">On Slaves.</note> as an Impoſt to Their Majeſties, for and during the Term and Time of Five Years aforeſaid, excepting only ſuch Slaves, who by Miſdemeanor ſhall by the Judgment of Two Juſtices of the Peace and Three Freeholders, be ordered to be Tranſported off this Iſland, by the Maſter or Owner of ſuch Slave or Slaves.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, That out of the ſeveral Summ or Summs of Money ariſing by Virtue of this Act, and one other Act, Entitled, <hi>An Act to Reimburſe Their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties Treaſury,</hi> made this preſent Seſſion; there ſhall be firſt Deducted and Paid unto Their Majeſties,<note place="margin">Deduction to Their Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties.</note> to and for the Uſe of Their Majeſties, the Summ of One Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Seven Hundred and Seventy Four Pounds Six<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teen Shillings, as a Summ equivalent to Their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties, for the Cuſtoms of Wines loſt in the Earth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quake.</p>
               <pb n="44" facs="tcp:109567:25"/>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted, That upon due Proof made in the Supreme Court of <hi>Judicature,</hi> an Action of Debt ſhall lie for Their Majeſties againſt any Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon whatſoever,<note place="margin">Bond not produced.</note> their Executors, Adminiſtrators, or At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torneys that ſtand Indebted to Their Majeſties for Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtoms, whether Bond be given or not, without being obliged to produce it; the giving of which ſhall not be pleaded in Bar, except by the Perſons named, and for the Summs in this Act mentioned. Provided alſo, that if the Bond for the ſaid Debt, ſuppoſed to be loſt, ſhall afterwards be found and put in Suit, that then the ſaid Judgment ſhall be, and be pleaded in Bar to the ſame, and that the ſaid Actions be brought within Two Courts after this Act becomes in Force.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, That after the Deduction and Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the ſaid Summ of One Thouſand Seven Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Seventy Four Pounds Sixteen Shillings unto Their Majeſties,<note place="margin">Remainder after Dedu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction.</note> the remainder of the Monies ariſing by Vir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tue of this Act, and the Act before-mentioned, ſhall be and remain as a Fund to Encourage ſuch of Their Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties Subjects, or others as are willing to Tranſport them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves hither, and be applied to no other Uſe, Intent, or Purpoſe whatſoever.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That whereas <hi>Benjamin Way, Joſeph Seargeant, William Hutchinſon,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Caſe of ſome Private Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons.</note> 
                  <hi>Francis Hall</hi> and <hi>Edmond Edlyn,</hi> ſtand in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>debted to Their Majeſties in the ſeveral Summs follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, <hi>viz. Benjamin Way,</hi> in the Summ of Nine Hundred Twenty One Pounds Twelve Shillings; <hi>Joſeph Seargeant,</hi> in the Summ of One Hundred Eighty Seven Pounds Four Shillings; <hi>William Hutchinſon,</hi> in the Summ of One Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred and Four Pounds; <hi>Francis Hall,</hi> in the Summ of Four Hundred Pounds, and <hi>Edmond Edlyn</hi> in the Summ of One Hundred and Sixty Two Pounds, which ſaid Summs were due to Their Majeſties for the Cuſtoms
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:109567:25"/>of Wines which were loſt in the Earthquake: The ſaid <hi>Benjamin Way, Joſeph Seargeant, William Hutchinſon, Francis Hall</hi> and <hi>Edmond Edlyn,</hi> and every of them, their Heirs, Executors, and Adminiſtrators ſhall be, and are hereby for ever indemnified and ſaved Harmleſs againſt Their Majeſties, Their Heirs and Succeſſors, from Payment of the ſaid ſeveral Summs due from the ſaid ſeveral Perſons, or any Part thereof, as alſo from all manner of Action or Actions, Suit or Suits, againſt them, or any of them, their, or any of their Executors, Adminiſtrators or Aſſigns for the ſame, already commenced, or to be commenced; and if all, or any of the Perſons aforeſaid, be Sued or Impleaded, they may Plead the General Iſſue, and give this Act in Evidence; any Law, Cuſtom, or Uſage to the contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">Encourage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment for Settlers.</note>AND to the end it may be underſtood what ſort of People are by this Act intended to be Encouraged, Be it Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That all Tradeſmen, and other Perſons of what Calling or Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition ſoever, not able to Pay their Paſſages, excepting <hi>Jews,</hi> Cripples and Children under Eleven Years of Age, who upon Encouragement of this Act, are willing to Tranſport themſelves to this Iſland, ſhall upon Repair<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to any Maſter or Commander of any Ship or Veſſel Bound for this Iſland,<note place="margin">Paſſage paid, and Perſon free.</note> be received on Board his Ship or Veſſel, and after his or their Arrival in this Iſland, be Free from all manner of Servitude whatſoever, and have Liberty to Hire, and Imploy him, her, or themſelves here, how they think fit, in any Honeſt Trade, Service or Calling; and the Captain, Maſter, or Commander of ſuch Ship or Veſſel ſhall receive of the Treaſurers named and appointed by this Act, for the Paſſage of every Perſon ſo Tranſporting him or themſelves from <hi>England</hi> or <hi>Scotland,</hi> the Summ of Seven Pounds Ten Shillings, and for every Perſon from <hi>Ireland,</hi> the Summ of Six Pounds currant Money of this Iſland, without Fraud or De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lay.</p>
               <pb n="46" facs="tcp:109567:26"/>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That for each Perſon ſo brought hither from <hi>Eu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rope,</hi> the Captain,<note place="margin">Captains, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Encou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rag'd.</note> Maſter, or Commander of each Ship or Veſſel, ſhall for his Encouragement, and to his own Uſe receive of the ſaid Treaſurer or Treaſurers, the Sum of Twenty Shillings <hi>per</hi> Head, over and above the ſaid Sums.</p>
               <p>AND whereas ſeveral of their Majeſties Subjects un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the qualifications aforeſaid, Reſiding at <hi>New Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land, New York, Carolina,</hi> or other Parts of <hi>America,</hi> the <hi>Windward</hi> Iſlands, and <hi>Providence,</hi> may upon the En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>couragement of this Act be willing to Tranſport them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves to this Iſland:</p>
               <p>BE it therefore Enacted, that all Maſters or Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manders, of any Veſſel or Veſſels, that ſhall Import any ſuch Perſons before mentioned, ſhall for every Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon ſo brought from <hi>New England,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Perſons from other Plan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tations.</note> 
                  <hi>New York, Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rolina,</hi> or other parts of <hi>America,</hi> receive the Sum of Three Pounds Ten Shillings; and for every Perſon brought from <hi>Providence</hi> and the <hi>Windward</hi> Iſlands, the Sum of Forty Shillings current Mony of this Iſland, without Fraud or Delay; and that the Maſter, or Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mander of every Veſſel, who ſhall Import any Perſons by Encouragement of this Act from <hi>New England, New York, Carolina,</hi> or other parts of <hi>America,</hi> the <hi>Windward</hi> Iſlands and <hi>Providence,</hi> ſhall receive the Sum of Ten Shillings <hi>per</hi> Head, to, and for his Own proper Uſe and Benefit, over and above the Sums aforeſaid, for the Paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſage of each Perſon.</p>
               <p>AND be it likewiſe Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That all and every Maſter or Maſters of any Veſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſel or Veſſels, who ſhall Import any Paſſenger upon the Credit of this Act, ſhall within Forty Eight Hours after his, or their Arrival, Deliver to the Secretary of this Iſland, or his Lawful Deputy upon Oath, which ſaid
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:109567:26"/>Oath the Secretary is hereby Impowered to Adminiſter, a fair written Liſt of all ſuch Perſons as he,<note place="margin">A Liſt to be given.</note> or they ſhall have brought to this Iſland: in which Liſt ſhall be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained the Names, Surnames, Age, Trade, and Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try of all, and every the ſaid Perſon and Perſons, as alſo if Single or Married, which ſaid Liſt the Secretary, or his Lawful Deputy, is forthwith to enter in a Book to be kept for that purpoſe, and then to Tranſmit the ſame, with his Certificate Indorſed, to the Treaſurer or Treaſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rers, receiving for the ſame the Sum of Two Shillings and Sixpence from the ſaid Treaſurer or Treaſurers, who are hereby Ordered and Required upon receipt thereof to pay the ſaid Maſter or Maſters, the ſeveral Sums for the reſpective Paſſages, as is above Directed.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, That for the well, and truly Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſing, Collecting, Levying, and paying in all, and e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very the Sum and Sums of Mony ariſing by virtue of this Act, all Merchants, and others Importing any of the Wines and Liquors aforeſaid, do,<note place="margin">Entry to be made, and Bond given:</note> and ſhall make Entry in the Office of the Receiver-General for the time being, after the ſame manner and methods as is preſcribed in an Act of this Country, Entitled, <hi>An Act for Raiſing a Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Revenue, for the Support of the Government of this His Majeſty's Iſland:</hi> all which ſaid Entries of this Additional Duty, and Impoſt on <hi>Negroes,</hi> by virtue of this Act laid on, ſhall be kept in a Book apart, and diſtinct from the other Branches of Their Majeſties Revenue; and all Bonds for their Additional Impoſt ſhall be taken in Their Majeſties Names, and the Mony ariſing thereon, as it ſhall become Due, ſhall be paid into the Hands of the Receiver-General, and be by him Paid over to the Treaſurer or Treaſurers, by virtue of this Act appointed, within Twenty Days after the Receipt thereof: For the taking the ſaid Bonds, and making the ſaid Entries, Receiving and Paying the ſaid Monies, the Receiver-General, or his Lawful Deputy, ſhall retain to him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:109567:27"/>Two and a Half <hi>per Cent.</hi> and no more, any Law, Cuſtom, or Uſage to the Contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, That for all ſuch quantities of any of the Liquors beforementioned, as the Cuſtoms Due for the ſame,<note place="margin">Cuſtom un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der <hi>5 l.</hi>
                  </note> ſhall amount to but Five Pounds or un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, no Bonds ſhall be taken, or Credit given after the Entry thereof; but the Cuſtoms for the ſame ſhall be im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mediately Paid to the Receiver-General, or his lawful Deputy, and by him Paid over into the Hands of the Treaſurer or Treaſurers, as is before Directed.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That all <hi>Negroes</hi> to be Exported, ſhall be Entred in the Receiver-Generals Office,<note place="margin">Negro's Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported.</note> and immediately Bond given by the Owner or Exporter, to Their Majeſties, for the payment of the Mony into the Hands of the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiver-General, or his lawful Deputy, within one Month after the Entry ſo made as aforeſaid, and whoſoever ſhall preſume after the ſaid Seventeenth Day of <hi>November,</hi> in this preſent Year, One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Three, to Export any Slave or Slaves, and not make ſuch Entry, and give Bond, and Pay as before in this Act is Directed, ſhall Forfeit for every ſuch Slave ſo Exported, the Sum of Fifty Pounds.</p>
               <p>AND foraſmuch as the preſent Neceſſity many require the Advancement of Mony upon the Credit of this Act,<note place="margin">Money ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vanced.</note> Be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, that it ſhall, and may be lawful for any Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or Perſons whatſoever, to Advance and Lend unto Their Majeſties upon the Credit of this Act any Sum, or Sums of Mony, not exceeding One Thouſand Pounds in the whole, and to have, and receive for the Loan of the ſaid Mony ſo Lent and Advanced, after the rate of Twelve Pounds Ten Shillings <hi>per Cent. per Annum.</hi>
               </p>
               <pb n="49" facs="tcp:109567:27"/>
               <p>AND to the End that the ſaid Mony that ſhall be Lent unto Their Majeſties upon the Credit hereof, may be well and ſufficiently ſecured, Be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, that all, and every Perſon and Perſons, who ſhall Advance and Lend unto Their Majeſties any Sum or Sums of Mony, not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding One Thouſand Pounds in the whole, as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, upon the Credit of this Act, and actually Pay the ſame into the Hands of the Treaſurer, or Treaſurers for the time being, ſhall be by the Treaſurer or Treaſurers,<note place="margin">How to be repaid.</note> upon the firſt Payment of Monies that ſhall be Paid into his, or their Hands by virtue of this Act, after Deducti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and Payment of the ſaid Sum of One Thouſand Seven Hundred Seventy Four Pounds Sixteen Shillings to Their Majeſties as aforeſaid, be forthwith Paid unto the Perſon or Perſons ſo lending the ſaid Sums, their Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors, Adminiſtrators, or Aſſigns ſucceſſively, as they ſhall become Due, with the Intereſt aforeſaid, for diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge of the Mony ſo Lent and Advanced, without Fee or Change.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted, That the Honourable <hi>Samuel Bernard,</hi> and <hi>Nicholas Law,</hi> Eſquires, and <hi>James Bradſhaw, William Hutchinſon, Thomas Clarke, Modyford Freeman,</hi> and <hi>James Baniſter,</hi> Eſquires, be, and are here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by Required and Impowered to nominate and appoint from time to time,<note place="margin">Managers appointed.</note> ſuch fit Perſon or Perſons in <hi>England, Scotland, Ireland, New England, New York,</hi> or any other Parts of <hi>America,</hi> or elſewhere, as they, or the Major part of them, ſhall think fit, to make known the pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port of this Act as aforeſaid, for the giving Notice to ſuch Perſons as are willing to Tranſport themſelves hither up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the Encouragement thereof.</p>
               <p>AND in Caſe of the Death, Abſence, or Refuſal of any of the Perſons aforementioned, That then it ſhall, and may be lawful for the Perſons Remaining, or Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viving, or the Major part of them, to chooſe to them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:109567:28"/>ſuch other Perſon or Perſons, as they ſhall think fit, to act in the room or ſtead of him, or them that ſhall Remove,<note place="margin">In caſe of Death <hi>&amp;</hi> how to be ſupplied.</note> Deceaſe, or Refuſe, and that the Perſon or Perſons ſo Choſen ſhall be, and are Impowered to act as fully, and freely, to all Intents and Purpoſes, as if he, or they had been mentioned and appointed by Name in this Act: and the Perſons therein nominated and appointed as aforeſaid, ſhall from time to time con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue to act, and do all, and every ſuch thing and things as by this Act they are Impowered and Required to perform.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, That the Commiſſioners appointed by virtue of this Act, or the Major part of them, from time to time are hereby Required and Impowered as often as they ſhall think convenient, to chooſe one, or more of themſelves to Receive,<note place="margin">Receivers how choſen.</note> and Pay the Mony a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſing by virtue of this Act, for the Uſes and Purpoſes herein mentioned; of the Receipt of all which the Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurer or Treaſurers for the time being, ſhall keep an ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>act and diſtinct Accompt, as alſo of all Payments made for the Uſes and Purpoſes by this Act required, and ren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der a Juſt and True Accompt thereof, when thereunto demanded, unto the reſt of the Perſons in this Act no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minated and appointed, or the Major part of them, or unto the Aſſembly of this Iſland when Sitting and Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſembled; and if the ſaid Treaſurer or Treaſurers for the Time being, after the Receipt of any of the ſaid Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies, ſhall divert or miſapply the ſame, or any part there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of by any pretence whatſoever, otherwiſe than before in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended and directed, contrary to the true intent and mean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of this Act; the Perſon or Perſons ſo Offending ſhall Forfeit to Their Majeſties,<note place="margin">Forfeiture for Miſap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plication.</note> for, and towards the Support, of the Government of this Iſland, and the contingent Charges thereof, double the Sum ſo diverted and miſap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plied; and the ſaid Treaſurer or Treaſurers for the time being ſhall be allowed Two and a Half <hi>per Cent.</hi> for de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fraying
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:109567:28"/>his, or their Charges, in, or about the diſcharge of the Truſt hereby in him, or them repoſed.</p>
               <p>AND whereas after the Expiration of this Act, ſome of the Monies ariſing by virtue hereof, may re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>main in the Hands of the Treaſurer or Treaſurers for the time being, Be it therefore Enacted by the Authority a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, that ſuch Sum or Sums of Mony, if any be,<note place="margin">Surplus of Money.</note> in the Hands of the ſaid Treaſurer or Treaſurers, ſhall, not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding the Expiration of this Act, be there, and ſtill in his or their Hands remain, and be Employed to the Uſes and Intents in this Act appointed.</p>
               <p>BE it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the Secretary of this Iſland ſhall from time to time, upon demand,<note place="margin">Copies of this Act to be de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liver'd.</note> give Copy or Copies of this Act to any Perſon without delay or excuſe, for every of which he ſhall re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive the Fee or Sum of Ten Shillings, and in Caſe he ſhall delay, or refuſe to give ſuch Copy or Copies as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, to any Perſon or Perſons demanding the ſame, he ſhall for every Copy ſo demanded, and not given, Forfeit the Sum of Forty Shillings, to be recovered be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore any Juſtice of the Peace.</p>
               <p>BE it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That if the Receiver-General, or his lawful Deputy, ſhall refuſe to make Entry, and do, and perform all, and every ſuch thing or things as by this Act, or any Branch thereof is enjoyned him;<note place="margin">Forfeiture of the Recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver-General on Refuſal of Entry.</note> he ſhall Forfeit for every ſuch Offence the Sum of Five Hundred Pounds Currant Mony of this Iſland, and all other Perſon or Perſons Offending contrary to the true Intent and Mean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of this Act, ſhall Forfeit for every ſuch Offence, wherein Penalties are not already laid, the Sum of One Hundred Pounds: the Moiety of all the Forfeitures with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in this Act mentioned, ſhall be to Their Majeſties, their Heirs and Succeſſors, for, and towards the Support of the Government of this Iſland, and the contingent Charges thereof, and the other Moiety to the Informer, or
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:109567:29"/>he that ſhall Sue for the ſame, to be Recovered by Action of Debt, Bill, Plaint or Information in any Court of Record, within this Iſland, where no Eſſoin, Protection, Wager of Law, or <hi>Nonvult ulterius proſequi</hi> ſhall be al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed, any Law, Cuſtom, or Uſage to the contrary in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <head>
                  <hi>An ACT</hi> For Raiſing Money to Solicit in <hi>England,</hi> the Affairs of this Their Majeſties Iſland.</head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">Preamble.</note>WHEREAS Their Majeſties Iſland of <hi>Jamaica,</hi> hath divers times lain under great Diſadvantages, through the Miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>repreſentation of the Proceedings and Intereſts thereof, which hath chiefly happened for want of ſome fit Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons fully Inſtructed to appear in <hi>England,</hi> and there truly Repreſent and Solicit the ſame: And inaſmuch as Their Majeſties have been Graciouſly pleaſed to per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit the raiſing Three Hundred Pounds Sterling, <hi>per Annum,</hi> to be Employed to the Uſe, and to prevent the Diſadvan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage above expreſſed, and that by a modeſt Calcula<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the ſaid Summ, it appears that Four Hundred and Fifty Pounds, currant Money of this Iſland of <hi>Jamaica,</hi> the Charges of Collecting, and Receivers Charges for the Receipt, and the Exchange in remitting the ſame be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing included, will not amount or produce more than the ſaid Summ of Three Hundred Pounds Sterling Money of <hi>England:</hi>
               </p>
               <pb n="53" facs="tcp:109567:29"/>
               <p>THE Aſſembly do therefore moſt humbly beſeech Your moſt Excellent Majeſties, That it may be Enacted, and be it Enacted, by the Lieutenant-Governour, Council and Aſſembly; and it is hereby Enacted by the Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity of the ſame,<note place="margin">Four Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred and Fif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty Pounds to be raiſed.</note> That the ſaid Summ of Four Hundred and Fifty Pounds, currant Money of this Iſland, for the making Good the ſaid Summ of Three Hundred Pounds Sterling Money of <hi>England,</hi> and defraying the Charges of collecting, receiving, and remitting the ſame, be raiſed, levied, and paid within Three Months after the Tenth Day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Three, and ſo the ſaid Summ to be raiſed, levied, and paid yearly, and every Year, for and during the full Time and Term of Eleven Years,<note place="margin">Time limited.</note> to and for the Uſes above-mentioned, to be paid by the Inhabitants of the ſeveral Pariſhes within this Iſland, into the Hands of ſuch Perſon or Perſons who ſhall from time to time be appointed by the Commiſſioners hereafter named, or the <hi>major</hi> Part of them, to be Receiver or Receivers of the ſame, according to the ſeveral Rates and Propor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions hereafter following: That is to ſay,<note place="margin">Rates of the ſeveral Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhes.</note> for the Pariſh and Town of <hi>Port-Royal,</hi> Forty Nine, Pounds Ten Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings and Ten Pence; for the Pariſh of St. <hi>Andrews,</hi> Fifty Two Pounds Seventeen Shillings and Five Pence; for the Pariſh of St. <hi>Katherines,</hi> Fifty Six Pounds Sixteen Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings and Three Pence; for the Pariſh of Sr. <hi>Dorothy,</hi> Twenty Five Pounds Three Shillings and One Peny; for the Pariſh of <hi>Vere,</hi> Forty Seven Pounds One Shilling and Eight Pence; for the Pariſh of <hi>Clarendon,</hi> Forty Two Pounds One Shilling and Eight Pence; for the Pariſh of Sr. <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> Fifty One Pound Six Shillings and Eight Pence; for the Pariſh of St. <hi>Thomas,</hi> to <hi>Windward,</hi> Twenty Seven Pounds Ten Shillings; for the Pariſh of Sr. <hi>Davids,</hi> Sixteen Pounds and Eleven Pence; for the Pariſh of Sr. <hi>Thomas</hi> in the Vale, Twenty One Pound Nine Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings; for the Pariſh of Sr. <hi>Johns,</hi> Fifteen Pounds Eight Shillings and Three Pence; for the Pariſh of St. <hi>George</hi>'s, Three Pounds Thirteen Shillings and-Six Pence; for the
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:109567:30"/>Pariſh of St. <hi>Mary</hi>'s, Eleven Pounds Five Shillings and Seven Pence; for the Pariſh of St. <hi>Ann</hi>'s, Seven Pounds Thirteen Shillings and Six Pence; for the Pariſh of St. <hi>James,</hi> Two Pounds Sixteen Shillings and Eight Pence; for the Town and Pariſh of <hi>Kingſton,</hi> Nineteen Pounds and Five Shillings.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, That the Juſtices and Veſtry-men for the time being, in their reſpective Pariſhes aforeſaid; and where no Veſtry is, the Juſtices by themſelves with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the Limits of their ſeveral Commiſſions, are hereby Impowered and Required at the uſual times of Aſſeſſing their Pariſh-Tax,<note place="margin">Aſſeſſors.</note> to Aſſeſs, Tax and Levy, for the ſaid Term of Eleven Years, the ſeveral Summs over and above the uſual Taxes aſſeſſed and raiſed on the ſeveral Pariſhes by Virtue of an Act of this Iſland, Entitled, <hi>An Act for the Maintenance of Miniſters and the Poor, and Erecting and Repairing of Churches.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>AND whereas in ſome Pariſhes there may not be Money in the Church-Wardens Hands for the paying of the Tax above aſſeſſed for this preſent Year, it is there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That then the Church-Wardens of ſuch Pariſh or Pariſhes,<note place="margin">Money to be advanc'd.</note> and where no Church-Wardens are, the Juſtices themſelves within the Limits of their Commiſſions, do Pay the ſaid Summ or Summs as is above Aſſeſſed for this preſent Year in ſuch manner as is hereafter Directed, under the Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty of Ten Pounds each, for refuſing to Pay the ſame.</p>
               <p>AND for the Reimburſing the ſaid Church-Wardens or Juſtices, who do by Virtue of this Act, Advance and Pay the ſaid Pariſh-Tax for this preſent Year, it ſhall and may be Lawful for the ſaid Juſtices and Ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtry, and where no Veſtry is, the Juſtices themſelves, within the Limits of their reſpective Commiſſions, are hereby Required and Impowered, That at the next uſual
<pb n="55" facs="tcp:109567:30"/>time of Aſſeſſing their Pariſh-Tax, that they Aſſeſs ſuch Summ or Summs of Money as ſhall have been Lent and Advanced by the Church-Wardens or Juſtices, as is above Required; which Money ſo Aſſeſſed and Levied, ſhall be by the Church-Wardens, and where no Church-Wardens are,<note place="margin">How to be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>imburſed.</note> by the Juſtices within the Limits of their reſpective Commiſſions, paid unto the Hands of the Perſons ſo Lending the Money for this preſent Year, with Lawful Intereſt for the ſame; which ſaid Summ, with the ſaid Intereſt, ſhall be Paid by the Church-Wardens or Juſtices, or where no Church-Wardens are, by the Juſtices within the Limits of their reſpective Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſions, on Demand, under Penalty of double the Summ ſo Lent, and Demanded as aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That the ſeveral Summs yearly to be Collected as aforeſaid, ſhall for this preſent Year, and the Years en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuing, during the time mentioned in this Act, be Paid by the Church-Wardens or Juſtices of each reſpective Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh, within Twenty One Days after their Receipt there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of,<note place="margin">Time of Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</note> into the Hands of the Receiver, or Receivers, Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>powered to Receive the ſame; and if any of the Juſtices, Church-Wardens, Veſtry-men, or Conſtables ſhall ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>glect his or their Duty in Aſſeſſing, Levying, or Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the ſaid Summs which are above required to be Aſſeſſed, Levied and Paid, he or they ſo neglecting or failing of his or their Duty therein, ſhall reſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctively Forfeit for every ſuch Offence, the Summ of Fifty Pounds.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the ſaid Money ſo Raiſed and Paid as aforeſaid, into the Hands of the ſaid Receiver or Receivers for the time being, ſhall by them be yearly remitted on the Countries Riſque, in ſuch manner as they ſhall think fit, into the Hands of <hi>Gilbert Heathcote,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">To whom re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted.</note> 
                  <hi>Bartholomew Gracedieu,</hi> and <hi>John Tutt,</hi> of <hi>London</hi> Merchants, or any One of them, or ſuch other Perſon or Perſons as ſhall
<pb n="56" facs="tcp:109567:31"/>from time to time be appointed to Solicit in <hi>England,</hi> the Publick Affairs of this Iſland as Occaſion ſhall require, and as to them ſhall ſeem moſt to the Intereſt and Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantage thereof.</p>
               <p>AND in Caſe of the Death, Abſence, or Refuſal of any of the Solicitors before-mentioned, or the Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners hereafter mentioned in this Act, that then the Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons remaining, or ſurviving, or the <hi>major</hi> Part of them, do chuſe to themſelves ſuch other Perſon or Perſons as they ſhall think fit, in the room or ſtead of him or them that ſhall Remove, Deceaſe, or Refuſe; and that the Perſon or Perſons ſo choſen, ſhall here and in <hi>England,</hi> each for themſelves, be Impowered to Act as fully to all Intents and Purpoſes in each Place, as if he or they had been mentioned and appointed by Name in this Act.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That the Honourable <hi>Samuel Bernard,</hi> and <hi>Nicholas Law</hi> Eſquires, and <hi>James Bradſhaw, William Hutchinſon, Thomas Clarke, James Baniſter,</hi> and <hi>Modyford Freeman</hi> Eſquires,<note place="margin">Commiſſioners and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceivers.</note> ſhall be, and are hereby Impowered and Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed to be Commiſſioners; and they, or the <hi>major</hi> Part of them, from time to time, to appoint one or more of themſelves to be Receiver or Receivers of the Money by this Act to be raiſed.</p>
               <p>AND whereas at this preſent Seſſions there are Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral Inſtructions drawn up by the Council and Aſſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly, for Direction to the Solicitors in <hi>England,</hi> the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners named in this Act,<note place="margin">Inſtructions to be ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerved.</note> are at no time to Order any thing contrary to any Particulars contained therein, but fully to obſerve and be directed thereby, any thing in this Act ſeeming to the contrary notwithſtanding; which ſaid Inſtructions are to be Signed by the Clerk of the Council, and the Speaker of the Aſſembly, and be En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tred in the Minutes of both Houſes.</p>
               <pb n="57" facs="tcp:109567:31"/>
               <p>PROVIDED nevertheleſs, That the Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners before-mentioned,<note place="margin">Farther In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtructions.</note> may from time to time upon any ſudden or emergent Occaſions, give to the Solicitors in <hi>England</hi> ſuch further Inſtructions as they ſhall think fit for the Publick Service of this Iſland.</p>
               <p>AND in caſe it ſhall be thought fit at any time here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after to turn out or alter any of the Solicitors in <hi>England,</hi> that then the ſaid Commiſſioners, or <hi>major</hi> Part of them, are hereby impowered from time to time to turn out,<note place="margin">Solicitors chang'd.</note> or alter as aforeſaid, all or any of the Solicitors in this Act mentioned.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted, That the Perſon or Perſons ſo named to be Receiver or Receivers ſhall receive and pay all ſuch Summ or Summs of Money as ſhall come to his or their Hands, ariſing by Virtue of this Act: Of all which the Receiver or Receivers for the time being, ſhall keep an Exact and Diſtinct Account of all Payments, and Remittances made for the Uſes and Purpoſes by this Act required,<note place="margin">Account to be given:</note> and render a Juſt and True Account thereof when demanded, unto the reſt of the Commiſſioners in this Act nominated, or the <hi>major</hi> Part of them, when thereunto required, or to the Aſſembly of this Iſland, when ſitting and aſſembled, of all the Summ and Summs of Money by him or them received, by Virtue of this Act, and how laid out or remitted; and if the ſaid Receiver or Receivers for the time being, after the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceipt of any of the ſaid Money, ſhall divert or miſap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ply the ſame, or any Part thereof, by any Pretence what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever, otherwiſe than before intended and directed, contrary to the true Intent and Meaning of this Act, the Perſon or Perſons ſo Offending, ſhall Forfeit to Their Majeſties, for and towards the Support of the Government of this Iſland, and the contingent Charges thereof, double the Summ ſo diverted or miſapplied; and the ſaid Receiver or Receivers for the time being, ſhall be allowed all his or their reaſonable Expences,
<pb n="58" facs="tcp:109567:32"/>in or about the Diſcharge of the Truſt hereby repoſed in him or them,<note place="margin">Expences al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed.</note> Commiſſion or pretence of Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion hereby excepted; and in caſe the Receiver or Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceivers for the time being, ſhall Neglect or Refuſe to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit the aforeſaid Summ or Summs of Money when re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived yearly, and every Year during the continuance of the Act, to the Solicitors in <hi>England,</hi> ſhall Forfeit for every ſuch Offence, the Summ of Five Hundred Pounds.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, That one Half of the Forfeiture con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained in this Act,<note place="margin">Forfeitures applied.</note> and not herein applied, ſhall be to our Sovereign Lord and Lady the King and Queen, Their Heirs and Succeſſors, for and towards the Support of the Government of this Iſland, and the contingent Charges thereof, the other Half to him or them that ſhall Sue for the ſame, which ſaid Forfeitures ſhall be recovered by Action of Debt, Bill, Plaint, or Information, in any of Their Majeſties Courts of Record within this Iſland, wherein no Eſſoyn, Injunction, Protection, Wager of Law, or <hi>Nonvult ulterius proſequi</hi> ſhall be allowed; any Law, Cuſtom, or Uſage to the contrary notwithſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <pb n="59" facs="tcp:109567:32"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>An ACT</hi> For Guarding the Sea-Coaſts.</head>
               <p>VVHEREAS ſince this preſent War with the <hi>French</hi> King, Their Majeſties Subjects,<note place="margin">Preamble.</note> Inhabiting the Sea-Coaſts of this Iſland, have been, and ſtill are frequently alarmed, and for their own Safety and Security of the Iſland in general, are obliged to keep conſtant Guards, and Look-outs, which by rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon of the Scarcity of White Men, is found to fall very ſeverely upon the poorer ſort of People, to their great Diſencouragement, and even Chaſing them away from their Habitations and Settlements:</p>
               <p>WE therefore Your Majeſties moſt Dutiful and Loyal Subjects, the Aſſembly of this Your Majeſties Iſland; do humbly beſeech Your Majeſties, That it may be Enacted, and be it Enacted by Their Majeſties Lieutenant-Governour, Council and Aſſembly, and it is here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by Enacted and Ordained by the Authority of the ſame, That the Juſtices and Veſtry, or the <hi>major</hi> Part of them, or the Juſtices within the Commiſſions of the Peace, where they have no Veſtries, in all and every the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhes of this Iſland adjacent to the Sea, and expoſed to the immediate Incurſions of an Enemy, ſhall, and are hereby Impowered, and Required to raiſe,<note place="margin">Money how to be raiſed.</note> or cauſe to be levied, ſuch Summ and Summs of Money, as to them by the Advice of the Chief Military Officer of that Place ſhall ſeem neceſſary for the Maintaining and Keeping Night-Watches, Guards, or Look-outs, in ſuch Place and Places as to them ſhall ſeem moſt proper and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venient for the Securing of the Inhabitants, and Diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vering and Preventing the Approach of the Enemy; and all and every ſuch Summ or Summs of Money as ſhall be thought needful as aforeſaid, to pay the ſaid
<pb n="60" facs="tcp:109567:33"/>Guards, Night-Watches, or Look-outs, ſhall be by them the ſaid Juſtices and Veſtry, and in caſe of no Veſtry, by the Juſtices within the Commiſſion of the Peace for the ſaid Pariſh, laid or aſſeſſed, levied or taxed upon the ſeveral Inhabitants, with and in ſuch method, manner, time and form, as the Pariſh-Taxes in their ſeveral and reſpective Pariſhes are, or ought to be raiſed, levied and taxed; and the ſaid Summ or Summs of Money ſo raiſed or levied, ſhall be Collected with the Pariſh-Tax, that is, and ſhall be yearly raiſed by an Act of this Iſland, En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>titled, <hi>An Act for the Maintenance of Miniſters and the Poor, and Erecting and Repairing of Churches,</hi> by the Conſtable or Conſtables of the ſeveral Pariſhes or Precincts, and by them forthwith paid into the Hands of the Church-Warden or Church-Wardens for the time being, who ſhall, and are hereby required to Iſſue forth and Pay the ſame to ſuch Perſon or Perſons employed in Guarding, Watching, or on Look-outs as aforeſaid, by Warrant from the Chief Officer of that Place: And that all and every Perſon or Perſons ſo employed and entruſted in Guarding, Watch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing,<note place="margin">Failure in Duty.</note> and for Look-outs that ſhall fail or neglect his or their Duty, according to the Charge and Truſt given them, ſhall be liable to ſuch Pains and Puniſhments, as if the Articles of War were now at ſuch time in Force in this Iſland to be inflicted on them for ſuch their Neglect.</p>
               <p>AND that for this preſent Year, the ſaid Juſtices with in their ſaid ſeveral Pariſhes, or within the Commiſſion of the Peace for the ſame, ſhall within Ten Days after the Fifteenth Day of <hi>September,</hi> One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Three, call and warn the Veſtry-men to appear at a certain Day, Time and Place, as to them ſhall ſeem convenient,<note place="margin">Juſtices, &amp;c. empower'd.</note> who are hereby, then and there, Impowered to make, and lay ſuch Tax as to them, by the Advice of the Military Officer of that Place, ſhall be thought need<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful for the Maintaining and Keeping ſuch Guards, Watches and Look-outs, as ſhall be thought requiſite for the Security of the Inhabitants, and preventing Incurſions of the Enemy, and that in ſuch Pariſhes where there is no
<pb n="61" facs="tcp:109567:33"/>Veſtry, the Juſtices within the Commiſſion of the Peace, ſhall lay ſuch Tax as ſhall be thought requiſite; and cauſe the ſame to be levied and imployed as aforeſaid; and for the Receiving and Collecting of the ſaid Tax, the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable ſhall retain to himſelf Twelve Pence in the Pound for the Levying and Collecting the ſame, any Law, Cuſtom, or Uſage to the contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">Pariſh of <hi>Vere</hi> con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sidered.</note>AND whereas ſeveral of the Inhabitants of the Pariſh of <hi>Vere,</hi> have for the general Good, and particularly for the Safeguard of their Pariſh, ſubſcribed to a Paper in the whole Summ of their Pariſh Tax, they were aſſeſ'd at the laſt Year, and paid the ſame by way of Loan unto Their Majeſties, for keeping ſuch Guards, and Night-Watches as aforeſaid, until they could be otherwiſe pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided for by an Act of the Aſſembly; nevertheleſs, many of the Inhabitants of the ſaid Pariſh have neglected and refuſed to Pay the ſame;</p>
               <p>BE it therefore Enacted and Ordained by the Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity aforeſaid, That the Juſtices and Veſtry of they ſaid Pariſh are hereby Required and Impowered at their firſt Meeting, in Order to the Maintaining Guards, and Look<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>outs, as aforeſaid, to Tax, Raiſe, and cauſe to be Levied ſuch Summ or Summs of Money as ſhall be made appear to them neceſſary to reimburſe ſuch Perſons as have paid and expended their Money for the Watches and Safeguard of the ſaid Pariſh, according to the Subſcriptions as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, over and above what it ſhall be thought neceſſary by the Juſtices and Veſtry, with the Advice of the Chief Military Officer, to Raiſe and Aſſeſs on the ſeveral Inha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitants for Maintaining their Guards and Look-outs as aforeſaid; which ſaid Summ and Summs of Money ſo Levied as aforeſaid, ſhall be by the Church-Wardens forthwith paid unto ſuch Perſon or Perſons that have de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſited and disburs'd their Money for Guarding and Look-outs according to the Subſcriptions aforeſaid.</p>
               <pb n="62" facs="tcp:109567:34"/>
               <p>AND whereas in ſome Pariſhes by reaſon of their long Tracts of Land on the Sea Coaſts, it will prove im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſſible to keep ſufficient Look-outs to give Warning of the Enemies approach, without the help of Beacons: Be it therefore Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the Juſtices and Veſtry,<note place="margin">Beacons to be erected.</note> or the Juſtices within the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion of the Peace where there is no Veſtry, ſhall Aſſeſs and Levy at the uſual time and times in manner afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, ſuch Summ and Summs of Money to erect and keep ſuch and ſo many Beacons, and in ſuch convenient Place and Places, as a Regimental Court-Martial ſhall think fit.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That all and every Juſtice or Juſtices of the Peace, Church-Warden or Church-Wardens that ſhall neglect or fail in the Execution of his or their Duty as aforeſaid, ſhall Forfeit the Summ of Five Pounds, for ſuch his Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>glect or Default,<note place="margin">Forfeiture upon Default.</note> and for every Veſtry-man or Conſtable, the Summ of Forty Shillings, to be recovered by Action of Debt, if not above Forty Shillings, before any Juſtice of the Peace, and if above-Forty Shillings, in any Court of Record within this Iſland, wherein no Eſſoin, Prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction, or Wager of Law ſhall be allowed, the one Half of which Forfeiture as aforeſaid, ſhall be for and towards the maintaining Guards and Look-outs, within the Pariſh where the Fault was committed, and the other Half to the Informer, or him that ſhall Sue for the ſame; any Law, Cuſtom, or Uſage to the contrary notwithſtanding. Provided always, that this Act, and all and every thing and things therein contained, ſhall be and continue in Force during the War with <hi>France,</hi> and no longer.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <pb n="63" facs="tcp:109567:34"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>An ACT</hi> For Raiſing Money as a farther Aid to Their MAJESTIES, for and towards the Defence of this Their Iſland of <hi>Ja<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maica.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>VVHEREAS the Proviſion heretofore made for the Security and Defence of this Their Majeſties Iſland,<note place="margin">Preamble.</note> hath been found Inſuffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient, and the <hi>French</hi> continue ſtill to make daily Depre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dations and Deſcents upon the Parts adjacent to the Sea, and take off, and carry away great Numbers of Slaves, and other Goods of conſiderable Value, to the Ruin of ſeveral of Their Majeſties good Subjects, and Impo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veriſhing the whole Iſland; for prevention of which, and diſabling the Enemy, a greater Force is abſolutely neceſſary;</p>
               <p>WE therefore Your Majeſties moſt Dutiful and Loyal Subjects, the Aſſembly of this Their Iſland of <hi>Jamaica,</hi> having taken into our ſerious Conſideration, how inju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rious the Ruin and Deſtruction of this their Plantation, may in time prove to Their Imperial Crown, and being ready and willing to provide further Aid for Their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties Iſland aforeſaid, and Reſiſtance of Their Enemy; have unanimouſly given and granted, and do hereby give and grant unto Their Majeſties, for and towards the continuance of the Two Sloops of War, already in Their Majeſties Service, with an Addition of Twenty Men more to each Sloop, and alſo towards the Buying, or Hiring, Providing, Victualling, or Manning of Two
<pb n="64" facs="tcp:109567:35"/>more Sloops of War, each conſiſting of Sixty effective Officers, Seamen, and Soldiers incluſively, all which ſaid Four Sloops of War to be employed for Six Months to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards the Defence of this Iſland,<note place="margin">Force to be augmented.</note> and guarding the Sea-Coaſts thereof, and in Cruiſing with Their Majeſties Fri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gats, or ſuch other Veſſel or Veſſels as ſhall be Impreſſed into their Service about the ſame, and Attacking, and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroying the Enemy, and alſo for continuing of Two Parties for the like time of Six Months, conſiſting each of Two Officers, and Ten Soldiers, for Reducing of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bellious <hi>Negroes,</hi> the full entire Sum of Seven Thouſand Five Hundred Pound, currant Mony of this Iſland; and alſo the Sum of One Thouſand Nine Hundred Seventy Three Pound Fourteen Shillings and Four Pence, for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merly Raiſed, and not yet applyed, by an Act made this laſt Seſſion of this preſent Aſſembly, Entitled, <hi>An Act for Raiſing Money, for, and towards the Defence of this Iſland:</hi> The whole amounting to Nine Thouſand Four Hundred Seventy Three Pound Fourteen Shillings and Four Pence, and do moſt humbly beſeech Their Majeſties to accept the ſame, and that it may be Enacted:</p>
               <p>AND be it therefore Enacted by Their Majeſties Lieutenant-Governour, Council, and Aſſembly of this Iſland, and it is hereby Enacted and Ordained by the Authority of the ſame,<note place="margin">Sum to be raiſed.</note> that the ſaid Sum of Seven Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Five Hundred Pound currant Money of this Iſland, be Aſſeſſed, Taxed, and laid on by the ſeveral and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpective Pariſhes, or Precincts, or within the Commiſſion of the Peace for the ſame, within this Iſland where they have any lawful Veſtries, and where they have no law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Veſtries by the Juſtices of that Pariſh or Precinct, or within the Commiſſion of the Peace for the ſame, or major part of the Veſtry, in all, and every the ſaid Pariſh or Pariſhes in this Iſland, on all, and every Perſon within their ſeveral and reſpective Pariſh or Precinct, by an equal and juſt Tax, to be paid within Three Months after the Tenth Day of <hi>November,</hi> which ſhall be in the Year of our Lord One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety
<pb n="65" facs="tcp:109567:35"/>Three, by the reſpective Pariſhes of this Their Majeſties Iſland of <hi>Jamaica,</hi> into the Hands of the Receiver or Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceivers hereafter named, according to the ſeveral Rates, and Proportions hereafter mentioned, in ſuch ſort and manner as by this preſent Act ſhall be limited and ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, and in no other way or manner whatſoever, that is to ſay: for every <hi>Negroe, Mulatto,</hi> or <hi>Indian</hi> Slave with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in this Iſland, of what Age, Condition, or Quality ſoe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver, or to whom ſoever belonging, ſhall be paid for by their Maſters, Proprietors, Owners, Poſſeſſors, Guardi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans, or Perſons Intruſted in the ſeveral Plantations, Pens, Crawles or Settlements within this Iſland, the Sum of Two Shillings for each <hi>Negro, Indian,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Slaves and Cattel tax'd.</note> or <hi>Mulatto</hi> Slave as aforeſaid, and alſo for all Horſes, Mares, Colts, Mules, Aſſes, and Neat Cattle, the Sum of Nine Pence for each Beaſt, and for all Sheep, Lambs, Goats, and Kids, the Sum of Two Shillings Six Pence <hi>per</hi> Score, and ſo in proportion for a greater or leſſer Quantity.</p>
               <p>AND for the Pariſh of <hi>Port-Royal,</hi> it is hereby En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, That the Juſtices and Veſtry ſhall Lay, Aſſeſs, Levy, and cauſe to be Levyed Sixteen Pence in the Pound on all Rents,<note place="margin">Rents and Trades.</note> to be paid by all Tenants, and allowed by their Land<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lords, and Proprietors, and on all Leaſes, to be paid by the Leſſee, and allowed by the Leſſor out of their Rents, and alſo on the ſeveral Inhabitants for their ſeveral Trades, Occupations, and Callings as much, and one third more in proportion, than they were Rated, Aſſeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed, and Taxed by the Juſtices and Veſtry, in the Pariſh-Roll, on <hi>Port-Royal</hi> aforeſaid, for this preſent Year One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Three, and alſo on all Perſons Reſiding at the Towns of St. <hi>Jago de la Vega,</hi> Six<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teen Pence in the Pound on all Rents to be Paid by all Tenants, and allowed by their Landlords and Proprie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors, and on all Leaſes to be Paid by the Leſſee, and al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed by the Leſſor, out of all their Rents, and alſo ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Rate, Tax, and Sum Aſſeſſed by the Juſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces and Veſtry of St. <hi>Katharines</hi> for this preſent Year One
<pb n="66" facs="tcp:109567:36"/>Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Three, and for the Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons Reſiding in the Town and Pariſh of <hi>Kingſton,</hi> Six<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teen Pence in the Pound on all Rents, to be Paid by all Tenants, and allowed by their Landlords and Proprie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors, and on all Leaſes, to be paid by the Leſſee, and al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed by the Leſſor out of their Rents, and for their ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Trades, Occupations, and Callings, to be Rated, Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſed, and Taxed by the Juſtices of the ſaid Town and Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh, any thing in this Act to the Contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority aforeſaid, That the Nation and People of the <hi>Jews,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">The <hi>Jews</hi> rated.</note> Reſiding within this Iſland, Pay, or Cauſe to be Paid towards the Raiſing of the ſaid Sum of Mony be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forementioned and expreſſed, to be Raiſed on the Inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants of this Iſland, over and above, and beſides the Tax as aforeſaid Aſſeſſed, the full Sum of One Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Pound currant Mony of this Iſland, to be rated Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſed, Taxed, Collected, and Paid in by <hi>Solomon Ararii, Jacob de Leon, Moles Toiro, Jacob Mendez, Guteres, Jacob Henriques, Jacob Rodrigues de Leon, Moſes Jeſurum Cordoſo, Samuel Gabay, Jacob Lopes Torres, Iſaac Cotileo, Iſaac Nunes Gonſales</hi> and <hi>Abraham Nunes,</hi> or any Five of them, into the Hands of the Receiver or Receivers hereafter mentioned, Impowered and Appointed to Receive the ſame, at, or within One Month after the Tenth Day of <hi>December,</hi> which ſhall be in the Year of our Lord, One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Three, any thing herein contained to the Contrary notwithſtanding: and in Caſe of Failure and Non-payment,</p>
               <p>BE it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid,<note place="margin">Caſe of Failure.</note> That the Sum of Two Hundred and Fifty Pound more, beſides the ſaid Sum of One Thouſand Pound above ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, be Aſſeſſed on the Nation and People of the <hi>Jews</hi> aforeſaid, and that then it ſhall, and may be lawful for the Treaſurer or Treaſurers hereafter appointed by Warrant of Diſtreſs under his, or their Hands and Seals directed to the Conſtable or Conſtables for the reſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctive
<pb n="67" facs="tcp:109567:36"/>Pariſhes where ſuch <hi>Jew</hi> or <hi>Jews</hi> Reſide, to Levy, or ſingly cauſe to be Levied at Diſcretion upon the ſeveral <hi>Jews</hi> Inhabitants of this Iſland, ſuch proportionable Sum or Sums as ſhall make up the Sum of One Thouſand Two Hundred Fifty Pound, as aforeſaid, and alſo if any of the <hi>Jews</hi> Rated, or Aſſeſſed by the Perſons above<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>named, ſhall refuſe to Pay the ſaid Sum by them ſo Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſed: that then it ſhall, and may be lawful for the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpective Juſtices in the reſpective Pariſhes where the ſaid <hi>Jews</hi> Reſide, for ſo much as any of the ſaid <hi>Jews</hi> are Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſed, and Rated by the Perſons aboveſaid, who are hereby Impowered to Iſſue out their Warrant or Warrants to the reſpective Conſtables to Diſtrain any of the Goods and Chattels of any of the ſaid <hi>Jews</hi> that ſhall refuſe, or delay to Pay the ſame, any Law, Cuſtom, or Uſage to the Contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted, That if the ſeveral Perſons, or any of them of the <hi>Jewiſh</hi> Nation aforemen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned, Impowred and Appointed to Aſſeſs, Levy, Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lect, and Pay in the aforeſaid Sum Aſſeſſed upon the Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the <hi>Jews,</hi> ſhall neglect his, or their Duty therein,<note place="margin">Neglect of <hi>Jewiſh</hi> Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſors.</note> that then it ſhall, and may be lawful for the Governour or Commander in Chief, by Warrant under his Hand and Seal directed to the Provoſt-Marſhal, or his lawful Deputy to Levy, or Cauſe to be Levyed, on all, and e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very Perſon, and Perſons to Offending One Hundred and Fifty Pound currant Money of this Iſland, or the va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue thereof, upon his, or their Monies, Slaves, Goods, or Chattels, and ſell the ſame by publick Outcry, returning the Overplus, if any be, to the Owner; and in Caſe no Monies, Slaves, or Goods are to be found as aforeſaid, that then he take into Cuſtody the Body of the Perſon or Perſons ſo Offending, and him, or them in ſafe Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtody keep, until he, or they Pay the ſaid Sum of One Hundred and Fifty Pound for the ſaid Offence, any Law, Cuſtom, or Uſage, or any thing in this Act ſeeming to the Contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <pb n="68" facs="tcp:109567:37"/>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority aforeſaid, That the reſpective Juſtices of the reſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctive Pariſhes, or Precincts, or within the Commiſſion of the Peace for the ſame, or any Two of them Deliver into the Hands of their reſpective Conſtables within their re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpective Pariſhes and Precincts,<note place="margin">Time of Col<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>lection.</note> a Roll of ſuch Tax, or Aſſeſſment as aforeſaid, ſo that the Collection be made within Three Months after the Tenth Day of <hi>November,</hi> which ſhall be in the Year of our Lord, One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Three, with a Warrant under the ſame, Signed and Sealed by the ſaid Juſtices, or any two of them, Impowring and Requiring the ſaid Conſtables to Levy the ſaid Tax or Aſſeſſment; and Pay the ſame into the Hands of the Church-Wardens for the time being in the Pariſh where the ſame is Taxed or Aſſeſſed as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid: and where it ſhall happen there are no Church-Wardens, that then the Conſtables are hereby required to Pay the ſame into the Hands of the Juſtices of the ſaid Pariſh, Deducting Four Pence in the Pound for Colleting the ſame in all the Pariſhes of this Iſland, (<hi>Port-Royal</hi> and <hi>Kingſton,</hi> only excepted) where it ſhall be done Gratis; who are hereby required to Receive, and Pay the ſame into the Hands of the Receiver or Receivers hereafter named, within one Month after the Collecting thereof: and leſt any Perſon or Perſons, ſo as aforeſaid Taxed or Aſſeſſed, ſhall refuſe, or delay to Pay his, her, or their Tax, or Aſſeſſment, the ſaid Juſtices, or any Two of them, are hereby required in the Warrant aforeſaid, to Impower and Command the Conſtable as aforeſaid, by virtue thereof to Diſtrain the Slaves,<note place="margin">Diſtreſs up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Non-pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</note> Horſes, Mares, Colts, Mules, Aſſes, Neat Cattle, Sheep, Lambs, Goats, Kids, or any other Perſonal Eſtate whatſoever, of him, her, or them, ſo refuſing or delaying, and Sell the ſame forthwith at Publick Outcry, retaining to themſelves Twelve Pence in the Pound for every ſuch Diſtreſs on Slaves, Horſes, Mares, Colts, Mules, Aſſes, Neat Cattle, Sheep, Lambs, Goats, Kids, or any other Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonal Eſtate whatſoever Diſtrained on, or Sold as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid,
<pb n="69" facs="tcp:109567:37"/>returning the Overplus, if any be, to the Owner.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority aforeſaid, That for the better Aſſeſſing, Colle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cting, Levying, and Paying in the Sums of Money ſo as aforeſaid limited and appointed to be Raiſed, and Paid as aforeſaid, and for the more effectual putting this Act in Execution, the Juſtices and Veſtries within their ſeveral Pariſhes and Precincts, are hereby required and impowered, immediately on Paſſing this Act, with all poſſible ſpeed to proceed to the Diſcharge of their ſaid Duties, in manner and form as is before Directed and Appointed.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, That if the Governour or Comman<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der in Chief for the time being, ſhall before the Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vying and Paying the Tax and Aſſeſſment by virtue of this Act laid on, and Aſſeſſed,<note place="margin">Caſe of Law-Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tial.</note> put Martial-Law in force in this Iſland, and for that Reaſon if any Perſon re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſe to Pay his, her, or their Tax as aforeſaid, all, and every Perſon or Perſons ſo refuſing, ſhall after the ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>piration of the Law-Martial, Pay double the Sum ſo laid on, and Aſſeſſed, to be Recovered by Warrant from any of Their Majeſties Juſtices of the Peace for the ſaid Precinct, directed to any Conſtable to Levy the ſame up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the Monies, Goods, or Chattels of the Perſon or Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons ſo Offending, and the ſaid Goods, or Chattels ſo Diſtrained, to Sell at publick Outcry, returning the Over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plus, if any be, to the Owner, retaining to himſelf Twelve Pence in the Pound for every ſuch Diſtreſs: all which ſaid Forfeitures of the Perſons ſo Offending ſhall be Paid as the other Monies by this Act ariſing, into the Hands of the Receivers in this Act nominated and appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, and Employed to the ſame Uſes, Intents and Purpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, as the Monies already by this Act Raiſed and Appro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priated, and to no other Uſe, Intent, and Purpoſe what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever;
<pb n="70" facs="tcp:109567:38"/>any Law, Cuſtom, or Uſage, or any Thing in this Act to the contrary in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That if the Juſtices, Veſtry-men, Conſtables, or Church-Wardens, or any of them, ſhall neglect, or wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully fail in his or their Duty, in Aſſeſſing, Collecting, or Paying the ſame as aforeſaid, that then, and in ſuch caſe,<note place="margin">Neglect of Aſſeſſors.</note> every Juſtice ſo neglecting, or wilfully fail<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in his or their Duty in this Act preſcribed, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to the true intent and meaning thereof, ſhall For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feit Fifty Pounds for every ſuch Offence; and all and every Veſtry-man, Church-Warden or Conſtable, the Summ of Twenty Pounds for every ſuch Offence as aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That all Owners of Slaves, Horſes, Mares, Colts, Mules, Aſſes, Neat Cattel, Sheep, Goats, Lambs, and Kids whatſoever, as aforeſaid, ſhall, and are hereby by themſelves, Guardians, Overſeers, Truſtees, or Pen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keepers within the ſeveral Pariſhes aforeſaid, required and obliged to give a True and Juſt Account,<note place="margin">Account on Oath.</note> on Oath, to the beſt of their Knowledge, at ſuch time or times as the Juſtices in each Pariſh or Precinct ſhall Direct, of all Slaves, Horſes, Mares, Colts, Mules, Aſſes, Neat Cattel, Sheep, Lambs, Goats, Kids, and Rents what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever as aforeſaid, belonging to ſuch Owner, Guardian, Overſeer, Truſtees, or Pen-keepers within their reſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctive Pariſh, or Precinct aforeſaid, to the Juſtices of the Peace, or any of them, in the ſaid Pariſhes or Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cincts, who are hereby required and impowered to Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſter the ſame, and to ask all further Queſtions, as to them, or any of them ſhall ſeem meet and neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſary, relating to this preſent Act; the Tenour of which Oaths ſhall be as followeth.</p>
               <pb n="71" facs="tcp:109567:38"/>
               <q>
                  <hi>I A. B.</hi> do Swear, that I have within the Pariſh of <hi>C</hi>— Slaves Young and Old, alſo — Horſes, Mares, Colts, Mules, Aſſes, Neat Cattel, Sheep, Goats, Lambs, Kids, and no more,</q>
               <p>So help me God.</p>
               <p>And if it be to an Overſeer,</p>
               <q>
                  <hi>I D. E.</hi> Overſeer of the Plantation of <hi>G. H.</hi> do Swear, that the ſaid <hi>G. H.</hi> hath within the Pariſh of <hi>I</hi>— Slaves Young and Old, and alſo — Horſes, Mares, Colts, Mules, Aſſes, Neat Cattel, Sheep, Lambs, Goats, Kids, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and no more, to the beſt of my Knowledge.</q>
               <p>And ſo to Pen-keepers, or any other Perſons, for Cattel, Horſes, Mares, Colts, Mules, Aſſes, Neat Cattel, Sheep, Lambs, Goats, Kids, and Rents whatſoever, <hi>mutatis mutandis.</hi> And if any Perſon or Perſons whatſoever, ſhall refuſe either by themſelves, Overſeers,<note place="margin">Caſe of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſal.</note> or Pen-keepers, to give an Account upon Oath as aforeſaid, of their Horſes, Mares, Colts, Mules, Aſſes, Neat Cattel, Sheep, Lambs, Goats, Kids, or Rents in manner afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, that then it ſhall be lawful for the Juſtices and Veſtry, or the Juſtices where there is no Veſtry, to Tax the Perſon or Perſons ſo refuſing, according to their Diſcretion.</p>
               <p>AND foraſmuch as the preſent Neceſſity will re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire the Advancement of Money, for and towards the Buying, or Hiring, and Equipping the ſaid Two Sloops and Men, and Victualling thoſe Two already in, and
<pb n="72" facs="tcp:109567:39"/>ſuch other Veſſel or Veſſels as ſhall be Impreſſed into the Service:</p>
               <p>BE it Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That it ſhall and may be lawful to, and for any Perſon or Perſons to Advance and Lend to Their Majeſties,<note place="margin">Money ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vanc'd.</note> for and towards the furtherance of this preſent Occaſion, ſuch Summ or Summs of Money as may be needful; and that whoſoever ſhall Advance and Lend any ſuch Summ or Summs of Money upon the Security of this Act, ſhall re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive for the Loan of the Summ they ſhall ſo Lend, after the Rate of Twelve Pound and a Half <hi>per Cent. per Annum,</hi> for the time he or they ſhall be indisburſt of the ſaid Money, on the Credit of this Act as aforeſaid; any thing before-mentioned to the contrary thereof in any wiſe not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND to the End that all Monies that ſhall be Lent unto Their Majeſties, upon the Credit hereof may be well and ſufficiently ſecured;<note place="margin">Security for the ſame.</note> Be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That all and every Perſon and Perſons, who ſhall Advance and Lend any Summ or Summs of Money to Their Majeſties on the Credit of this Act, and actually Pay the ſame into the Hands of the Receiver or Receivers herein after named and appointed, ſhall by the Receiver or Receivers on the firſt Payment of Money that ſhall be paid into the Receivers Hands, by Virtue of this Act, be forthwith paid unto the Perſon or Perſons, their Executors, or Adminiſtrators ſo Lending the ſaid Summ advanced, with the Intereſt of the ſame, for the Diſcharge of the Money ſo lent and advanced; and that all and every other Summ and Summs of Money that ſhall be laid out, or paid by the Receiver or Receivers, for, and towards the Buying, Equipping, Victualling, and Fit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting to Sea; as alſo for Paying the Officers and Sea-men on Board the ſaid Four Sloops, and Victualling ſuch other Veſſel or Veſſels as ſhall be Impreſſed; as alſo for Paying the Officers and Soldiers of the Two Parties before<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentioned, for reducing the Rebellious <hi>Negroes,</hi> ſhall, as
<pb n="73" facs="tcp:109567:39"/>they become Due, be paid by the Receiver or Receivers that are hereafter mentioned and appointed, without Fee or Charge.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That the Honourable Colonel <hi>Charles Knights,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Names of the Receivers.</note> one of Their Majeſties Council of this Iſland, and alſo Colonel <hi>Thomas Clarke,</hi> Captain <hi>Lancelot Talbot,</hi> Captain <hi>Robert Wardlow, William Hutchinſon</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr>, Captain <hi>Joſiah Heathcote,</hi> and Captain <hi>Thomas Clarke,</hi> be, and are hereby Required, Impowered, and Warranted to be Receiver or Receivers of all and ſingular the ſeveral Summs aforeſaid, men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned and intended to be raiſed on the ſeveral Pariſhes or People aforeſaid, and ſhall, and may lawfully by Advice and Conſent of the Lieutenant-Governour, or Commander in Chief, forthwith Buy or Hire Two more Good and Subſtantial Sloops fit for War, and Provide, Equip, Fit ready for the Sea, and Victual the ſame for Sixty effective Officers, Sea-men and Soldiers, incluſively, for each Sloop, for the ſaid Six Months, or for ſuch shorter time as to them ſhall appear moſt Convenient; and that the ſaid Two Sloops being thus Fitted and Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctualled, it is hereby Requeſted, That the Right Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable Sir <hi>William Beeſton,</hi> Knight,<note place="margin">Captain to be Commiſſion'd.</note> Their Majeſties Lieu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenant-Governour aforeſaid, by Commiſſion under his Hand and Seal, do Conſtitute, and Appoint on Board of each of the ſaid Sloops, ſuch Diſcreet and Able Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tains for this preſent Service, as his Honour ſhall in his Prudence think Fit, and can Confide in; and that each of the ſaid Captains receive for their Pay, after the Rate of Six Pounds <hi>per</hi> Month,<note place="margin">Payments ſettled.</note> and likewiſe appoint by his Warrant for each Sloop, one Maſter, at Four Pounds <hi>per</hi> Month, one Boatſwain, one Gunner, at Three Pounds <hi>per</hi> Month each, and one Chirurgeon, and one Carpen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, at Four Pounds <hi>per</hi> Month each, Two Quarter-Maſters at Fifty Shillings <hi>per</hi> Month each, on Board each Sloop, and command and require them in Their Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties Name, to Raiſe and Enliſt on Board the ſaid Two Sloops, by Impreſſing or otherwiſe, to make and fit up
<pb n="74" facs="tcp:109567:40"/>the full Number of Sixty Effective Officers, Sea-men, and Soldiers in each Sloop, who ſhall alſo receive after the Rate of Forty Shillings each Man <hi>per</hi> Month, and that their Monthly Pay ariſing for this preſent Service, ſhall be paid out of the Money raiſed by this preſent Act, Commanding and Requiring the reſpective Captains of each Sloop aforeſaid, by his Commiſſion and Inſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctions therewith to be given, that they take Care from time to time, to their utmoſt Ability, to Guard and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fend the Coaſts of this Iſland, by conſtant Cruiſing, and looking out both Windward and Leeward, North and South ſide of this Iſland, as his Honour ſhall in his great Wiſdom from time to time Direct and Command.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That for the more ſpeedy Supplying with Neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaries, Victualling, Fitting out, and Diſpatching to Sea the Veſſels of War aforeſaid, the Commiſſioners in this Act nominated and appointed, are hereby Impowered to Employ Captain <hi>William Dodington,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Commiſſary appointed.</note> or any other fit Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, in caſe of his Death, Removal, or Misbehaviour, to buy and provide Victuals, Arms and Ammunition, and all other Neceſſaries whatſoever, convenient for the ſaid Veſſels, and draw Bills upon the Treaſurer or Treaſurers for the Value; for which Service they ſhall allow and pay unto the ſaid <hi>William Dodington,</hi> or other Perſon ſo Employed, after the Rate of Five Pound for every Hundred Pounds worth of Proviſions, Arms, Am<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munition, or other Things needful by the ſaid Perſon ſo bought.</p>
               <p>BE it alſo Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That Colonel <hi>Charles Knights,</hi> and <hi>Joſiah Heathcote</hi> Eſquires, be, and are hereby appointed, impowered, and warranted to be Treaſurers to Receive and Pay all ſuch Summ and Summs of Money as ſhall from time to time come to their Hands,<note place="margin">Treaſurers.</note> for the more eaſie and ready Diſpatch of ſuch Perſons as they may have occaſion to Deal with; or Pay all ſuch Wages unto the Officers, Seamen and
<pb n="75" facs="tcp:109567:40"/>Soldiers, as the Occaſion and Intent of this Act may re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire; and as ſoon as the Receiver or Receivers before appointed and impowered, have Bought, Hired, and E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quipped the ſaid Sloops, and Victualled them with ſuffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient Victuals for their reſpective Complements of Men aforeſaid, for the time they ſhall find convenient, that the ſaid Sloops be forthwith diſpatch'd out to Sea, by the Command and Direction of the Lieutenant-Governour or Commander in Chief, to Cruiſe about the Coaſts of this Iſland as aforeſaid: and that the Receiver or Recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers keep a diſtinct Account of the Money raiſed and ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>propriated by this preſent Act, and for all Payments made for the Uſes and Purpoſes in this Act required, and render a Juſt and True Account thereof,<note place="margin">Account to be given.</note> when de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded, unto Their Majeſties Lieutenant Governour, or Commander in Chief, and Council, of all ſuch Summ and Summs of Money, by them, and every of them, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived by Virtue of this preſent Act, and how laid out, and for what, and to whom, and for what Uſes; and ſhall in like manner give an Account to the Aſſembly of this Iſland when ſitting and aſſembled, when there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unto required, of ſo much of the ſaid Money, as ſhall be by them, and every of them reſpectively received, and to whom the ſame are iſſued and paid by them re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpectively, and to what Uſes; and if the ſaid Receiver or Receivers, or any of them, after the Receipt of any the ſaid Money, ſhall divert or miſapply the ſame, or any Part thereof, by any Pretence whatſoever, otherwiſe than before intended and directed, contrary to the true Intent and Meaning of this Act, he or they ſo Offending, ſhall Forfeit to Their Majeſties, for, and towards the Support of the Government of this Iſland, and contingent Charges thereof, double the Summ ſo diverted or miſap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plied.</p>
               <p>AND for the better Order and Government of the ſaid Sloops, or other Veſſel or Veſſels of War, wherein the Honour of Their Majeſties, and Intereſt of this Iſland are ſo much concerned; Be it further Enacted by the
<pb n="76" facs="tcp:109567:41"/>Authority aforeſaid, That all and every the Articles and Orders mentioned in a certain Act of Parliament made in the Thirteenth Year of the Reign of His Majeſty King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second of Bleſſed Memory,<note place="margin">Articles and Orders.</note> for the Eſtabliſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Articles and Orders for the Regulating, and better Governing of his Majeſty's Navy, and Ships of War, and Forces by Sea, ſhall be duly and reſpetively put in Execution, obſerved and obeyed on Board the ſaid Sloops and other Veſſels of War, and are hereby declared to be the Laws of this Iſland, againſt all ſuch Perſon or Perſons on Board the ſaid Sloops or Veſſels as ſhall offend therein; and for further Encouragement of the Officers, Sea-men, and Soldiers on Board the ſaid Sloops or Veſſels, all Ships, Sloops, or Veſſels by them taken from the Enemy, and belonging to this Iſland, are likewiſe hereby given them for the ſaid Encouragement: Provided always that all Slaves, Veſſels, or Goods belonging to Their Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties Subjects of this Iſland, which the ſaid Sloops or Veſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſels of War ſhall happen to re-take before they ſhall have arrived at the Enemies Ports, during the time that they or any of them are Employed in this preſent Service on the Countries Charge as aforeſaid, ſhall be returned to the reſpective Owners or Proprietors, their Agents or Attornies; any Law, Cuſtom, or Uſage to the contrary in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the ſaid Parties hereby raiſed, or to be raiſed for the ſubduing the Rebellious <hi>Negroes</hi> aforeſaid, in caſe of Miſde<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>meanor, or neglect of their Duty in that behalf, ſhall be lia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble to the Pains and Puniſhments preſcribed in the Articles of War,<note place="margin">Pay for the Soldiers.</note> as when Martial-Law is in Force in this Iſland, and that the Captains of each Party receive for his Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice, in this Act intended and appointed, the Summ of Four Pounds <hi>per</hi> Month, and that each Serjeant receive alſo Fifty Shillings <hi>per</hi> Month, and each Soldier, Forty Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs <hi>per</hi> Month, to be paid by the Receiver or Recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers, without any Fee or Charge to either Officer or Soldier.</p>
               <pb n="77" facs="tcp:109567:41"/>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, That for the better Encouraging the Perſons Employed on Board the ſaid Sloops or other Veſſels for the Service of Their Majeſties and this Iſland, that they ſhall receive as Salvage for all Veſſels, Slaves, and other Goods taken of this Iſland, and by them re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taken before they are Landed in any of the Enemies Commiſſion-Ports, one ſixth Part of the Veſſels, Slaves,<note place="margin">Salvage al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed.</note> or Goods ſo re-taken, or the Value thereof, the ſaid Veſſel, Slave, or Goods having been firſt appraiſed by Two Perſons indifferently Choſen, one by the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mander or Commanders of the ſaid Sloops or Veſſels, and the other by the reſpective Owner or Owners; which ſhall be divided among the Officers, Sea-men, and Sol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diers of the ſaid Veſſels, proportionably to the Pay each Perſon receives of his Country for that Service.</p>
               <p>AND that all ſuch Perſons as ſhall go out in the Parties to reduce the <hi>Negroes</hi> in Rebellion, may be in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duced to proceed with the more Reſolution and Vigor; It is hereby Enacted, that they ſhall receive from the Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurers, for each <hi>Negro</hi> kill'd that was actually in Rebel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lion, which ſhall be evidenced by bringing in his Head to any Juſtice, the Summ of Forty Shillings;<note place="margin">Rewards for Negroes ſlain or taken.</note> and for each <hi>Negroe</hi> in Rebellion taken, and brought in alive, not maimed or mortally wounded, the Summ of Ten Pounds, to be paid by the Owner or Proprietor of ſuch Slave or Slaves, who is hereby obliged under the Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty of Fifty Pounds, to Tranſport the Slave or Slaves ſo reduced from actual Rebellion; and in caſe that no Owner can be found, that then the Treaſurer or Treaſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rers by this Act appointed, or either of them, ſhall be by Virtue of this Act, obliged and impowered to Pay the ſaid Ten Pound out of the Treaſury, and receive the ſaid Slave or Slaves, and him, and them, Sell and Tran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſport as aforeſaid, and the Produce retain in his Hands, to be Employed in the ſaid Service, and for defraying the contingent Charges thereof; and to the end it may be
<pb n="78" facs="tcp:109567:42"/>better known what <hi>Negro</hi> ſhall be accounted Rebellious, it is hereby declared, That all <hi>Negroes</hi> abſenting them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves from their Owners Plantation the Term of Six Months, be, and are accounted as in actual Rebellion, any thing to the contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND be it Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That in caſe any of the Officers, or Sea-men on Board the ſaid Sloops or Veſſels, or in the ſaid Parties ſhall in actual Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice,<note place="margin">Sea-man or Soldier diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>abled.</note> loſe either Leg or Arm, or be otherwiſe Diſabled, that then, and in all ſuch Caſes, all and every of the diſabled Men, ſhall receive Ten Pounds <hi>per Annum</hi> with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Charge, during his or their natural Life, and alſo their Cures to be paid for out of the Publick Revenue of this Iſland, by Order of the Lieutenant-Governour and Council, or of the Government of this Iſland, out of the firſt Payment.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That when there ſhall be no neceſſity for the ſaid Sloops or Veſſels of War, that it ſhall, and may be law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful for the Commiſſioners, or the <hi>major</hi> Part of them, to Sell the ſame, with all the Apparel and Furniture, and of the Money ariſing therefrom, with all other Summs of Money which ſhall remain over and above,<note place="margin">Remainder how applied.</note> or be not expended, of the Money ariſing, and appropriated by Virtue of this Act, and not hereby applied, ſhall be and remain in the Hands of the ſaid Treaſurers, or either of them, by this Act appointed, to be applied and diſpoſed of, for and towards ſuch other Uſe or Uſes as the Aſſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly of this Iſland ſhall appoint by a Law; and that the ſaid Receiver or Receivers, Treaſurer or Treaſurers, ſhall be allowed all his, or their, or either of their, reaſonable Charges, in and about the Diſcharging the Truſt hereby repoſed in them, Commiſſion or Pretences to Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion, hereby excepted.</p>
               <pb n="79" facs="tcp:109567:42"/>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That the Fines and Forfeitures mentioned in this Act, and not declared where they ſhall be Recovered,<note place="margin">Forfeitures, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> diſpoſed of.</note> or how Diſpoſed of, be One Half to Their Majeſties, for and towards the Support of the Government of this Iſland, and the contingent Charges thereof; the other Half to the Informer, who ſhall Sue for the ſame in any Court of Record within this Iſland, wherein no Eſſoin, Protection, Injunction, Wager of Law, or <hi>Nonvult ul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terius proſequi</hi> ſhall be allowed.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <head>
                  <hi>An ACT</hi> Appropriating ſeveral Summs of Money heretofore Raiſed, to the immediate Service of this I<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſland.</head>
               <p>WHEREAS there have been ſeveral Sums of Money raiſed by Virtue of one Act,<note place="margin">Preamble.</note> Entitled, <hi>An Act for Raiſing Money, for, and towards the Defence of this Iſland;</hi> and alſo by one other Act, Entitled, <hi>An Act for Raiſing Monies, as a fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Aid to Their Majeſties, for, and towards the Defence of this Iſland:</hi> And whereas it is provided in the ſaid Acts, That ſuch Part of the Monies ſo raiſed, and not laid out to the Uſes therein directed, ſhould be appro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priated to ſuch Uſe or Service as the Governour, Council, and Aſſembly ſhall ſeem meet: We do therefore moſt humbly beſeech Your Majeſties, that it may be Enacted:</p>
               <pb n="80" facs="tcp:109567:43"/>
               <p>AND be it Enacted by your Majeſties Lieutenant-Governour, Council, and Aſſembly, and it is hereby Enacted, and Ordained by the Authority of the ſame, That of the Monies ariſing by virtue of the Acts above<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentioned, and not hitherto applied, or made uſe of, One Thouſand and Three Hundred Pound currant Money of this Iſland,<note place="margin">Money ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>propriated.</note> be applied for the Payment of One Thouſand Pound <hi>Sterling</hi> in <hi>England,</hi> to Colonel <hi>Peter Beckford,</hi> to be by him made uſe of for the Service of this Iſland, in ſuch manner as he ſhall think fit, to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards the effecting ſuch things as he ſhall be directed by the Governour there to Solicite.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That of the Monies ariſing by virtue of the Acts above<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentioned, and not hitherto applied, or made uſe of, ſo much thereof as ſhall be neceſſary for the Victualling and Manning of a Sloop to Tranſport Colonel <hi>Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Beckford,</hi> who is now going for <hi>England</hi> for the Service of this Iſland, ſhall be Paid as the Governour ſhall Direct.</p>
               <p>AND be it alſo Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That ſuch Money as ſhall ariſe from the Freight of Goods, Shipped on Board the ſaid Sloop, either to, or from <hi>England,</hi> be by Colonel <hi>Peter Beckford</hi> applyed to the Defraying the Charges of the ſaid Veſſel, and that the Commander of the ſaid Sloop do from time to time obſerve all ſuch Orders and Inſtructions as he ſhall receive from the ſaid Colonel <hi>Beckford.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, That of the Monies ariſing by virtue of the Acts aforeſaid, the Sum of One Thouſand Pound ſhall be Paid into the Hands of the Treaſurer or Treaſurers, Appointed by an Act Entitled, <hi>An Act to Reimburſe Their Majeſties Treaſury, and Encourage Their Subjects to come and Settle in this Iſland,</hi> to be by them Employed, and
<pb n="81" facs="tcp:109567:43"/>uſed for the paying the Paſſages of ſuch Perſons as ſhall Tranſport themſelves hither upon the Encouragement of the ſaid Act, and to no other Uſes, Intents, or Purpoſes whatſoever, upon the Penalties in the ſaid Act men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That of the Money ariſing by virtue of the Acts aforeſaid, and not hitherto applyed, or made uſe of, that Seventy Pounds, or ſuch part thereof as ſhall be Expended, be applyed and made uſe of for the defraying the Charge of a Sloop already ſent to <hi>Windward,</hi> to Cruiſe there, to give notice to the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Fleet, daily expected here, of the Additional Force the <hi>French</hi> have, or may ſudden<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly receive.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted, that of the Money ariſing by virtue of the Acts aforeſaid, and not hitherto applyed, or made uſe of, the Sum of One Hundred Sixty Two Pounds, be Paid into the Hands of Colonel <hi>Edward Stan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton,</hi> for defraying the Charge of Twelve Men for Six Months, to be conſtantly kept at <hi>Fort-William</hi> at <hi>Port-Morant</hi> for their Defence thereof, and the Security of the Adjacent Parts.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That the Remainder of the ſaid Monies ariſing by virtue of the beforementioned Acts, and not by this pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Act applyed, ſhall be by the Governour, by, and with the Advice and Conſent of the Council, applyed, and made uſe of for the immediate Defence of this Iſland, and to no other Uſes, Intents, or Purpoſes whatſoever, and the Receiver or Receivers, Treaſurer or Treaſurers, in the ſaid Act appointed, are hereby Required and Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>powered to Pay the ſame accordingly, under the Penal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties in this Act hereaftermentioned, any thing in this, or any other Act ſeeming to the Contrary, in any wiſe not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding.</p>
               <pb n="82" facs="tcp:109567:44"/>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted, that the Receivers and Treaſurers in the ſaid Acts appointed, are hereby Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired and Impowred to Pay the ſeveral Sums by this Act appropriated, into the Hands of ſuch Perſon or Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons as ſhall be Impowred to receive the ſame, by virtue of a Warrant to them, or any of them, under the Hand of the Governour (by, and with the Advice and Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent of the Council of this Iſland) and if the ſaid Recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver,<note place="margin">Forfeit of the Receiver or Treaſurer refuſing to pay.</note> or Receivers, Treaſurer, or Treaſurers, or any of them, ſhall refuſe to Pay the aforeſaid Sums, or any part thereof, having the ſame in their, or any of their Hands, the Receiver, or Treaſurer ſo refuſing, ſhall reſpectively Forfeit to Their Majeſties, for, and towards the Support of this Government, and the Charges thereof, double the Sum he ſhall ſo refuſe to Pay, to be Recovered by Action of Debt, Bill, Plaint, or Information in any Court of Record, where no Eſſoin, Protection, or Wager of Law ſhall be allowed.</p>
               <p>AND whereas with part of the Monies by the ſaid Acts ariſing, there were purchaſed for the Service of the Country Two Sloops,<note place="margin">Two Sloops to be diſpoſed of.</note> be it Enacted that the Governour, ſell, or make uſe of the ſaid Sloops for the Countries Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice at his Diſcretion, and if ſold, the Governour apply the Monies, by, and with the Advice and Conſent of the Council as before directed.</p>
               <p>AND whereas ſeveral Sums of Money ordered to be Aſſeſſed, and Levyed by the abovementioned Acts, either not having been Aſſeſſed, nor Levyed within the time in the ſaid Acts limited and appointed in ſome of the Pariſhes within this Iſland;</p>
               <p>BE it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That where any Tax mentioned to be Raiſed by either of the above-recited Acts,<note place="margin">Re-Aſſeſſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment to be made.</note> and omitted to be either Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſed or Levyed by the Juſtices and Veſtry, or the Juſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, where the Veſtries neglect their Duty, or where no
<pb n="83" facs="tcp:109567:44"/>Veſtry is, are Impowered at any other Day, or Place, within Three Months after the Paſſing this Act, as to the ſaid Juſtices ſhall ſeem meet to Appoint, to Aſſeſs, and Levy, as well during Martial Law, as while the Common-Law is in force, upon the ſeveral Inhabitants of the ſaid Pariſhes, the ſaid Taxes: and iſſue out their Warrants accordingly to the reſpective Conſtables for the Collecting, Levying, and Diſtraining for the ſame, and Payment thereof, as is directed in the ſaid Acts; which ſaid Conſtables are hereby Impowered to Collect, and in Caſe of refuſal to Levy, and Diſtrain for the ſame ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cordingly, notwithſtanding the time then limited in the ſaid Acts be Elapſed, by reaſon of Martial-Law, or any other Cauſe, Protection, or Priviledge whatſoever; and whatſoever Juſtices, or Veſtry, or Conſtables, ſhall o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit to do their Duty therein, ſhall Forfeit as is directed by the ſaid Acts, and to be Recovered and applied ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cordingly.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That all Pains and Penalties,<note place="margin">Penalties re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted.</note> by the abovemen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned Acts, by any the Juſtices, or Veſtry of the reſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpective Pariſhes incurred, are hereby abſolutely remitted and diſcharged, and the Parties Offending fully indemni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fied for the ſame, any Law, or Statute to the Contrary in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <pb n="84" facs="tcp:109567:45"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>An ACT</hi> For Appropriating ſeveral Sums of Money for the ſpeedy Relief of the Wounded, and Diſtreſſed Inhabitants of this Iſland, who have ſuffered by the late Invaſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of the <hi>French.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>WHEREAS there have been ſeveral Sums of Money Raiſed by virtue of one Act,<note place="margin">Preamble.</note> Entitled, <hi>An Act for Raiſing Money, for, and toward<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> the Defence of this Iſland;</hi> And alſo by One other Act, Entitled, <hi>An Act for Raiſing Money as a fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Aid to their Majeſties, for, and towards the Defence of this Iſland;</hi> and whereas it's Provided in the ſaid Acts, that ſuch part of the Money ſo Raiſed, and not laid out to the Uſes therein Directed, ſhould be appropriated to ſuch other Uſe and Service as to the Governour, Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cil, and Aſſembly ſhall ſeem meet.</p>
               <p>AND whereas by a Subſequent Act of Their Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties Lieutenant-Governour, Council, and Aſſembly of this Their Majeſties Iſland of <hi>Jamaica,</hi> made this preſent Seſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions of this Aſſembly; 'twas Enacted among other things, that of the Money ariſing by virtue of the Acts abovementioned, and not therein applied or made uſe of, the Sum of One Thouſand and Three Hundred Pound currant Money of this Iſland,<note place="margin">Recourſe to former Acts.</note> ſhould be applied for the Payment of One Thouſand Pound Sterling in <hi>England,</hi> to Colonel <hi>Peter Beckford,</hi> to be by him made uſe of for the Service of this Iſland, in ſuch manner as he
<pb n="85" facs="tcp:109567:45"/>ſhould think fit, towards the Effecting ſuch things as he ſhould be directed there to Solicite by the Governour.</p>
               <p>AND whereas by the ſaid Act it was further En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted by the Authority aforeſaid, that out of the Monies ariſing by virtue of the ſaid Acts abovementioned, and not applied or made uſe of, as much thereof as ſhould be neceſſary for the Victualling and Manning a Sloop to Tranſport Colonel <hi>Peter Beckford,</hi> who was then going for <hi>England</hi> for the Service of this Iſland, ſhould be Paid as the Governour ſhould Direct.</p>
               <p>AND whereas it was further Enacted by the Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity aforeſaid, That of the Monies ariſing by virtue of the Acts abovementioned, and not hitherto applied or made uſe of, the Sum of One Hundred Sixty and Two Pounds, ſhould be Paid into the Hands of Colonel <hi>Ed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward Stanton,</hi> for defraying the Charge of Twelve Men for Six Months, to be conſtantly kept at <hi>Fort-William.</hi> at <hi>Port-Morant</hi> for the Defence thereof, and Security of the adjacent Parts.</p>
               <p>AND whereas the Receivers and Treaſurers in the ſaid Act firſt abovementioned and appointed, are Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired and Impowered by the ſaid appropriating Act, to Pay the ſeveral Sums by the ſaid Acts appropriated un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der certain Penalties therein contained, into the Hands of ſuch Perſon or Perſons as ſhall be impowered to receive the ſame, by virtue of a Warrant, to them, or any of them, under the Hand of the Governour, by, and with the Advice, and Conſent of the Council; ſince the Paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing of which Act, Intitled, <hi>An Act for Appropriating ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Sums of Money heretofore Raiſed to the immediate Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice of this Iſland;</hi> this Your Majeſties Iſland has been moſt miſerably harraſſed by Your Majeſties Enemies, Subjects to the Crown of <hi>France,</hi> who with inhuman barbarity, with Fire and Sword, have laid Waſt Four Pariſhes of this Iſland, and infeſted and deſtroyed ſeveral Plantations in the other Pariſhes, to the utter ruin and
<pb n="86" facs="tcp:109567:46"/>deſtruction of moſt of the Inhabitants thereof, whereby without ſome ſpeedy Relief, ſeveral Hundreds of this Your Majeſties Iſland muſt periſh through Extreme Want,<note place="margin">General Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lamity.</note> and the ſaid Pariſhes, and moſt part of the Sea-Coaſts be wholly Deſerted, being deſtitute of Habitations, and having no Means to Rebuild them, except ſome ſpeedy Succour from the Publick.</p>
               <p>WE therefore Your Majeſties Lieutenant-Governour, Council, and Aſſembly, do humbly pray Your Majeſty, that for the immediate Relief and Support of the ſaid poor diſtreſſed Inhabitants of this Iſland, who have ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fered in the late Invaſion; it may be Enacted, and it is hereby Enacted by the Authority of the ſame, that the aforeſaid Sum of One Thouſand and Three Hundred Pounds above recited, by the Appropriating Act ordered to be applied for the Payment of One Thouſand Pound <hi>Sterling</hi> in <hi>England</hi> to Colonel <hi>Peter Beckford,</hi> to be by him made uſe of as by the ſaid Act is directed, as alſo the ſaid Sum of One Hundred, Sixty and Two Pound, by the ſaid Act appointed to be Paid into the Hands of Colonel <hi>Edward Stanton,</hi> for the defraying the Charge of Twelve Men for Six Months, to be conſtantly kept at <hi>Fort-William</hi> at <hi>Port-Morant</hi> for the Defence thereof, and the Security of the Parts adjacent, which ſaid Sums are not yet made uſe of, be forth with applied for,<note place="margin">Appropriati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons taken off.</note> and to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards the Relief of the ſaid diſtreſſed Inhabitants of this Your Majeſties Iſland of <hi>Jamaica,</hi> who have ſuffered by the barbarous Cruelties of Your Majeſties Enemies, in the late Invaſion of this Iſland by the <hi>French,</hi> as alſo for the Relief of the Sick and Wounded Perſons in the late Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pedition to <hi>Whily-Wood</hi> againſt the Enemy, and to no other uſe whatſoever; to be diſtributed in ſuch manner, and to ſuch Perſons as ſhall ſeem meet to the Commiſſioners to be appointed by Your Majeſties Lieutenant-Governor, and Council of this Your Iſland for that purpoſe.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, that the abovementioned Act, Paſt this preſent Seſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions
<pb n="87" facs="tcp:109567:46"/>Entitled, <hi>An Act appropriating ſeveral Sums of Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney heretofore Raiſed, to the immediate Service of this Iſland,</hi> as to ſo much of the ſaid Act only as con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerns the applying the One Thouſand and Three Hundred Pound, for the Payment of One Thouſand Pound <hi>Sterling</hi> in <hi>England</hi> to Colonel <hi>Peter Beckford,</hi> to be by him made uſe of for the Service of this Iſland; as alſo for the applying any Sums of Monies other than what are already Expended for the Victualling and Manning a Sloop to Tranſport the ſaid Colonel <hi>Peter Beckford</hi> for <hi>England,</hi> or whereby the Receivers or Treaſurers, who by the Two Acts firſt abovementioned, are Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, Required, and Impowered to Pay the ſeveral Sums, by the ſaid Appropriating Act applied, into the Hands of ſuch Perſon or Perſons as ſhall be Impowered to receive the ſame by virtue of a Warrant to them, or any of them, under the Hand of the Governour, by, and with the Advice and Conſent of the Council, as al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo for the applying One Hundred Sixty and Two Pounds to be Paid into the Hands of Colonel <hi>Edward Stanton,</hi> for the defraying the Charge of Twelve Men for Six Months, to be conſtantly kept at <hi>Fort-William</hi> at <hi>Port-Morant,</hi> ſhall be,<note place="margin">Repeal of Clauſes.</note> and are hereby Repealed to all In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents and Purpoſes whatſoever, any thing in the ſaid recited Act to the Contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <pb n="88" facs="tcp:109567:47"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>AN ACT</hi> For the Encouragement, and Free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of Servants, and Slaves which have done, or ſhall do any remarkable Service againſt the <hi>French</hi> during this preſent War.</head>
               <p>WHEREAS upon Advice of the late In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vaſion made by the <hi>French</hi> upon this Iſland,<note place="margin">Preamble.</note> there was ſet forth an Order of Council of War for the Encouragement of <hi>Negroes,</hi> that All <hi>Negroes,</hi> or Slaves that ſhould do any Eminent Service againſt the Enemy ſhould be forthwith ſet Free, and that it is alſo thought reaſonable for the Reward of Servants that have behaved themſelves well in the late Service, that they be freed of the time they have yet to Serve:</p>
               <p>BE it therefore Enacted and Ordained by Their Majeſties Lieutenant-Governour, Council, and Aſſembly, and it is hereby Enacted and Ordained by the Authority of the ſame, that all Servants who receive no Salary, which have, or ſhall do any good Service againſt the Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my, the <hi>French,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Servants ſignalizing themſelves againſt the Enemy.</note> and can prove the ſame before the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners hereafter named, ſhall forthwith be freed; and that the ſaid Commiſſioners upon Enquiry made of what time any ſuch Servant or Servants had to Serve, and his, and their Occupation, ſhall Value and Appraiſe the ſaid time, he, or they had to Serve, and give him, or them, a Certificate mentioning, his, or their Name or Names, and the Party, or Parties, to whom he, or they belonged, and the Sum or Sums the Owner, or Owners ought to
<pb n="89" facs="tcp:109567:47"/>receive for him or them, which being Entred into the Secretary's Office, ſhall be a ſufficient Teſtimony of his or their Freedom, as alſo a good Proof for the Owner or Owners to Recover the Summ or Summs he or they were appraiſed at.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, That all Slaves that have, or ſhall during this War with <hi>France,</hi> do any Remarkable good Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice againſt the Enemy,<note place="margin">Slaves freed.</note> and make Proofs thereof be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the ſaid Commiſſioners hereafter named, ſhall be Freed; and the ſaid Commiſſioners ſhall give the ſaid Slave a Certificate, mentioning his Name, the Perſon to whom he belonged, and the Price he was appraiſed and valued at, which is not to exceed the Summ of Fifty Pounds, which ſaid Certificate being entred into the Secretary's Office, ſhall be ſufficient to Diſcharge him of his Slavery, and a Proof for the Owner to Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cover what he was appraiſed at, which Summ for ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Servant or Slave ſo ſet Free and appraiſed, is to be paid out of Money to be raiſed for that purpoſe.</p>
               <p>AND whereas divers Perſons have for the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence of this Iſland, Armed, and ſent out ſeveral of their <hi>Negroes</hi> or Slaves, who have been killed in Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice:</p>
               <p>BE it therefore further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That upon Proof made before the ſaid Commiſſioners,<note place="margin">Slave kill'd.</note> of any ſuch <hi>Negro</hi> or Slave ſo killed in Service, or that ſhall be during the War, the Owner or Owners thereof, ſhall receive ſuch Summ or Summs of Money as the Commiſſioners ſhall think fit, not exceeding the Summ of Fifty Pounds, to be paid to the Owner or Owners, in the ſame manner, as is before expreſſed for Servants, <hi>Negroes,</hi> or Slaves ſo Freed.</p>
               <pb n="90" facs="tcp:109567:48"/>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, that any Owner or Overſeer, that ſhall hin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der any Servant or Slave from Repairing to the Commiſſioners hereafter in this Act mentioned,<note place="margin">Owner de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taining a Slave.</note> to make their Pretenſions, and Claim their Freedom, ſuch Owner or Overſeer, ſhall Forfeit ſuch Servant or Slave, and they be made Free, and no Satisfa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction to be made to the Owner for ſuch Servant or Slave.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, That the Honourable <hi>Richard Lloyd</hi> Eſquire, <hi>Francis Roſe, James Baniſter, Thomas Bindlos,</hi> and <hi>John Walters</hi> Eſquires,<note place="margin">Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners for Claims.</note> or any Three of them, be, and are hereby Authorized and Appointed to be Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners for the Hearing and Determining all Claims that ſhall be made by Virtue of this Act, by any Servant or Slave, and that the ſaid Commiſſioners, or any Three of them, are hereby fully Impowered to Adminiſter Oaths to any Perſon or Perſons that can give Evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence therein, and Iſſue out their Warrants for all Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons to attend and come before them, who can give Evidence relating to the Matters, to be by them De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>termined, by Virtue of this Act, and to Impriſon for Three Months without Bail or Mainprize, all ſuch Perſons as ſhall refuſe Obedience to ſuch their War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rants iſſued out, and the Determination concerning the Freedom of any Servant or Slave made by the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners aforeſaid, or any Three of them, purſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ant to this Act, being ſignified under their Hands and Seals, ſhall be the final Determination of all Claims and Diſputes that ſhall or may ariſe by Virtue of this Act without any further Appeal; any Thing to the contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That the Honourable <hi>Nicholas Laws</hi> Eſquire, <hi>Edward Stanton, Modyford Freeman, Joſiah Heathcote,</hi> and <hi>James
<pb n="91" facs="tcp:109567:48"/>Bradſhaw</hi> Eſquires, or any Three of them, be, and are hereby Appointed and Authorized to be Commiſſioners to Hear and Determine all Claims that ſhall or may be made by Virtue of this Act,<note place="margin">Other Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners.</note> by any Servant or Slave who ſhall belong to the Pariſhes of <hi>Kingſton,</hi> St. <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>drews,</hi> St. <hi>Davids,</hi> and St. <hi>Thomas</hi> to <hi>Windward,</hi> in the ſame manner, and have and full like Power and Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority as is given to the Commiſſioners firſt above<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentioned.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That he Honourable <hi>Richard Lloyd</hi> Eſquire, <hi>Francis Roſe, James Baniſter, Thomas Bindlos,</hi> and <hi>John Walters</hi> Eſquires, or any Three of them, do meet on <hi>Thurſday</hi> the Nineth Day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> in this preſent Year, One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Four, and St. <hi>Jago de la Vega,</hi> and ſo every <hi>Thurſday</hi> in the next Six Weeks fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing,<note place="margin">Time of Meeting.</note> and then to adjourn themſelves from time to time as they ſhall think fit.</p>
               <p>AND the Honourable <hi>Nicholas Laws, Edward Stanton, Modyford Freeman, Joſiah Heathcote,</hi> and <hi>James Bradſhaw</hi> Eſquires, or any Three of them, are hereby required to meet at <hi>Kingſton,</hi> on <hi>Thurſday</hi> the Nineth of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> in this preſent Year, One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Four, and every <hi>Thurſday</hi> in the next Six Weeks follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, and then to adjourn themſelves from time to time as they ſhall think fit; and all Marſhals and Conſtables,<note place="margin">Officers to attend.</note> are hereby required to give their Attendance, and Exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cute their Order as required by the ſaid Commiſſioners; and the Secretary keep a Book, wherein ſhall be Entred the Certificates of all ſuch Servants or Slaves who ſhall be Freed by Virtue of this Act as aforeſaid, and that he take Fifteen Pence for his Fee, and no more.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, That all Accounts for Proviſions fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhed to Their Majeſties for Man and Horſe, for Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Work done, and Materials found for the Fortifica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions,
<pb n="92" facs="tcp:109567:49"/>and all others Things and Matters relating any wiſe to the Preparations that were made for Defence for this Iſland, be ſtated and adjuſted by <hi>Samuel Lewis</hi> and <hi>John Walters</hi> Eſquires,<note place="margin">Auditors of Accounts.</note> at St. <hi>Jago de la Vega; Charles Whittle</hi> and <hi>Charles Saddler</hi> Eſquires, of <hi>Port-Royal; Edmond Edlin</hi> and <hi>Samuel Foxley</hi> Eſquires, at <hi>Kingſton,</hi> who are hereby Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, Authorized, and Impowered to <hi>audit</hi> the ſame; and that a Certificate of the State thereof, under the Hands and Seals of the ſaid Commiſſioners, or any one of them, ſhall be ſufficient to Entitle the ſeveral Parties concerned to demand and receive out of the Money to be raiſed for that purpoſe, the Summ due to them, without any further Proof.</p>
               <p>AND the ſaid Commiſſioners are hereby Required and Impowered to Hear and Determine the ſeveral Cauſes in this Act mentioned Material or any other Law to the contrary notwithſtanding: Provided this Act continue in Force during this preſent War with <hi>France,</hi> and no longer.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <pb n="93" facs="tcp:109567:49"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>An ACT</hi> For Prevention of Indebted Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons from Departing this I<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſland in the Time of Martial-Law.</head>
               <p>WHEREAS by an Act of this Iſland now in Force, Entitled,<note place="margin">Preamble.</note> 
                  <hi>An Act for Settling the Militia;</hi> the Martial-Law may on ſome Emergent Occaſions be declared to be in Force, on the ceaſing of which, the Common-Law revives and takes Place, whereby in the ſaid Times, ſeveral Ill-diſpoſed Perſons, and indebted, take Advantage and go off the Iſland, to the manifeſt Loſs of their Creditors, and ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral Diſcouragement to Trade: Be it therefore Enacted and Ordained by the Lieutenant-Governour, Council and Aſſembly, and it is hereby Enacted by the Authority of the ſame, That it ſhall and may be lawful for any Creditor or Creditors, to Stop, Arreſt, and Detain in Priſon by due Proceſs of Law, and Debtor or Debtors that ſhall attempt, or go about to depart this Iſland,<note place="margin">Debtors de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained.</note> un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>til he or they ſhall Pay and Satisfy their Debt or Debts; or in caſe of ſuch going off, or departure, a Foreign Attachment may Iſſue againſt his or their Goods or Chattels, as in time of the Common-Law,<note place="margin">Attachment.</note> notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding the ſaid afore-recited Act, or any Clauſe therein, being, or ſeeming to the contrary notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND whereas ſeveral Diſputes have heretofore ariſen about the Proceedings of the Surveyors of High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ways,<note place="margin">Surveyors of High-ways.</note>
                  <pb n="94" facs="tcp:109567:50"/>and of the Juſtices, Veſtries, and Church-Wardens within the ſeveral Pariſhes and Precincts in this Iſland, for keeping in Repair the High ways, Rai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing and Laying on the Pariſh Taxes, and Collecting, Levying, and Applying the ſame by the Conſtable, or any other Officer or Officers thereto appointed, in the time when Martial-Law is in Force in this Iſland, for the prevention of which, and avoiding the like Incon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venience occaſioned by Evil diſpoſed Perſons, to the Prejudice of Their Majeſties Service, and Injury to the Publick:</p>
               <p>BE it Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the Church-Wardens, and Surveyors of the High-ways, ſhall proceed to the Diſcharge of their ſeveral Duties; and the Juſtices, and the Veſtries in the ſeveral and reſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctive Pariſhes and Precincts within this Iſland, as well when Martial-Law is in Force, as at any other time, are here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by Required and Impowered to Meet, and Raiſe ſuch Parochial Tax or Taxes, as by the ſeveral Acts is Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rected and Appointed; and the ſeveral Conſtables Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lect, Levy, and Diſtrain for the ſame accordingly; and any Juſtice, Church-Warden, Veſtry-man, Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyor or Conſtable, neglecting his or their Duty, he or they ſo Offending, ſhall incur the Penalty in the Acts mentioned; any Act, Uſage, or Cuſtom to the contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>AND be it further Enacted, That this Act ſhall continue in Force during this preſent War with <hi>France,</hi> and no longer.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="confirmation">
               <pb n="95" facs="tcp:109567:50"/>
               <p>WHICH Laws having up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the Peruſal of the Right Honourable, the Lords of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee of Trade, and Foreign Plan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tations, been Preſented to His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty at this Board, His Majeſty was Graciouſly Pleaſed, with the Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice of His Privy-Council, to Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prove and Confirm the ſame; and purſuant to His Royal Pleaſure thereupon, Signified and Expreſſed, all the ſaid Laws, as afore-men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned, are hereby Approved and Confirmed accordingly.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>Will. Bridgeman.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="part">
            <div type="preamble">
               <pb n="96" facs="tcp:109567:51"/>
               <head>AT THE COURT AT KENSINGTON, The 26<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Day of <hi>December,</hi> 1695.</head>
               <head type="sub">PRESENT <hi>The King's Moſt Excellent</hi> MAJESTY, In COUNCIL.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>Lord Keeper.</item>
                  <item>Lord Privy-Seal.</item>
                  <item>Duke of <hi>Norfolk.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Duke of <hi>Schonberge.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Duke of <hi>Shrewsbury.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Marq. of <hi>Wincheſter.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Lord Great Chamberlain.</item>
                  <item>Earl of <hi>Bridgwater.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Earl of <hi>Stamford.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Earl of <hi>Scarborough.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Earl of <hi>Romney.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Lord <hi>Godolphin.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Mr. Vice-Chamberlain.</item>
                  <item>Mr. Secret. <hi>Trumbull.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Mr. Chancellor of the <hi>Exchequer.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>L. Chief Juſtice <hi>Holt.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Mr. <hi>Ruſſell.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Mr. <hi>Boſcawen.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Mr. <hi>Smith.</hi>
                  </item>
               </list>
               <p>WHEREAS by Commiſſion under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> to Sir <hi>William Beeſton,</hi> Knight, His MAJESTY<hi>'s</hi> Lieutenant-Governour, and Commander in Chief of the Iſland of
<pb n="97" facs="tcp:109567:51"/>
                  <hi>JAMAICA,</hi> bearing Date the Twentieth Day of <hi>September,</hi> One Thouſand Six Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Ninety Two, in the Fourth Year of His MAJESTY<hi>'s</hi> Reign; His MAJESTY has been Graciouſly pleaſed to Authorize and Impower the Governour, Council, and Aſſembly of the ſaid Iſland, to Conſtitute, and Ordain Laws, Statutes and Ordinances, which are to Continue and be in Force, till His MAJESTY<hi>'s</hi> Pleaſure be ſignified to the contrary: And for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>aſmuch as a certain Law, has in purſuance of the ſaid Commiſſion, been tranſmitted to His MAJESTY, with the Humble Deſire of the Governour, Council and Aſſembly, That His MAJESTY would be Pleaſed to Paſs the ſame in the Words following, <hi>viz.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <pb n="98" facs="tcp:109567:52"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>An ACT</hi> To Enable <hi>George Ivey</hi> Eſquire, to Sell his Eſtate for the Payment of the Debts of his Father <hi>William Ivey</hi> Eſquire, Deceaſed.</head>
               <p>WHEREAS <hi>William Ivey</hi> Eſquire,<note place="margin">Preamble.</note> lately Deceaſed, was Seized in his Demeſnes as of Fee, of, and in ſeveral Plantations, Lands, Tenements and Hereditaments, with the Appur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenances, in the Pariſhes of <hi>Clarendon, Vere,</hi> and S. <hi>Katherines,</hi> and elſewhere within this Iſland, and of ſeveral <hi>Negroes,</hi> and Stock thereunto belonging and appertaining: All which ſaid Plantations, Lands, Tenements and Heredi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taments, together with all and every the <hi>Negroes</hi> thereon being, or thereunto belonging, by his Laſt Will and Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtament, bearing Date the One and Twentieth Day of <hi>September,</hi> One Thouſand Six Hundred Eighty Nine; he deviſed to <hi>George Ivey</hi> Eſquire, his Eldeſt Son and his Heirs, and for want of Iſſue of him the ſaid <hi>George,</hi> to <hi>William Ivey,</hi> Second Son of the ſaid <hi>William</hi> the Teſtator, and the Heirs of his Body, with divers Remainders over; and of his ſaid Will, made the ſaid <hi>George</hi> his Eldeſt Son ſole Executor, who ſince, has duly proved his ſaid Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther's ſaid Will.</p>
               <p>AND whereas the ſaid <hi>William</hi> the Teſtator, was at the time of his Deceaſe indebted to the Royal <hi>African</hi> Company of <hi>England,</hi> and to divers other Perſons, by Judgment, Bonds and otherwiſe, in the Summ of Two Thouſand Pounds and upwards; and foraſmuch as the Perſonal Eſtate of the ſaid <hi>William</hi> the Teſtator, not including the ſaid <hi>Negroes</hi> and Stock, was ſo very incon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiderable,
<pb n="99" facs="tcp:109567:52"/>that the ſaid <hi>George Ivey</hi> by Reaſon of the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tail aforeſaid, without the Aſſiſtance of an Act of the Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſembly, has no way left of Paying his Fathers ſaid Debts, unleſs by the Sale of all the ſaid <hi>Negroes,</hi> and Stock left upon, and belonging to the Lands and Plantations ſo In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tailed, which muſt inevitably Ruin and Deſtroy the ſaid Plantations, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>AND foraſmuch as it is highly juſt and reaſonable, that no Act of the ſaid <hi>William Ivey,</hi> the Teſtator, ſhould prevent, or hinder all, or any part of his ſaid Eſtate, from being lyable, and ſubject to the payment of his juſt Debts, or debar the ſaid <hi>George,</hi> his eldeſt Son, from diſpoſing of, and applying the ſame for the payment and diſcharge of the ſame; and foraſmuch as <hi>William Ivey,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Conſent of the Second Son.</note> the ſecond Son of <hi>William</hi> the Teſtator, to whom the next remainder in Tail after the Death of <hi>George,</hi> the Tenant now in Poſſeſſion, without Iſſue of his Body is limited, has, upon Conſideration of the Sum of Four Hundred Pounds, teſtified, and declared his Conſent to the Paſſing of this preſent Act:</p>
               <p>BE it therefore Enacted by Their Majeſties Lieutenant-Governour, Council, and Aſſembly, and it is hereby Enacted by the Authority of the ſame, that for the Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the Debts aforeſaid, it ſhall, and may be law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful to, and for the ſaid <hi>George Ivey,</hi> and he is hereby fully Authorized, Impowered, and Enabled to Sell, Diſpoſe of, or Convey, or by his laſt Will and Teſtament to Deviſe all, or any part or parcel of the ſaid Plantations, Lands, Tenements, and other Hereditaments above<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentioned, together with all, and every the <hi>Negroes</hi> thereunto belonging, or appertaining, to any Perſon or Perſons whatſoever, in ſuch manner and form, and as amply, and effectually, to all Intents, Conſtructions, and Purpoſes, as if the ſame had Deſcended to him the ſaid <hi>George Ivey,</hi> and he were thereof Seized and Poſſeſſed in Fee-Simple, and no ſuch Intail and Remainder, or Remainders as aforeſaid had ever been made, limited, or
<pb n="100" facs="tcp:109567:53"/>created; and the Purchaſer, or Purchaſers, Deviſee, or Deviſees of the ſame, or any part or parcel thereof, ſhall be deemed, adjudged, and taken to be Seized thereof, and of every part and parcel thereof, to them, and their Heirs for ever, as if the ſaid <hi>George</hi> had ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fered a Common Recovery in Their Majeſties Court of <hi>Common-Pleas,</hi> at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> of all, or any part or par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cel of the ſaid Premiſes,<note place="margin">Purchaſer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſecured.</note> to the Uſe, or Uſes of the Pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſer, or Purchaſers, Deviſee or Deviſees, and of their Heirs for ever; and the ſaid Purchaſer, or Purchaſers, Deviſee or Deviſees, their Heirs or Aſſigns, ſhall, and may hold, occupy, and enjoy the ſame free from any Eſtates, Uſes, Limitations, Remainders, Charges, and Proviſoes, had, made, or created, in, and by the ſaid laſt Will and Teſtament of the abovementioned <hi>William Ivey,</hi> the Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtator, any Law, Cuſtom, or Uſage to the Contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="confirmation">
               <pb n="101" facs="tcp:109567:53"/>
               <p>WHICH Law having up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the Peruſal of the Right Honourable, the Lords of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee of Trade, and Foreign Plan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tations, been Preſented to His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty at this Board, His Majeſty was Graciouſly Pleaſed, with the Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice of His Privy-Council, to Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prove and Confirm the ſame; and purſuant to His Royal Pleaſure thereupon, Signified and Expreſſed, the ſaid Law as afore-mentioned, is hereby Approved and Confirmed accordingly.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>Will. Bridgeman.</signed>
               </closer>
               <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="publishers_advertisement">
            <pb facs="tcp:109567:54"/>
            <head>BOOKS Printed for, and Sold by <hi>Charles Harper</hi> at the <hi>Flower-de-luce,</hi> over-againſt St. <hi>Dunſtan</hi>'s Church in <hi>Fleet-ſtreet.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>THE Life of our Bleſſed Lord and Saviour Jeſus Chriſt. An Heroic Poem: Dedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cated to Her moſt Sacred Majeſty, in Ten Books. Attempted by <hi>Samuel Weſley,</hi> M. A. each Book Illuſtrated by neceſſary Notes, Explaining all the more Dif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficult Matters in the whole Hiſtory: Alſo a Prefaratory Diſcourſe concerning Heroic Poetry. The Second Edition Reviſed by the Author, and Improved with the Addition of a Large Map of the <hi>Holy-Land;</hi> and a Table of the Principal Matters; with Sixty Copper-Plates, by the celebrated Hand of <hi>W. Faithorne.</hi> Fol.</p>
            <p>The Second and Third Parts of the Works of Mr. <hi>Abraham Cowley.</hi> The Second containing what was written and publiſhed by himſelf in his younger Years, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>printed together. The Sixth Edit. The Third Part containing his Six Books of Plants, <hi>viz.</hi> the Firſt and Second of Herbs, the Third and Fourth of Flowers, the Fifth and Sixth of Trees: Now made <hi>Engliſh</hi> by ſeveral Hands, with neceſſary Tables to both Parts, and divers Poems in praiſe of the Author. <hi>Fol.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Reſoves: Divine, Moral, Political. With ſeveral New Additions in Proſe and Verſe. In this Eleveth Edition, References are made to the Poetical Citations heretofore much wanted. By <hi>Owen Felltham</hi> 
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr> 
               <hi>Fol.</hi> Price 12 <hi>s.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Works of the Famous <hi>Nicholas Machival,</hi> Citizen and Secretary of <hi>Florence.</hi> Newly and faithfully Tranſlated into <hi>Engliſh. Fol.</hi> Price 15 <hi>s.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Whole Duty of Man, according to the Law of Nature, by that Famous Civi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lian <hi>Samuel Puffendorf;</hi> Now made <hi>Engliſh. Octavo.</hi> Price 3 <hi>s.</hi> 6 <hi>d.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Dr. <hi>Willis</hi>'s Practice of Phyſick, being the whole Works of that Famous Phyſician; rendred into <hi>Engliſh.</hi> Second Edit. with Forty Copper-Plates. <hi>Fol.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Hiſtorical and Miſcellaneous Tracts of the Reverend and Learned <hi>Peter Heylin,</hi> D. D. Now Collected into one Vol. And an Account of the Life of the Author, never before publiſhed. <hi>Fol.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Religion of Proteſtants, a ſafe way to Salvation; with a Diſcourſe of the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtolical Inſtitution of Epiſcopacy. By <hi>W. Chillingworth,</hi> M. A. To which in this Edit. is added his Letter, ſhewing the Reaſon why he left Popery. <hi>Fol.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Hiſtory of Q. <hi>Elizabeth:</hi> By <hi>W. Cambden</hi> K. at Arms. Fourth Edit. <hi>Fol.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>An Impartial Collection of the great Affairs of State, from the beginning of the <hi>Scotch</hi> Rebellion in the Year 1639. to the Murder of King <hi>Charles</hi> the Firſt. <hi>Fol.</hi> in Two Vol. By Dr. <hi>Nalſon.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Dugdale</hi>'s Monaſticon Anglicanum. <hi>Fol.</hi> in Three Vol.</p>
            <p>The Hiſtory of K. <hi>Edward</hi> II. King of <hi>England,</hi> and Lord of <hi>Ireland.</hi> Fol.</p>
            <p>Dr. <hi>Willis</hi>'s Practic. of Phyſick. <hi>Octav.</hi> With his Treatiſe of the Plague. Price 7 <hi>s.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Biſhop <hi>Uſher</hi>'s Power of the Prince, and the Obedience required of the Subject, with a large Preface, by Biſhop <hi>Sanderſon.</hi> Octav.</p>
            <p>Animadverſ. on a Book Entit. <hi>The Theory of the Earth:</hi> By <hi>Herbert</hi> L. B. of <hi>Hereford.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A Treatiſe of Moral and Intellectual Virtues, wherein their Nature is fully ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plained, and their Uſefulneſs proved: By <hi>J. Hartcliff,</hi> B. D. Pride 4 <hi>s.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Contemplations Moral and Divine, in Two Parts, by Sir <hi>Matth. Hale,</hi> Kt. late Chief Juſtice of the King's-Bench. <hi>Octav.</hi> Price 5 <hi>s.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A Voyage to <hi>Suratt,</hi> in the Year 1689. Giving a large Account of that City, and its Inhabitants, and of the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Factory there. Likewiſe a Deſcription of <hi>Madera,</hi> St. <hi>Jago, Annobon, Cabenda,</hi> and <hi>Malemba</hi> (or the Coaſt of <hi>Africa</hi>) St. <hi>Helena, Johanna, Bombay,</hi> the City of <hi>Muſcatt,</hi> and its Inhabitants in <hi>Arabia Felix, Mocha,</hi> and other Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritim Towns on the <hi>Red-Sea,</hi> the <hi>Cape of good Hope,</hi> and the <hi>Iſland of Aſcenſion.</hi> By <hi>J. Ovington,</hi> M. A. Chaplain to His Majeſty. <hi>Octav.</hi> Price 6 <hi>s.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A plain Method of Chriſtian Devotion: Laid down in Diſcourſes, Meditations, and Prayers, fitted to the various Occaſion of a Religious Life: Tranſlated and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſed from the <hi>French</hi> of Monſieur <hi>Jurieu,</hi> the Two and Twentieth Edition; with a Preface: By <hi>W. Fleetwood,</hi> Chaplain in Ordinary to his Majeſty. Price 2 <hi>s.</hi> 6 <hi>d.</hi>
            </p>
            <div type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:109567:54"/>
               <head>LAW-BOOKS.</head>
               <p>THE Reports of Sir <hi>Peyton Ventris,</hi> Knight, late one of the Juſtices of the <hi>Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon-Pleas,</hi> in Two Parts. The firſt containing ſelect Caſes adjudged in the <hi>King's-Bench,</hi> in the Reign of K. <hi>Charles</hi> II. The Second Part, containing Choice Caſes, adjudged in the <hi>Common-Pleas,</hi> in the Reign of K. <hi>Charles</hi> II. and K. <hi>James</hi> II. and in the three firſt Years of his now Majeſty K. <hi>William</hi> and the late Q. <hi>Mary,</hi> while he was a Judge in the ſaid Court, with the Pleadings to the ſame; with the Allowance and Approbation of the Lord-Keeper and all the Judges. 2 Vol. in <hi>Fol.</hi> Price 1 <hi>l.</hi> 10 <hi>s.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Lord <hi>Coke</hi>'s Reports in <hi>Engliſh.</hi> Folio.</p>
               <p>Judge <hi>Crook</hi>'s Reports in 3 Vol. the Third Edition, with References to all the late Reports. <hi>Folio.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Lord <hi>Coke</hi>'s Commentary on <hi>Littleton.</hi> Folio.</p>
               <p>— His Commentary on <hi>Magna Charta.</hi> Folio.</p>
               <p>— His Pleas of the Crown, or the Third Part of the Inſtitutes. <hi>Folio.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>— His Juriſdiction of Courts, or Fourth Part of the Inſtitutes.</p>
               <p>— His Eleven Reports in <hi>French.</hi> Folio.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Bulſtrode</hi>'s Reports, with New References. <hi>Folio.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Leonard</hi>'s Reports in Four Parts, with New References. <hi>Folio.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Year-Books in 10 Vol. the laſt Edit. with New Not. and Tables to them. all. <hi>Fol.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Reports of the Lord-Keeper <hi>Littleton,</hi> in the time of King <hi>Charles</hi> I. <hi>Folio.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Reports of the Learned Judge, Sir <hi>Henry Hobart,</hi> the Fourth Edition corrected and amended. <hi>Folio.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Reports in the Court of <hi>King's-Bench</hi> at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> from the 12th. to the 30th Year of King <hi>Charles</hi> II. by <hi>Joſ. Keble</hi> of <hi>Grays-Inn,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> in Three Vol. <hi>Folio.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Kelway</hi>'s Reports with new References to all the late Reports. <hi>Fol.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Reports of ſeveral eſpecial Caſes in the Court of <hi>Common-Pleas,</hi> by <hi>S. Carter</hi> of the <hi>Inner Temple,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> 
                  <hi>Fol.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>An Aſſiſtance to Juſtices of the Peace, for the eaſier Performance of their Duty, the Firſt Part containing the particular Clauſes of all ſuch Statutes from <hi>Magna Charta,</hi> until the firſt of King <hi>James</hi> II. that do any ways concern a Juſtice of Peace; in the other Part, the whole Office of a Juſtice of Peace is methodically di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geſted, with the moſt approved Preſidents under proper Heads, to which is now added a Table for the ready finding out the Preſidents, with a large Table of the matters never before Printed: By <hi>Joſ. Keble</hi> of <hi>Grays-Inn,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr>
               </p>
               <p>An exact Abridgment of the Records in the <hi>Tower</hi> of <hi>London,</hi> being of great Uſe for all that are concerned in Parliamentary Affairs, and Profeſſors of the Laws of this Realm, Collected by Sir <hi>Rob. Cotton,</hi> Knight and Baronet. <hi>Fol.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>An exact Abridgment of the Statutes of King <hi>William</hi> and Queen <hi>Mary,</hi> and of King <hi>William</hi> III. in Force and Uſe. Begun by <hi>Jo. Waſhington</hi> of the <hi>Middle Temple</hi> Eſquire, and ſince his Death Reviſed and continued to the End of the laſt Seſſion of Parliament, <hi>April</hi> 27. 1696. <hi>Octavo.</hi> Price 4 <hi>s.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The <hi>Scrivener's Guide:</hi> Being choice and approved Forms of Precedents, of all ſorts of Buſineſs now in Uſe and Practice, in a much better method than any yet printed; being uſeful for all Gentlemen, but chiefly for thoſe who practice the Law. <hi>Octavo. Price</hi> 5 <hi>s.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Styles</hi>'s Practical Regiſter, begun in the Reign of King <hi>Charles</hi> I. conſiſting of Rules, Orders, and principal Obſervations concerning the Practice of the Common Law in the Courts of <hi>Weſtminſter;</hi> particularly the <hi>Kings Bench,</hi> as well in matters Criminal as Civil; carefully continued down to this time. The Third Edition. <hi>Octavo. Price</hi> 6 <hi>s.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>An exact Abridgment of all the Statutes in Form and Uſe from the beginning of <hi>Magna Charta;</hi> begun by <hi>Edm. Wingate,</hi> and ſince continued by <hi>J. Waſhington</hi> to the Year 1689. In this Impreſſion many hundred of falſe References are corrected. <hi>Price</hi> 7. <hi>s.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Two Dialogues in <hi>Engliſh</hi> between a Doctor of Divinity, and a Student of the Laws of <hi>England,</hi> of the Grounds of the ſaid Laws, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Price 2 <hi>s</hi> 6 <hi>d.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The new <hi>Natura Brevium</hi> of the moſt Reverend Judge Mr. <hi>Anthony Fitz. Herbert,</hi> Corrected and Reviſed. Price 6 <hi>s.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="publishers_advertisement">
            <pb facs="tcp:109567:55"/>
            <head>Some Books Printed and Sold by <hi>Samuel Crouch,</hi> at the Corner of <hi>Popes-Head-Alley</hi> next <hi>Cornhil.</hi> FOLIO.</head>
            <p>THE Hiſtory, Life, Reign and Death of <hi>Edward</hi> II. King of <hi>England,</hi> and Lord of <hi>Ireland;</hi> with the Riſe and Fall of his great Favourites, <hi>Gaveſton</hi> and the <hi>Spencers:</hi> By <hi>E.F.</hi> in the Year 1627; and Printed <hi>Verbatim</hi> from the Original. Hiſtorical Collections of Private Matters of State, of Weighty Matters in Law, of Remarkable Proceedings in Parliaments; beginning the Sixteenth Year of King <hi>James,</hi> Anno 1618, and ending the Fifth Year of King <hi>Charles,</hi> 1629. Digeſted into order of Time, and now Publiſh'd by <hi>John Ruſhworth,</hi> 
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr> of <hi>Lincolns-Inn.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Cambridge</hi> Concordance. <hi>QUARTO.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>THE Rape: or the Innocent Impoſters; a Tragedy acted at the Theatre Royal.</p>
            <p>The New Alamode Secretary: or Practical Pen-Man.</p>
            <p>Youths Introduction to Trade: an Exerciſe-Book, chiefly deſigned for the Uſe of the Writing-School, to Employ Youth at <hi>Night</hi> and other <hi>vacant</hi> Times while they learn to Write; by which the Young Apprentice may be able to Apply his Writing and Arithmetick to Buſineſs; as, a Merchant, Shop-keeper, or other in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferior Trades: Firſt Methodized for the Benefit of the Author's Scholars: and Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſhed for the Uſe of ſuch as Tech Writing and Arithmetick: by <hi>John Ayres.</hi> The Second Edition, Corrected, and very much Enlarged.</p>
            <p>Tables for the Forbearance and Diſcompt of Money; whereby by Intereſt from 10000 <hi>l.</hi> to One Shilling, from One Day to 365, is exactly Calculated to the Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſandth Part of a Peny; with the Rebate of all Sums: Likewiſe Tables for the For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bearance, Diſcompts, and the Purchaſe of Annuities for 31 Years, at the Rate of 6 <hi>per Cent per Annum.</hi> With an exact Table for the ready Summing up of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modities: All performed by Addition only, for the Help of the Meaneſt Capacity. The Third Edition: by <hi>Roger Clavel,</hi> Gent. Student in the Mathematicks.</p>
            <p>The Preſent State of <hi>Europe</hi> Examined, and found Languiſhing: Occaſioned by the Greatneſs of the <hi>French</hi> Monarchy. For the Cure thereof, a Remedy is moſt humbly propoſed by <hi>Tho. Manly,</hi> 
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr>
            </p>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Large and Small <hi>Octavo's:</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <hi>DE Jure Maritimo &amp; Navali:</hi> or a Treatiſe of Affairs Maritime, and of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merce in Three Books: The Fourth Edition: by <hi>Charles Molloy.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>A Rational Practice of Chyrurgery: or Chyrurgical Obſervations Reſolved ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Solid Fundaments of true Philoſophy: by <hi>John Muys,</hi> Doctor of Phy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſick in <hi>Arnheim.</hi> In Five Decades.</p>
               <p>Dr. <hi>Thompſon</hi>'s Method of Curing Chymically.</p>
               <p>Obſervations upon the United Provinces of the <hi>Netherlands:</hi> by Sir <hi>William Temple,</hi> The Fifth Edition. Corrected and Augmented.</p>
               <p>The Ingenious and Diverting Letters of the Lady—Travels into <hi>Spain.</hi> Deſcribing the Devotions, Nunneries, Humours, Cuſtoms, Laws, Militia, Trade, Diet, and Recreations of that People. Intermixt with great Variety of Modern Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ventures, and Surpriſing Accidents: being the Trueſt and Beſt Remarks Extant on that Court and Country. The Fourth Edition Corrected. In Three Parts Compleat.</p>
               <p>The Phyſical Dictionary. Wherein the Terms of Anatomy, the Names and Cauſes of Diſeaſes, Chyrurgical Inſtruments and their Uſe; are accurately Deſcrib'd. Alſo the Names and Virtues of Medicinal Plants, Minerals, Stones, Gums, Salts, Earths, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And the Method of chooſing the beſt Drugs: The Terms of Chymi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtry, and of the Apothecaries Art; and the various Forms of Medicines, and the ways of Compounding them. By <hi>Stephen Blancard,</hi> M. D. Phyſick-Profeſſor at <hi>Middleburg</hi> in <hi>Zealand.</hi> The Third Edition, with the Addition of above a Thouſand Terms of Art, and their Explanation.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Carden</hi>'s Three Books of Conſolation, Engliſhed, of great Uſe in theſe Times.</p>
               <p>The Art of Painting of Oyl. Wherein is included each particular Circumſtance relating to that Art and Myſtery. Containing the beſt and moſt approved Rules for preparing, mixing, and working of Oyl-Colours The whole Treatiſe being ſo full Compleat, and ſo exactly fitted to the meaneſt Capacity, that all Perſons what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever, may be able by theſe Directions, to Paint in Oyl-Colours. By <hi>J. Smith,</hi> C.M.</p>
               <pb facs="tcp:109567:55"/>
            </div>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
